<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aashayein-Foundation on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/aashayein-foundation/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aashayein-Foundation on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/aashayein-foundation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In mired thoughts...</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2009/11/11/in-mired-thoughts.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2009/11/11/in-mired-thoughts.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m out here seated in the balcony of my house with the lappy streaming out  Yanni&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Keys to imagination&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s not yet December, yet the chill is in the air already. Been a while that I visited my own blog so decided to keep things at bay and record things happening  in my life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Work’s been a bit demanding of late. Not really hectic but these late night client calls with atypical and unrelenting requests all in a short time span is sort of draining. I’m just hoping against hope that the next three days slice through comfortably.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot that’s been happening otherwise too.  A lot of decision making and much of selective time distribution for various activities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, thanks to the GHAC folks, I got to attend a very informative first aid certification course. Had some real good hands-on on performing CPR and understood in practical terms the imminent first aid doctrines in case of accidents or personal injury. Also got to meet couple of real cool folks! Sadly I could not join them the second day as I had to attend a family function.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This weekend would be one very important checkpoint in my career and I would prefer to keep it obscure till things materialize. If all goes well, I’ll be riding over to the Begumpet airport to catch up with the HBC folks for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/HyderabadBicyclingClub/calendar/11839620/&#34;&gt;conglomeration ride&lt;/a&gt;. Hell, I’m still riding if things don’t work the way I want it to. Badly need a long relaxing ride to let things sink in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The weekend after this, I’d be running my first half marathon! Eagerly looking forward to this Nov 22nd. I&amp;rsquo;ve been training decently well [if not religiously!] for a month now and all I’m looking forward to is to complete the marathon without any major setbacks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then on December 13th, we at Aashayein foundation are organizing a walkathon – &lt;a href=&#34;http://in.aashayeinfoundation.org/walk-for-a-cause/&#34;&gt;Walk On ’09.&lt;/a&gt; All proceeds from this event would be routed to the child education activities that the foundation has been diligently working towards for the past few years.  This being the first time that we’re pulling up a show of this magnitude, there’s been a flurry of activity happening in the team.  Everyone’s fingers are crossed and hope and excitement is high in the air.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Late this year during Christmas, I plan to head to the Pench tiger reserve for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/home.php#/event.php?eid=176390600814&#34;&gt;Junglethlon&lt;/a&gt;. Activities would include Jungle mountain Biking, River bed running, rock climbing, rappelling, jungle navigation and survival! I&amp;rsquo;d initially planned to do a long ride in the western ghats in Kerala or around Araku but later decided to hold up these plans and head for the Junglethlon. The very thought gets the adrenalin spiking up and this seems to be quite a promising way to end the  year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time to crash and rise to yet another day. And oh yes, avoid the run for the bus early in the morning tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is my uncle Kishan...</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2009/06/27/this-is-my-uncle-kishan.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2009/06/27/this-is-my-uncle-kishan.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An assortment of about fifteen kids are seated in front of me. All supposedly fifth and sixth graders. The syllabus mandates me to read out to them a story and ask them questions based on it. Something akin to the reading comprehension questions that we solve. I set off in my task in reading out a para and asking the one in the third row a very simple question. His poker faced response immediately states he&amp;rsquo;s not got a word of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been talking. Same applies almost every other kid out here. I break up the sentences now to see if that helps them. Still the same response. I finally check to see if they at least know the individual words in the sentence. Turns out that NONE of them are even able to appreciate the presence of a &amp;rsquo;the&amp;rsquo; in the sentence! Besides, when asked to translate a statement like - &amp;lsquo;This is my uncle Kishan&amp;rsquo; to telugu, I get the weirdest responses imaginable! They do not know the difference between &amp;lsquo;Buying&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Going&amp;rsquo;! Teaching them to decipher paragraphs is way too optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next hour or so goes in asking them to echo back just four sentences, asking them to focus on my lip movement and giving them a suitable transliteration. With small role plays I try to engage them to capture the essence of what was being talked about in the book. They soon seem to be liking the whole concept and cheerfully engage each other sheepishly shouting broken English sentences. The misplaced it&amp;rsquo;s, the&amp;rsquo;s and she&amp;rsquo;s don&amp;rsquo;t matter a dime but as they chorously repeat what I read out from the book, I find it hard to digest the fact that these kids do not have access to even basic primary education. These kids from the Arundati Upper primary school have just three people to teach them-Two ladies [ One who is just recuperating from an operation and the other being the Head mistress] and a septuagenarian gentleman who&amp;rsquo;s been voluntuarily teaching them for the past two years. The community that runs this school wants to raze this down and build a complex here instead. That would equate to about 100 of these kids losing one last oppurtunity to get a hold on their lifes. Imagine one of your kids/nephew/niece to be in their shoes. Wait, they don&amp;rsquo;t even have shoes to walk in!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Estb. by the community about fifty years back they have kids from class 1 to 7. There&amp;rsquo;s a fan or two in the building with no Power to run them. The dripping roof of the two or three rooms that constitutes this school would satiate the thirst of the kids directly in monsoon. A couple of ayah&amp;rsquo;s[Read girls probably in their 9th or 10th grade] take classes for the kids in the lower grades!The kids come here to the school for the sole motivation of the mid-day meal that the government provides them or should i say - &amp;lsquo;supposedly&amp;rsquo;. The kids who&amp;rsquo;re in the fifth and sixth grade in no way can match any regular third grade kid from the other regular schools. Those who move out from the school, I understand discontinue their education and take up a mechanics job or other petty things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I head back home with a &amp;lsquo;Telugu&amp;rsquo; medium math text book to understand what I&amp;rsquo;ll have to teach them next week, the vicious reality still remains blaring out there on the immense hurdle ahead of them and more so the onus on us to give them their basic right to education.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Drop in a mail to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:info.hyd@aashayeinfoundation.org&#34;&gt;info.hyd@aashayeinfoundation.org&lt;/a&gt; if you could spare a couple of hours in the weekends! We need your help!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
