<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vaccines on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/vaccines/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vaccines on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/vaccines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jabbed</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/16/jabbed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/16/jabbed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since March 2020, I&amp;rsquo;ve had this internal debate of getting the Covid Vaccine mostly underlined by the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3d3bb2ac73.65468826&#34;&gt;science behind mRNA&lt;/a&gt; is fascinating and so is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3c8962f2a2.96282489&#34;&gt;engineering of the vaccine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every strand of mRNA is made up of four molecular building blocks called nucleosides. But in its altered, synthetic form, one of those building blocks, like a misaligned wheel on a car, was throwing everything off by signaling the immune system. So Karikó and Weissman simply subbed it out for a slightly tweaked version, creating a hybrid mRNA that could sneak its way into cells without alerting the body’s defenses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statnews&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We unfortunately &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/vaccinesafety/concerns/concerns-history.html%5D&#34;&gt;have not had a spectacular history&lt;/a&gt; with vaccines. With humans involved and the ensuing politics, money and power-plays; vaccines are built for the average human being. Then with anything manufactured and delivered at scale, we&amp;rsquo;re prone to Logistics and Supply chain Management issues.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Covid19 vaccines are not a once and done deal. The effects &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/607a14edb61f01.57427531&#34;&gt;last apparently at most a year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did cave in and got the first ‘jab&amp;rsquo; of the Moderna vaccine today at the Consulate. As with all vaccines and medical interventions, this was not quite an easy decision. The decision was probably 40% gut, 40% trusting the mechanics of the mRNA vaccine and 20% of &amp;lsquo;Why am I even considering it&amp;rsquo;. The drivers for the gut-feeling likely being:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Getting the vaccine would possibly break the link in transmitting the virus to an immune-compromised person. We live with our in-laws and that&amp;rsquo;s the least I can do for them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I consider myself to be a fairly young and healthy person and absolutely do not mind wearing masks and exercising social distancing. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve shamefully caught myself pulling down the mask during brief interactions with people. Despite best efforts, the masking system alone is not fool-proof.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; to be outdoors to stay healthy and be sane. Travel and Freedom are my primary &amp;lsquo;movers&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From an extremely exaggerated perspective, I see C19 as the Smallpox / Polio of this century. Few folks in the family are still reeling with the brutal after-effects of these diseases. I think I can take the risk of the possible side-effects for the marginal leg-up the vaccine might give my immune system in case I contract the virus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Folks in the family are leaning towards getting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/607a1f2977e8c3.93743514&#34;&gt;Covaxin&lt;/a&gt; vaccine. India is having it&amp;rsquo;s worst wave so far and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping we swing back downwards as sharply as we rose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA, RNA, Vaccines and Humans</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/12/28/dna-rna-vaccines-and-humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/12/28/dna-rna-vaccines-and-humans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been meandering through &lt;a href=&#34;https://berthub.eu/index.html&#34;&gt;Bert&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s webpage and a few other sites - Such a treasure trove of information on the C-19 vaccine and biology/technology in general. No seriously, dive into these links for some great layman(ish) explanation of DNA, RNA, Vaccines and what not!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3c8962f2a2.96282489&#34;&gt;Reverse Engineering the source code of the BioNTech/Pfizer SARS-CoV-2 Vaccine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea38322bb2a0.08041300&#34;&gt;No, Really, mRNA Vaccines Are Not Going To Affect Your DNA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3d3bb2ac73.65468826&#34;&gt;The story of mRNA: From a loose idea to a tool that may help curb Covid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3e5f534579.64795290&#34;&gt;I Made a Covid-19 Vaccine in my Kitchen and it Worked&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: These links point to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;Wallabag instance&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d much prefer linking to the original article. However, I find this as a good way to save information which I can access later even if the original source vanishes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
