<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/categories/family/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:36:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/categories/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-06 00:36:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/06/ca-aefm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:36:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/06/ca-aefm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;M just received an invite for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.state.gov/global-community-liaison-office/overseas-family-member-employment/family-member-employment-within-a-u-s-embassy-or-consulate/consular-affairs-appointment-eligible-family-member-program/&#34;&gt;CA-AEFM&lt;/a&gt; March&#39;25 cohort. Long overdue! Adds a small wrench to our planning for the PCS next year but as Pappaji says - it&amp;rsquo;s a Happy problem! Super excited! &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/06/ca-aefm/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sixth</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/11/sixth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/11/sixth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;Sixth.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S celebrated her 6th today.  Unicorn themed - of course - and had her first and probably last ever Piñata. But for a mega meltdown initially she did great all through the event.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, we signed up for a Diwali party organized by the Indian Association in Mexico. Primarily on a whim and maybe for the food? The event was last evening and boy, it was a terrible disappointment! It started late as expected. And obnoxiously loud for no reason. Not quite sure if it was the acoustics at the venue or just the MC shouting into the mic.  Maybe both? I love some good rock and metal. I love some good loud music. But I guess not all loud is the same. Also, this day and age, who even does a looping slideshow of pictures of people organizing the event? Dinner was supposed to be served by 1900. Servers said they had orders to serve only at 2030. Maybe the organizers wanted the food to be served only after the main event? When we rechecked at 2030, they said it was pushed to 2130. Had enough of it and walked out.  People were still on the dance floor and there was a good turn out. I guess this kinda boisterous social mayhem is just not my jam?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We head out to a Japanese (?) restaurant in Polanco since Nimi&amp;rsquo;s, Mei Mei and Manaw were all closed for service. Sushi was &lt;em&gt;meh&lt;/em&gt;. S did great all through the evening though despite the loud music and the crowd. That &amp;lsquo;Sticker by number&amp;rsquo; book that she received as a gift from Maddy kept her fully occupied!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Monday morning here and S is off for school. She was mildly upset that I get to stay at home while she needs to go to school. Fair world logic, I guess. We drop her and get to spend a couple hours together watching &lt;em&gt;Spenser Confidential&lt;/em&gt;. Enjoyed it all the more because we recognized quite a few locations where the movie was shot. M&amp;rsquo;s got some brunch out with the ladies in a bit and then a couple more hours before I need to pick up S. Maybe I should tweak that 3D printer?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diwali</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/31/diwali/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/31/diwali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;Diwali2024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being overseas and not having access to firecrackers, this festival is just not what it used to be. I wish I could go back to those days when we would try and wake up before Kitta mama would burst his 1000 wala before the break of dawn. Days when you yearn to wear those new set of clothes - The only time of the year when you get new clothes and not hand-me-downs. Days when you make a TON of sweets and savories to share with family and friends. Days when you would hop into people&amp;rsquo;s houses uninvited to see what special delicacy they&amp;rsquo;ve made. Days when every single house is lit up and the smoke of firecrackers permeate everything. Such good memories&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diwali this year was super low key. We did light up some &lt;em&gt;Diyas&lt;/em&gt; and M had ordered some savory snacks from one of her local contacts. A few calls to family and I think we called it a day. Times when you miss being amongst family and friends. Happy Halloween and Diwali - I guess?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All of 65 lbs</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/09/all-of-65-lbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/09/all-of-65-lbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With quite a few developments on the personal front, the last few months has kept me quite &amp;lsquo;busy&amp;rsquo;. Despite Covid, I did a bunch of travel which is always nice! Last August, Appa kinda lost his patience and wanted to make a trip to India. We figured September was the most optimal time and I flew over to MD to accompany him back. With just a day off work, I was able to finagle a whirlwind weekend trip to the US and back. M and S head over to the states in October to be a bit of a help in MD while I looked after two grand old men here in India. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while that I&amp;rsquo;ve done this and but for a few rough days, I loved spending time helping them accomplish what they wanted to over the course of three months. Appa was able to get most of his &amp;lsquo;admin&amp;rsquo; stuff done and more importantly got to spend time with his younger brother.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In December I made a quick trip to Delhi to meet folks at work. Was good catching up after all of these months of telework! Mid December and just before the Omicron wave hit the Asian region, we were asked to report into work on premises. Obviously made sense to take Appa back to MD since we didn&amp;rsquo;t want him to be living alone - more so when we started seeing the Omicron effect in the US, Israel and UK. I accompanied him back on the 31st and used this opportunity to also take some time off to spend with M &amp;amp; S! It was a much needed break and we did get to do a bunch of stuff in the short time that I was there: Got the Moderna booster - In tandem with Jet-lag, the next day fatigue was a killer, Went on a nice date with M to a Thai restaurant - but for the jasmine spray hand sanitizer..UGH!, Took S our for &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/01/trolley-trail/&#34;&gt;a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/05/patapsco-thru-trail/&#34;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/06/oregon-ridge-park/&#34;&gt;hikes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/05/january-6-2022-0609/&#34;&gt;Built a scooter&lt;/a&gt; for S, Migrated my servers over to MD, packed my belongings in all of 65lbs and moved to Delhi. The return leg was quite happening with American transferring my booking to BA and transiting  me via Heathrow. Called for a lot of last minute Covid digital paperwork. Thank goodness to smartphones and free WiFi access in Airports!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For now I&amp;rsquo;m super excited to be in Delhi! Still too many variables at play and oddly that seems to be the constant in our lives. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to explore this fascinating city and then head further up north during the weekends. Omicron is going to hugely shape the next few months and I&amp;rsquo;m going to make best use of the wrenches it&amp;rsquo;s gonna throw.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy (Belated) New Year!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diyas and memories</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/11/04/diyas-and-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/11/04/diyas-and-memories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diwali it is and I&amp;rsquo;m so lucky to be at AJ this year. Though most of the family is not here, I did want to get those positive light vibes in the house. Appa and I got the diyas out and lit them up like we&amp;rsquo;ve usually done during the years past.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Imagepipe_4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brought back so many fond memories of celebrating the festival when we were kids. Starting right at 04:00 with &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/?s=kitta&#34;&gt;Kitta Mama&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s 1000 Walla, Appa and Amma&amp;rsquo;s push to get us that pre-dawn morning shower, the house bustling with activity as sweets and savories are consumed quicker than they&amp;rsquo;re made, neighbors drifting in and out exchanging wishes and gifts, kids bragging on the volume of firecracker purchase, bursting crackers near oblivious strangers in the colony, smoke of various hues of green and orange bellowing from that ‘snake’ firecracker, appa bursting the ‘lakshmi bomb’ using a pair of tongs, and amma -oh looking so beautiful- cautiously lighting the ‘sparkler’ while keeping an eye on all of us.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is one festival really close to my heart since it reminds me so much of the good times we had with Amma. I so wish she were around with us today and it&amp;rsquo;s just not fair that she left us so early. It&amp;rsquo;s been 21 years and it feels just yesterday we were on that &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2018/11/20/shasta/&#34;&gt;hospital terrace watching fireworks&lt;/a&gt; during her last Diwali. But then to think of it, nothing really is the same as before. The celebration across the colony is heavily dampened. Those old neighbors have moved out. Folks now use digital lights if at all they do light up their houses. Barely anyone is actually bursting fire crackers. In essence, it feels like the spirit of celebration is quite diluted for whatever reason. Time flies and I&amp;rsquo;m glad some memories remain etched.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy Diwali to you and your loved ones. There&amp;rsquo;s so much power in those tiny flickering flames.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jabbed</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/16/jabbed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/16/jabbed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since March 2020, I&amp;rsquo;ve had this internal debate of getting the Covid Vaccine mostly underlined by the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3d3bb2ac73.65468826&#34;&gt;science behind mRNA&lt;/a&gt; is fascinating and so is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3c8962f2a2.96282489&#34;&gt;engineering of the vaccine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every strand of mRNA is made up of four molecular building blocks called nucleosides. But in its altered, synthetic form, one of those building blocks, like a misaligned wheel on a car, was throwing everything off by signaling the immune system. So Karikó and Weissman simply subbed it out for a slightly tweaked version, creating a hybrid mRNA that could sneak its way into cells without alerting the body’s defenses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statnews&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We unfortunately &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/vaccinesafety/concerns/concerns-history.html%5D&#34;&gt;have not had a spectacular history&lt;/a&gt; with vaccines. With humans involved and the ensuing politics, money and power-plays; vaccines are built for the average human being. Then with anything manufactured and delivered at scale, we&amp;rsquo;re prone to Logistics and Supply chain Management issues.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Covid19 vaccines are not a once and done deal. The effects &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/607a14edb61f01.57427531&#34;&gt;last apparently at most a year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did cave in and got the first ‘jab&amp;rsquo; of the Moderna vaccine today at the Consulate. As with all vaccines and medical interventions, this was not quite an easy decision. The decision was probably 40% gut, 40% trusting the mechanics of the mRNA vaccine and 20% of &amp;lsquo;Why am I even considering it&amp;rsquo;. The drivers for the gut-feeling likely being:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Getting the vaccine would possibly break the link in transmitting the virus to an immune-compromised person. We live with our in-laws and that&amp;rsquo;s the least I can do for them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I consider myself to be a fairly young and healthy person and absolutely do not mind wearing masks and exercising social distancing. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve shamefully caught myself pulling down the mask during brief interactions with people. Despite best efforts, the masking system alone is not fool-proof.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; to be outdoors to stay healthy and be sane. Travel and Freedom are my primary &amp;lsquo;movers&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From an extremely exaggerated perspective, I see C19 as the Smallpox / Polio of this century. Few folks in the family are still reeling with the brutal after-effects of these diseases. I think I can take the risk of the possible side-effects for the marginal leg-up the vaccine might give my immune system in case I contract the virus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Folks in the family are leaning towards getting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/607a1f2977e8c3.93743514&#34;&gt;Covaxin&lt;/a&gt; vaccine. India is having it&amp;rsquo;s worst wave so far and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping we swing back downwards as sharply as we rose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>April 16, 2021 23:50</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/15/april-16-2021-2350/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/15/april-16-2021-2350/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh wow, Appa. Nee romba beautiful aa irrukai&amp;rdquo; - Shasta&amp;rsquo;s impromptu response on me wearing the white checked shorts&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Listening</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/10/16/listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/10/16/listening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20191017_040638-1200x1200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Morning muses with the little munchkin perched on top of her stack of books. Babbling, pointing, standing and now slowly trying to walk; this soon to be 11 brat is growing way too fast!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nawab land</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/09/01/nawab-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/09/01/nawab-land/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just back from an impromptu trip to Lucknow! Miss V got a few days off school, so we decided to fly north to visit Manni&amp;rsquo;s parents. Absolutely floored by the  city of the Nawabs and its numerous parks. Oh, but so hot and humid! While the prime intent was to spend time with Mama and Mami, we did get to hop around the city quite a bit and also indulge in the gastronomic pilgrimage!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 01 - Sikander Bagh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We head out to Sikander Bagh for a stroll in the National Botanical Research Institute. Drove past the fortified walls which once were stormed in by the British in 1857 during their seige of Lucknow. Feasted on some Kastha and Dahi-Jalebi for breakfast and devoured some &amp;lsquo;chat&amp;rsquo; in Nishat gunj for dinner. Shasta enjoyed the ride in the e-rickshaws!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery itemtag=&amp;ldquo;dl&amp;rdquo; icontag=&amp;ldquo;dt&amp;rdquo; captiontag=&amp;ldquo;dd&amp;rdquo; columns=&amp;ldquo;3&amp;rdquo; link=&amp;ldquo;post&amp;rdquo; size=&amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;title&amp;rdquo; thumb_width=&amp;ldquo;75&amp;rdquo; thumb_height=&amp;ldquo;75&amp;rdquo; thumb_size=&amp;ldquo;thumbnail&amp;rdquo; main_size=&amp;ldquo;thumbnail&amp;rdquo; tile_size=&amp;ldquo;thumbnail&amp;rdquo; fx=&amp;ldquo;slide&amp;rdquo; controls=&amp;ldquo;hide&amp;rdquo; timeout=&amp;ldquo;4000&amp;rdquo; speed=&amp;ldquo;1000&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;5950,5951&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;menu_order ID&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 02 - Janeshwar Park and Science center&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On landing in Lucknow, on our way home from the airport, we drove past quite a few impressively lit monuments and parks. Mayawati during her term as the CM apparently &amp;lsquo;invested&amp;rsquo; a lot in building parks and memorials. Lucknow did look very glamorous that night and we wanted to visit a few of the parks while we were here. We were bowled over by Janeshwar park that we visited on the second day morning. Reminded me of the historical state parks in the U.S.!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Later during the day, we took Miss V to the science center. While a few of the installations were rusty and not quite maintained, this is one good space for kids to spend a decent couple hours exploring around.  Aminabad was on cards for the day. However, with the heat, we decided  to save this for another trip.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery order=&amp;ldquo;ASC&amp;rdquo; itemtag=&amp;ldquo;dl&amp;rdquo; icontag=&amp;ldquo;dt&amp;rdquo; captiontag=&amp;ldquo;dd&amp;rdquo; columns=&amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; link=&amp;ldquo;post&amp;rdquo; size=&amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; id=&amp;ldquo;5948&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;5949,5954,5955,5961&amp;rdquo; orderby=&amp;ldquo;menu_order ID&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 03 - Bara Imambara, Chota Imambara, Roomi Darwaza, Chattar Manzil, Clock tower, Bhool Bhulaiya, Shahi Bawli&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Covered most of these historical spots on the third day. Bhool Bhulaiya and the Bawli were pretty interesting. Just as we were about to leave, a strong thunder-shower held us back for about an hour. Skipped Chota Imambara and head to Indira nagar(?) for a late lunch in a basement Dhaba. After a much needed nap at home, we head over to a Pappaji&amp;rsquo;s place for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; link=&amp;ldquo;post&amp;rdquo; size=&amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;5979,5981,5970,5969,5967,5972&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 04 - Ramakrishna Math and Mission Mangal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Decided to take it easy. Mama wanted to visit the Math and we gladly accompanied. Later that evening we head over to the recently constructed Umrao mall to watch Mission Mangal with Mami. Our first movie in the theater after Shasta&amp;rsquo;s birth! She slept through most of the movie and everyone did have a fabulous time!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids=&amp;ldquo;5988&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So glad we were able to make it to Lucknow! This was also Miss V&amp;rsquo;s first trip to the north and we&amp;rsquo;re so glad we were able to give her a glimpse of this part of the country. She sure does have a better appreciation for Hindi now!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shasta</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2018/11/20/shasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2018/11/20/shasta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about 2 AM and I am on a side bed in Sinai Hospital. Earlier today (yesterday) Meena and I brought into this world a sparkingly beautiful 7lb 5oz girl. I remember seeing Meena during the institute at TFI with some of her school kids and thinking she would be a wonderful mother one day. Eight years from then, as I see this little munchkin in the crib beside her, I am more than thankful for all that has led to this day. I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled beyond limits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20181130_2349301.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tara, Zara, Agni, Annapurna were all front runners for the name. With our mutual love for the mountains and belief that the name should exude power and confidence, we eventually zeroed in on Shasta. I first came across the name on a Dirtbag diaries podcast - &lt;a href=&#34;http://dirtbagdiaries.com/flying-deep/&#34;&gt;Flying Deep&lt;/a&gt;. I profusely liked the way it sounded and the fact that Mt. Shasta was a towering, potentially active volcano sealed the deal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m psyched that we&amp;rsquo;re naming her after a mountain. While climbing up a peak or on the ridge, I always feel the eerie and calming sense of belonging. It always reminds me of days spent in the hospital living by the day&amp;hellip;a mixed bag of memories I so wish, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have, yet I&amp;rsquo;m so thankful I do&amp;hellip; Somewhere deep under I knew Amma wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make it. She&amp;rsquo;d been swinging in and out of consciousness for several months now. One of those lucky days in November 1999, her vitals seemed reasonably stable. She was longing for some fresh air and I was able to finagle one of the nurses to take us outdoors. We took amma on a wheelchair to the terrace of the hospital. It was a dark, chilly and breezy night. Hyderabad was just about wrapping up its Diwali celebrations. Far down where our vision could stretch, every now and then a rocket would shoot up and the fireworks would brighten up the sky. Amma was thrilled! As another waft of cold air blew on the terrace, amma clenched my fists and said &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve never been this high on the mountains. This is the most beautiful sun rise I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen&amp;rdquo;. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take us a lot to figure out she was having yet another bout of hallucination. The last few months the medications were wrecking havoc. This time though on that terrace, I felt a sense of thankfulness. For this, was one of those moments when I could see that child-like sparkle in her eyes, something that would remain captured in my memories of her and something which I&amp;rsquo;d never see again&amp;hellip;forever. From that day, Mountains and more so sunrise on those ridges took a whole different meaning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few days back, as we floated the name within the family circle, one of my cousin&amp;rsquo;s mentioned Shasta meant &amp;rsquo;teacher&amp;rsquo; in Sanskrit. Meena and I met through a teaching fellowship and I thought it was pretty awesome that we ended up naming our kid - Shasta! Shasta, also happens to be a reference to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shasta_%28deity%29#Kerala&#34;&gt;south Indian Hindu deity&lt;/a&gt; that my ancestors have long worshiped. All in all we seem to have appeased all generations!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the middle name we decided to just leave it as R, depicting Ratna - amma&amp;rsquo;s name, Rajesh - a dear cousin of mine who committed suicide a few years back and Ramu anna - another cousin who &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2018/08/13/ramu-anna/&#34;&gt;very recently&lt;/a&gt; passed away fighting cancer. The hope is that we&amp;rsquo;re saliently reminded of them all through Shasta.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I can&amp;rsquo;t quite foresee the future, I believe we do have in mind the kind of person we would like to raise. The world at this point in time has a lot of negative things going on. We hope as Shasta grows and develops a personality of her own, she does so much more than what we&amp;rsquo;ve done to bring in more positivity around her.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving on...</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2018/08/14/moving-on.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2018/08/14/moving-on.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we stood there in front of the casket, me pouring the last drop of water in his mouth, memories flashed in front of my eyes. Of monkeys cornering us that early morning on their house terrace in Ahmedabad; Of walking on the busy roads in Habsiguda, him walking on my left, guarding me from the traffic and I craning my neck to look at him as he mentions how I would be wonderful doctor; Of  us both sitting beside Amma in the hospital bed and him explaining in &amp;lsquo;kid terms&amp;rsquo; what was likely happening in Amma&amp;rsquo;s brain as she was fighting her tumor; Of him and Sharath gate crashing wedding receptions in our colony; Of all the discussions we had on &amp;rsquo;living&amp;rsquo; life and making a concerted effort on spending more time with family; Of the weekend in Queens, NY during their visit to the east coast; Of Grouse Grind and the Dragon boat race, he wanted to do together; Of setting up a local cloud server and him wanting to get into software development and app design; Of all the outdoor trips we planned to do over the next few years; Of our visit to Allouette lake when we visited them a few years back in Vancouver; Of him making arrangements to get a ride for us from the airport to the hospital where he was the patient, Of him asking me not to leave that early when I visited him in June&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The person in the casket in no way resembled the person we&amp;rsquo;d known. Cancer had devoured him inside-out and it was excruciatingly painful to see him in this state. I was hoping beyond hope that this was all a bad dream and he would wake up, we&amp;rsquo;d call this a miracle and get back to our regular lives&amp;hellip;We knew the end was coming and looking at him in deep pain a few months back, I then hoped it would happen sooner than later&amp;hellip; but being there and to see his casket go into the furnace and realizing it&amp;rsquo;s all over, I wish I had dropped everything I was doing and spent more time with him over the last few months&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the flight back to Boston, as I was trying to make sense of it all, I was volleying between Ramu anna&amp;rsquo;s death this year and Rajesh&amp;rsquo;s suicide in 2015. I was reminded of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/08/24/voyager/&#34;&gt;podcast on Voyager1&lt;/a&gt; and Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s Pale Blue Dot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Pale_Blue_Dot1-286x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s us. On it everyone you love, everyone you know, everyone you ever heard of, every human being who ever was, lived out their lives. The aggregate of our joy and suffering, thousands of confident religions, ideologies, and economic doctrines, every hunter and forager, every hero and coward, every creator and destroyer of civilization, every king and peasant, every young couple in love, every mother and father, hopeful child, inventor and explorer, every teacher of morals, every corrupt politician, every “superstar,” every “supreme leader,” every saint and sinner in the history of our species lived there – on a mote of dust suspended in a sunbeam. &amp;ndash; Carl Sagan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the big scheme of things, we&amp;rsquo;re all so dispensable. Arguably, There&amp;rsquo;s so, so little that you have control over and there&amp;rsquo;s no rhyme or reason for certain things. Life is best lived, living in the moment and spending time with family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rest in peace, Ramu Anna. You were a terrific person and will be sorely missed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunrise at the confluence</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/10/15/sunrise-at-the-confluence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/10/15/sunrise-at-the-confluence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;@ Kanyakumari, India&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A glimpse of sunrise at the tip of the Indian subcontinent, where the Arabian Sea and the Bay of Bengal meet the Indian Ocean. Tourists throng to this overlook, right behind the Bagvathi Amman temple at the break of dawn (and the onset of dusk).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vivekananda memorial continues to be one of those few locations to be maintained sparking clean. Nothing much seems to have changed since my last visit to this place seven years ago. The shrouded Thiruvalluvar statue that&amp;rsquo;s to the far right talks volumes of the current political situation in the state. The ferry no longer stops at the statue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Appa&amp;rsquo;s 81st birthday (official). He had that sparkle in his eye&amp;rsquo;s when he was looking up to the sun rise above the horizon. Despite this being such a rushed trip, I&amp;rsquo;m so glad we could get him here. Climbing up one of the stairs on the Vivekananda memorial he mentioned this would probably be his last visit. Was quite disturbing to see him struggle through something that&amp;rsquo;s always been second nature. With old age his mobility seems to be drastically reducing. Hope over the next few years, we&amp;rsquo;re able to find better means of taking him to more places outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/favorite?tweet_id=920796903759011841&#34;&gt;like&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?tweet_id=920796903759011841&#34;&gt;reply&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/retweet?tweet_id=920796903759011841&#34;&gt;repost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/07/11/memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/07/11/memories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get into my house, I believe from the side entrance. Looks like there&amp;rsquo;s nobody in there. It&amp;rsquo;s mildly windy. Possibly from an open window? There&amp;rsquo;s a barely audible calming music from MS coming out from the bedroom. As I walk in, I notice TVM in the bed cocooned in a blanket, her eye&amp;rsquo;s glazed and probing deep in thought. I gently tap her and ask her if everything&amp;rsquo;s okay. She turns around and I somehow know she&amp;rsquo;s thinking of Amma. Tears well up in her eyes as she asks if we did everything we could. I&amp;rsquo;m petrified. I don&amp;rsquo;t have an answer for her and I&amp;rsquo;m left standing there for a seemingly long time&amp;hellip; All of a sudden I notice someone trying to open the window mesh and get the keys from the inside. Atchuth? I open the main door and see Nikhil, Sharath, Aparna and a few other kids. They say they&amp;rsquo;re back from Brueggers. I come back to the bedroom to check on TVM. She&amp;rsquo;s smiling as if nothing in the past really happened.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wait. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense. There&amp;rsquo;s no Brueggers in Habsiguda. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to a Brueggers myself. This can&amp;rsquo;t be real. I turn around and realize it&amp;rsquo;s 04:40am. Hop off the bed, into my yoga clothes and head to the kitchen. I&amp;rsquo;m insanely awake and fresh. As I work on different tasks in the kitchen the dream keeps playing in my mind&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Miss Me has long been saying I should write more about Amma. Unfortunately, most of my memories now only seem to be from her last few years in the hospital. Times mostly dabbled with pain&amp;hellip;I barely recollect any memories of me growing up with her around. Memories need triggers and someday hopefully when they kick in, I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to recollect more of the good times I spent with her&amp;hellip;If only I could get those back, I&amp;rsquo;d treasure them for life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/cropped-cropped-SP01-550afdebv1_site_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com&#34;&gt;Srikanth Perinkulam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vishu Kani</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/04/22/vishu-kani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/04/22/vishu-kani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VishuKani 2017. My first ever kani setup. Vishu has always been one of my favorite festivals. The simplicity and the depth of celebrations that Appa and Amma had for us, is something I&amp;rsquo;d always remember. May we all have a prosperous, enriching and mesmerizing year ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/FullSizeRender.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FullSizeRender.jpg&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Paruammai</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2010/04/11/meeting-paruammai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2010/04/11/meeting-paruammai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about 04:30Hrs and there&amp;rsquo;s not a single soul or bus in the stand. At about 05:00hrs, a tea vendor rides in on his bicycle. I check with him if there&amp;rsquo;s a direct bus to Pallavur to which he responds in affirmative stating the first one should be leaving at about 05:30hrs. He even obliges to get me on to the right bus once it comes in -  Buses in Kerala are mostly marked in Malayalam and unless you know to read the language, It becomes a bit difficult in boarding the right bus. I&amp;rsquo;m amazingly pleased and gulp about three glasses of his hot masala tea.Buses start rolling into the stand one by one. It so appears that this gentleman is quite popular in the Bus stand and all the Drivers seem to know him by the name. He individually goes about handing over tea and flower garlands[For the deities in the buses] to each of the drivers. Slowly the Bus stand comes to life with newspaper vendors and the omnipresent &amp;lsquo;Lottery ticket wallahs&amp;rsquo;. [I&amp;rsquo;m amazed at how the Lottery fever has struck Kerala. You&amp;rsquo;d find folks selling tickets at any given point of time at any given nook and corner of the state (religious places included!). Some day I should get back and try figuring out how this whole system works!]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At 05:30hrs, as promised I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;lsquo;packed off&amp;rsquo; in the right bus and the conductor is instructed to drop me off at Pallavur. The bus lazily winds up the narrow roads and in about an hour i&amp;rsquo;m asked to pop off the bus. I straddle through the village roads and finally manage to reach the first landmark that my dad had given -  A community pond just beside the Shiva temple. A bit of asking around and I finally make it to that distant relative&amp;rsquo;s house. This is the first time that I was meeting these people ever since I grew up and it takes a while to figure out where exactly they map on to me in the family tree. My main intention to come to Pallavur was to meet Paruammai. After easing out a bit with my newly found relatives, I check with them how I could get to her.  She apparently was staying a bit deeper in the village and I&amp;rsquo;m told that she should be coming by this road at about 08:30hrs. As I eagerly wait for her I&amp;rsquo;m lost in thought as to how she&amp;rsquo;d be faring.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At about 08:45hrs, Paruammai finally comes by. I&amp;rsquo;m excited looking at her still able bodied personality - She infact looked much much healthier than she was when she left us years back. Must probably be the village air and water! Just one change being that she&amp;rsquo;s now got even bigger holes in her ears! Apparently, she does not recognise me in first sight but as I talk slowly and remind her of the yesteryear&amp;rsquo;s she simply acknowledges with tears welling up in her eyes. A long conversation ensues of things small and big, of people and kids she was acquainted with, of relationships sweet and sour and of times that just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get back. I show her pics of the now &amp;lsquo;big&amp;rsquo; kids[My Brothers, Sisters and Cousins] and their children and in a moments jiffy she runs out of the house, calling in people from the village to tell them how happy she was to see the light of this day - to see the pictures of the kids of the kids who she herself had raised. The excitement in her eyes and voice told it all. That very moment, I realise my Kerala visit and purpose was solved. This day for sure is one of those best days in my life till date&amp;hellip;She now is working [still strong at this age!] in a village teachers house taking care of their pet dog.I&amp;rsquo;m not sure If she would be around the next time I come down. But the photograph and the video that I took with her would remain one of my most cherished possessions for time to come.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/10829560&#34;&gt;Paruammai at Pallavur - 23rd March 2010&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/user3566295&#34;&gt;Srikanth Perinkulam&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
