<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Urban-Lyf on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/urban-lyf/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Urban-Lyf on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/urban-lyf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Woman in the Mundu!</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2008/03/21/the-woman-in-the-mundu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2008/03/21/the-woman-in-the-mundu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The bus jerks along on the road as I get back home from Office. It&amp;rsquo;s only 6:30pm and I&amp;rsquo;ve still got about 20kms to traverse. That effectively translated to an hour&amp;rsquo;s time given the traffic situation at M&amp;rsquo;patnam. A colleague seated beside me is hooked to the Fountainhead in her hands and is already drooping. Damn and I&amp;rsquo;m here still awake. My gray cells surprisingly show no signs of tiredness and at the same time my mp3 player gets discharged totally.How better can things get !&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All I get to do is gape out of the window thinking nothing worthwhile. All of a sudden, there falls a drop on my semi protruding head and even before I realize, it starts drizzling. The first summer rain! People on the road start flurrying on the roads and kids start jumping all around. Amidst all this my sight chances on a frail old woman in the typical white malayali mundu( Dhothi) trying to stop an autorickshaw. For a second there was a sudden thought impulse passed on to my brain- Was this Paruammai?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spring from my seat , literally jerk the female beside me and jump out of the bus. Fortunately, the bus was round a corner and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much traffic. But even before I get close, the Auto driver pulls the rod and pushes off.All I get to see is a part of the mundu flirting with the wind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paruammai was more of a family member till a few years ago. She&amp;rsquo;d come in as a servant maid and soon became a part of the family . She&amp;rsquo;d helped taking care of me and ideally most of the kids in the family at Hyd right from when we were born! She&amp;rsquo;s been a part and parcel of every family function that I remember and would easily be notching 90 now. About four years ago, she left for her own native - Andhra, a place in Kerala. Old age was taking its toll and she wanted to spend time with people from her bloodline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I jump into another rickshaw and ask him to follow the other one. He skeptically gives me a look but nevertheless accedes. Traffic makes things worse and we happen to trail for sometime. The other auto takes a left a bit ahead and even before my guy follows the trail and turns around we&amp;rsquo;ve lost track. Lanes and diversions!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hop out and start walking across almost giving up. Just when i decide to get back, I notice a rustic building a few yards away. Something urges me to check it out. I walk towards it and there sight a board fading to cry out - Dasmar Old age home. The woman I saw on the roads is now walking towards the door with a pole in her hand. I knock uneasily on the gate to get her attention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;She turns around and I realise this wasn&amp;rsquo;t Paruammai. The woman limps towards the gate slowly and even before I open my mouth in a hoarse voice she blurts out - Maakevaru oddhu! Avalsinantha ayipoyindhi! ( We dont need anyone. All that had to be done is done!) .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m at loss of words. All I do is shamelessly walk back trying to find my way out of the maze. Back on the roads I hurl myself into an auto and am back home&amp;hellip;Hope Paruammai is hale and hearty wherever she is!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Forgoing one&amp;rsquo;s own relations for petty benefits? How insane people can get!!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CARE FOR YOUR PEOPLE!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
