<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/technology/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:41:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024-11-29 22:41:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/11/29/2024-11-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:41:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/11/29/2024-11-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just struck me that most of my disk drives are quite old. Almost all of them were salvaged from old laptops. Age does not necessarily equate to performance and I do have decent backups, but only a question of time before I see them going kaput. Living vicariously on the edge when it comes to self-hosting!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks - Feb 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/05/state-of-the-networks-feb-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/05/state-of-the-networks-feb-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A quick rundown on the state of the home-servers I run or applications I host on the cloud.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Published while listening to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://invidious.snopyta.org/watch?v=RlcY37n5j9M&#34;&gt;Malang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With our temporary relocation, I currently manage two &amp;lsquo;home-labs&amp;rsquo; - one which I remotely manage with a WireGuard tunnel and the other just a local-access only setup. The remote home-lab is essentially a Nextcloud server running on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dietpi.com/&#34;&gt;DietPi OS&lt;/a&gt; spun on an RPi4. I pulled down the HAProxy config on the fronting server since that was no longer required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Homelab-SoTN-Feb-2021-600x478.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The local home-lab currently encompasses four units:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ownyourbits.com/nextcloudpi/&#34;&gt;NextcloudPi&lt;/a&gt; running on an RPi3 and connected to a 1TB main drive: This has been our primary document and media backup servers silently chugging along for close to three years now!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osmc.tv/&#34;&gt;OSMC&lt;/a&gt; installed on another RPi3: With a 1TB media drive, Amazon video and Youtube addons this primarily serves as a secondary family Television. A bit on the sluggish end but does the job for now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DietPi running on an &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.odroid.com/odroid-xu4/odroid-xu4&#34;&gt;Odroid-XU4&lt;/a&gt;: Pi-Hole for Ad control and WireGuard to access the remote home-lab.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pop.system76.com/&#34;&gt;PoPOS&lt;/a&gt; running on an Intel NUC7: My primary workstation! An attached 1TB drive acts as the secondary backup for my NC setup and then I run sync jobs to a 256GB flash drive for a cold backup of the really important files.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then, on a remote VM I run a slew of services that handle most of my social and productivity tools. Fronted by Traefik and running in docker containers, the following services run on the 8GB server:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bookstackapp.com/&#34;&gt;Bookstack&lt;/a&gt; – Wiki software which I am currently using to help publish my dad’s second book&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://known.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;Known&lt;/a&gt; – I mostly use this as a quick bookmarking tool. I also post short updates or status notes here infrequently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wallabag.it/en&#34;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; – Read-later app&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/14/guyon-flats-and-tuffys-tavern-trail/&#34;&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt; – Way better than Instagram and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixel.srkn.org/sriperinkulam&#34;&gt;my go-to space&lt;/a&gt; to post individual images&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://selfoss.aditu.de/&#34;&gt;Minflux&lt;/a&gt; – The light-weight feed-reader that I pipe all my RSS subscriptions to&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium&#34;&gt;Trilium Notes&lt;/a&gt; – A terrific Evernote alternative with awesome Markdown support&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbernhard/signal-cli-rest-api&#34;&gt;Signal-CLI&lt;/a&gt; – I use this for server trigger notifications to be sent via SMS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://etherpad.org/&#34;&gt;Etherpad&lt;/a&gt; – Quick, collaborative notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptpad.fr/&#34;&gt;CryptPad&lt;/a&gt; - Collaboration suite for documents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Calibre - I use this to manage &lt;a href=&#34;https://lib.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;my digital books collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lychee - A nifty photo gallery where I currently save my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/08/26/stamp-collection-digitized/&#34;&gt;digital stamps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;WordPress – I run 4 instances of WordPress – Portals for folks in my family&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nextcloud – This one’s more to test the recent releases before I deploy them on my home-lab&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometime down the lane I would like to setup a &lt;a href=&#34;https://snikket.org/&#34;&gt;Snikket instance&lt;/a&gt; for family chats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DIY Passport Photos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/25/diy-passport-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/25/diy-passport-photos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick and simple way to make and print your own passport photos[PP]. I&amp;rsquo;ve used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt; - which is a fabulous photo editing tool. They have a nifty &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;installer&lt;/a&gt; irrespective of which OS you use and have stood the test of time. There are a slew of different ways to arrive at the final product. This method has worked well for me over the past and based on your specific needs, you might have to alter a few settings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s say you have the below image that you&amp;rsquo;d like to make PP&amp;rsquo;s out of and you&amp;rsquo;d like them to be 2&amp;rsquo;&amp;lsquo;x2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; with other constraints laid out &lt;a href=&#34;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/passports/how-apply/photos.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This one&amp;rsquo;s obviously a bad image to start out with, but should be a good test subject!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Dummy-1-150x150.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isolate and sanitize&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ideally, you&amp;rsquo;d want to get a good photo of the subject. Make sure s/he is standing against a light background and there&amp;rsquo;s sufficient uniform lighting on the face. If you&amp;rsquo;re not able to get that you&amp;rsquo;ll have to &amp;lsquo;sanitize&amp;rsquo; the image first. And here&amp;rsquo;s how we go about doing that:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open the image in GIMP and scale the image such that the distance between the top of the head and the bottom of the chin is about 1.1875 inch [Midway between 1 inch and 1.375 inch - The specs that was mentioned in the Travel web portal].&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To measure: Press &amp;lsquo;Shift+M&amp;rsquo; - This is the shortcut for the measure tool. Use the mouse pointer to measure distance. The measurements should be visible at the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To scale: Navigate to &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Image&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; on the top navigation bar and then select &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Scale Image&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. Change the &lt;em&gt;Image size&lt;/em&gt; attribute to % and scale down to the requisite level. For instance, I had to scale down to 60% since my initial Head-chin length was about 50mm.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally measure the resulting image&amp;rsquo;s head to chin length in pixels. In our test case this was 366 pixels after the scaling. So our DPI [Dots (Pixels) per inch] is 366/1.1875 ~=308. We&amp;rsquo;ll use this later to crop our image.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Before-scaling-1200x652.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/scale-image-1200x656.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. If your image does not have a uniform light background or has shadows [Like in our case] here&amp;rsquo;s how you digitally make the background white. Do note that certain agencies/services do not accept digitally altered images - So make sure you have some great lighting!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Select the Paths tool - Shortcut &amp;lsquo;B&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use your mouse and make a path around the subject. Make sure you close out the loop at the end by pressing Ctrl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Convert the path to a selection by pressing on the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Selection from path&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; on the &lt;strong&gt;Path&lt;/strong&gt; sidebar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Selection-from-path-600x326.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Press Ctrl+I to invert the selection and press Delete on your keyboard to erase the background.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve cleared the background, export the image as a jpeg and save for further processing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create the 2&amp;rsquo;&amp;lsquo;x2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; image&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since we have a 308 DPI image , The 2&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot; image would be about [308x2, 308x2] pixels = 617x617 pixels. [Your values would obviously be different based on where you started!]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To crop out our 2&amp;quot;x2&amp;quot; image, click on the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Rectangular Select tool&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; - [Shortcut R]. Then on the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;Rectangular Select&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo; sidebar, check the &lt;em&gt;Fixed&lt;/em&gt; checkbox and set the parameter to &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;size&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. Also further below switch the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;No guides&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; drop-down to &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Center Lines&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. Now click on the image and you should see a square box with central guide lines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/2x2-grab-600x326.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Move the box and center it so as to fit the image well within the box. Finally, Right-click on the Image, select &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Image&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; and then &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Crop to Selection&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build the 4&amp;quot;x6&amp;quot; canvas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lets create a new image canvas to hold our 6 PP photos. Use the shortcut Ctrl+N to create a new image. Set the image size as 4&amp;quot;x6&amp;quot;. Open the advanced options and set the X and Y resolution to 308 pixels/in. While here you might also want to set the &lt;em&gt;Fill&lt;/em&gt; option to &lt;em&gt;White&lt;/em&gt;. Now that we have the base canvas ready, navigate to Image&amp;gt;Guides&amp;gt;New Guide(By Percent) and create two horizontal (33.33%,66.66%) and one vertical(50.00%) guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Canvas-1200x675.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Guides-1200x675.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now switch back to the previous GIMP window that has the 2&amp;quot;x2&amp;quot; image. Select all with Ctrl+A, Copy with Ctrl+C, switch over to the 4&amp;quot;x6&amp;quot; canvas and paste it over six times with Ctrl+V. Move the pasted images to the individual boxes. The guides will help snap the the images correctly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Final-4x6-1-1200x652.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! You now have a stellar looking 4&amp;quot;x6&amp;quot; canvas that you can export to a jpeg/jpg format and print out on a matte photo card either at home or any of the external printing centers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital reset</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/10/digital-reset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/10/digital-reset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been sitting on the ledge for a while now and Whatsapp&amp;rsquo;s latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ffaa21254e415.40990025&#34;&gt;ultimatum&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; what I needed to see myself out the doors. I value my freedom and privacy - way more than the perceived convenience and I&amp;rsquo;ve deleted my Whatsapp account for good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since FB bought Whatsapp in 2014, they&amp;rsquo;ve been working on building a feature-set that would keep users tethered to the network - read receipts, web clients, weeding out third party clients, voice calls, removing the 1$ annual fee, file sharing, encryption, desktop clients, video calls, customer service platform for enterprises, status, enhanced video call features - you get it. The most recent move is a strategic attempt to enhance their monetizing pipeline by building the framework to better mine metadata across its various platforms - Whatsapp, Instagram, Facebook and CrowdTangle. In growing economies, Payments has been one realm they have had their eyes on for a while now and this latest move will turbo-boost that intent and help them compete with PayTM, Google and Amazon Payment systems. I&amp;rsquo;m surprised they took 6 years to get here though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Users currently have until Feb 8, 2021 to agree. Very few of the millions of users will end up deleting their accounts since most just cannot see beyond Whatsapp and the mainstream messaging platforms. Given its huge user base and the network effect, It&amp;rsquo;s terrifically socially engineered to keep you from moving out to other apps because of the perceived benefits. Also how do you move your family and then the extended network out of a system that is already so inter-twined? If most of your connections don&amp;rsquo;t move where&amp;rsquo;s the draw in moving out? And honestly, I would have probably stayed had they given me an option to opt-out of its most recent terms and conditions. As a business, I know you&amp;rsquo;re eyeing the honey pot - But hey, not at my expense, free will and something that you shove down my throat. Good riddance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I use(d) Whatsapp primarily to stay connected with close family. I&amp;rsquo;m coercing nudging them to move over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.signal.org/&#34;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://delta.chat/en/&#34;&gt;Delta-chat&lt;/a&gt;. Surprisingly, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that difficult to get them to move. I should have done this several months back…I created groups on Signal and shared those individual links in the Whatsapp groups that I was part of, left a message and immediately deleted my account not waiting for many responses or questions. Majority accepted and are now on Signal! And for those that don&amp;rsquo;t, there&amp;rsquo;s always the old school way of connecting via SMS/voice calls. My FB and Instagram accounts are in dormant mode for the last few years now and the only social space I&amp;rsquo;m ‘active’ is on this blog. Since moving over my RSS feeds to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/miniflux/&#34;&gt;miniflux&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m more actively following people&amp;rsquo;s blogs and find that way more enriching than mainstream media. I&amp;rsquo;m gunning on the premise that if someone really wants to get in touch with me, they will figure out how to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Love these digital resets. See you on the other side!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PS: Before deleting your account, If you do want to archive your chat history, make sure you manually &lt;em&gt;export&lt;/em&gt; and not backup all your chats prior to moving. The backup option on Whatsapp doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much since the messages are encrypted and Whatsapp deletes the backups too when the account is deleted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephemeral devices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/06/ephemeral-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/06/ephemeral-devices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is fascinating! A few GPS devices apparently had a mild(?) &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ff48e143fb7f0.93623598&#34;&gt;path offset issue&lt;/a&gt; few days ago:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The issue has to do with the ephemeris data file, also called the EPO file (Extended Prediction Orbit) or Connected Predictive Ephemeris (CPE). Or simply the satellite pre-cache file. That’s the file that’s delivered to your device on a frequent basis (usually every few days). This file is what makes your watch near-instantly find GPS satellites when you go outside. It’s basically a cheat-sheet of where the satellites are for the next few days, or up to a week or so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice this on my Forerunner 235 but I find it super intriguing to read about the &amp;lsquo;inner workings&amp;rsquo; of the background handshake. When I first got the Forerunner 235, I was amazed at how quickly it latched on to the satellites in contrast to the Forerunner 305 that I was actively using then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple decades ago when you bought a new &amp;lsquo;gadget&amp;rsquo;, you would get not only a &amp;lsquo;how-to&amp;rsquo; but also a technical sheet outlining the inner workings of the device. I miss seeing those sheets now!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA, RNA, Vaccines and Humans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/28/dna-rna-vaccines-and-humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/12/28/dna-rna-vaccines-and-humans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been meandering through &lt;a href=&#34;https://berthub.eu/index.html&#34;&gt;Bert&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s webpage and a few other sites - Such a treasure trove of information on the C-19 vaccine and biology/technology in general. No seriously, dive into these links for some great layman(ish) explanation of DNA, RNA, Vaccines and what not!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3c8962f2a2.96282489&#34;&gt;Reverse Engineering the source code of the BioNTech/Pfizer SARS-CoV-2 Vaccine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea38322bb2a0.08041300&#34;&gt;No, Really, mRNA Vaccines Are Not Going To Affect Your DNA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3d3bb2ac73.65468826&#34;&gt;The story of mRNA: From a loose idea to a tool that may help curb Covid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3e5f534579.64795290&#34;&gt;I Made a Covid-19 Vaccine in my Kitchen and it Worked&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: These links point to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;Wallabag instance&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d much prefer linking to the original article. However, I find this as a good way to save information which I can access later even if the original source vanishes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting drives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/01/encrypting-drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/11/01/encrypting-drives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier last week one of my external hard-disks went kaput. Though it&amp;rsquo;s fair to assume the recent travel could have led to this, my guess is that it was just a case of an ill-fated drive. While I did lose all the data on that drive, I thankfully had duplicate copies of the over 200GB data on other drives or machines. This is the first time that I&amp;rsquo;m losing a hard-drive and I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I was prudent enough to have multiple copies. All thanks to the folks over at Backblaze who frequently &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/category/cloud-storage/hard-drive-stats/&#34;&gt;publish hard-drive failure statistics&lt;/a&gt; on their stock!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20201017_100233-1200x1200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, losing that data got me thinking if I was really wise in just storing that data naked without any encryption. If I did want to claim the warranty on the drive, I will have to send over the hard-drive to Seagate. I am just not comfortable sending it over now since technically, most if not all of it, can be forensically retrieved. On that thought while researching on possible encryption tools, I landed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.veracrypt.fr/&#34;&gt;VeraCrypt&lt;/a&gt;. I instantly formatted my backup drives, setup an encrypted container and pointed my selfhosted Nextcloud installation to that virtual &amp;lsquo;drive&amp;rsquo;. The initial formatting does take time since VeraCrypt replaces data bit-by-bit and creates a clean slate. Once that is done, decrypting the data is just a matter of seconds. While at it, I also subjected all my other hard-drives to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/S.M.A.R.T.&#34;&gt;SMART&lt;/a&gt; tests and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Badblocks&#34;&gt;badblock&lt;/a&gt; tests to make sure they were following suit!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been about two weeks and I am super impressed with the ease and functionality of Veracrypt. It definitely is an additional step in the workflow. However, as they say - Privacy comes at a cost and I am willing to go that extra mile for an overall peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini yet mighty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/21/mini-yet-mighty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/08/21/mini-yet-mighty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had my eyes on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/products/boards-kits/nuc.html&#34;&gt;Intel NUC&lt;/a&gt; for a while now. My current laptop has been on a downward spiral and a few days back, when I came across a fabulous deal on eBay for an unboxed but unused NUC, I took the dive and ordered it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With 16GB RAM, 256GB NVMe SSD, 8TH Gen Core i7 Pro processor and Windows 10 Pro pre-installed - This is the most powerful machine I&amp;rsquo;ve owned. Agreed speed and performance is all relative. I&amp;rsquo;m just amazed that all of this fits in a tiny 4&amp;quot;x 4&amp;quot;x 1&amp;quot; box!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/odfywNUIw08ldUgYLl3wgoarJq9gnPRPxRJ7JXbY.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While at it, I also decided to switch over from &lt;a href=&#34;https://elementary.io/&#34;&gt;ElementaryOS&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pop.system76.com/&#34;&gt;PopOS&lt;/a&gt;. The PopOS install was a breeze. After a quick drive-partition all it took was probably a couple minutes to install the OS! Super impressed with the UI and the tiling feature on large screens is crisp!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks – Jun 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/18/state-of-the-networks-jun-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/06/18/state-of-the-networks-jun-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A quick rundown on the state of the home-servers I run or applications I host on the cloud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My &amp;lsquo;Homelab&amp;rsquo; setup has not changed much since my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/02/04/state-of-the-networks-jan-2020/&#34;&gt;last update in January&lt;/a&gt;. I did add in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/switched/&#34;&gt;switch&lt;/a&gt; and installed a wireguard vpn on the RPI 3B+ that fronts as a reverse proxy for the Nextcloud media devices. I also got a Seagate 2TB drive and built two partitions into it. One acts as a backup for my Nextcloud files and the other is a &amp;lsquo;cold backup&amp;rsquo; of my Hetzner cloud instance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/State-of-the-Network-Jun-2020--1200x977.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For personal use, I maintain two remote cloud servers on Hetzner:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hetzner 01&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first server essentially handles most of my social and productivity tools. Fronted by Traefik and running in docker containers, the following services run on the 8GB server:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bookstackapp.com/&#34;&gt;Bookstack&lt;/a&gt; - Wiki software which I am currently using to help publish my dad&amp;rsquo;s second book&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://known.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;Known&lt;/a&gt; - FB alternative. I mostly use this as a quick bookmarking tool. I also post short updates or status notes here infrequently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wordpress  - I run 4 instances of Wordpress - Portals for folks in my family.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wallabag.it/en&#34;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; - Read-later app&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/14/guyon-flats-and-tuffys-tavern-trail/&#34;&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt; - My go-to space to post individual images.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://selfoss.aditu.de/&#34;&gt;Selfoss&lt;/a&gt; - The light-weight feed-reader that I pipe all my RSS subscriptions to.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nextcloud - This one&amp;rsquo;s more to test the recent releases before I deploy them on my homelab.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium&#34;&gt;Trilium Notes&lt;/a&gt; - My go-to place to save quick notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbernhard/signal-cli-rest-api&#34;&gt;Signal-CLI&lt;/a&gt; - I use this for server trigger notifications to be sent via SMS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mattermost - Slack alternative&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Etherpad - Quick, collaborative notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hetzner 02:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This server hosts my Matrix and Jitsi Conference applications. While at it, I also have a Riot instance running in parallel that fronts the Synapse install.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switched!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/17/switched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/17/switched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far I had all the micro-servers in the home network connected either to a LAN port or to an Orbi Satellite. This week I implemented a simple 8 port un-managed TP-Link switch into my &amp;lsquo;homelab&amp;rsquo;. Costed just about 18 bucks with a price-match from amazon and it has tremendously improved upload/download speeds! Also it&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool to visually see that the RPi3B+ boards are being throttled at 10/100Mbps while the RPi4 is rummaging at 1000Mbps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While at it, I re-purposed a few card-board boxes and built a bare bones stack. Ain&amp;rsquo;t pretty does absolutely does the job!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20200517_030654-868x1200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 19 - feeds and sessions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/10/weeknote-19-feeds-and-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/10/weeknote-19-feeds-and-sessions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few things that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weather&amp;rsquo;s been pretty erratic this week. We also had a mild dusting yesterday out of the blue! Might consider heading out for a hike later today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I nudged Meena to write more. We&amp;rsquo;ve had some interesting discussions on Yoga and other things over the past week and I do think she has a ton to share! She&amp;rsquo;s also planning to train for a 50miler which I am super excited about! Oh and beyond all that marketing ploy, Happy Mothers&amp;rsquo; day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shasta&amp;rsquo;s talking a lot more now. Pretty sure her verbal diarrhea is soon going to start soon too!  The other day, while sitting with Appa she said something to the effect of &amp;lsquo;i-pae&amp;rsquo; pointing to the ipad. Grandfather and daughter are totally connecting on these gadgets!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Git: I agree on many levels with &lt;a href=&#34;https://kevq.uk/confession-i-have-no-idea-how-to-use-git/&#34;&gt;what Kev posted recently&lt;/a&gt; about Github. I enjoy working on and deploying software tools. What I do not enjoy is the whole git pull, push, fork thing!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sessions: I am running a session later this week for the Khat-pat folks on self hosting. Planning to keep it mostly hands-on and crisp. The idea is to get them started on taking better control of their presence on the interwebs! I&amp;rsquo;d also love to join the Indieweb folks one of these days. They have &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.indieweb.org/2020/05/online-indieweb-meetup-nyc-vkY32vBfCTEJ&#34;&gt;one coming up on the 20th&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tools: Earlier this week, I came across e-mail cloaking services - &lt;a href=&#34;https://simplelogin.io/&#34;&gt;Simplelogin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://anonaddy.com/&#34;&gt;Anondaddy&lt;/a&gt;. Love the idea and I might give them a shot the next time I subscribe or sign-up for a service.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feed Readers: Over the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve used multiple feed readers - Netvibes, TheOldReader, FreshRSS and Fever. They were all good in specific aspects but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really find them to be that one tool which I could use to consume the inter-webs my way. Earlier this week I decided to self-host one and narrowed down to FreshRSS, miniflux and selfoss. After a few iterations of deploying and testing, I stuck with &lt;a href=&#34;https://selfoss.aditu.de/&#34;&gt;selfoss&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s super light-weight and has all the specific features I was looking for.  To deploy it on docker, I used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/28/deploying-known-on-a-docker-stack/&#34;&gt;boiler-plate template that I created earlier&lt;/a&gt; when setting up my &lt;a href=&#34;https://known.srkn.org&#34;&gt;known&lt;/a&gt; instance.  The gist file for the docker-compose is &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/bf31682e6d9805ac29d6e4ff02bacb28&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The install should take you at most 10 minutes assuming you have the base framework setup. What I do love about selfoss is the ability to push articles over to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;wallabag&lt;/a&gt; instance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trilium: I&amp;rsquo;ve moved most of my notes over to Trilium and I am absolutely loving it! While it&amp;rsquo;s hierarchical, it is also setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium/wiki/Patterns-of-personal-knowledge-base&#34;&gt;not to be one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb322c0461ff3.59682906&#34;&gt;Time-restricted eating&lt;/a&gt;: Philip &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philipbrewer.net/2020/05/03/experiments-with-time-restricted-eating/&#34;&gt;referenced this article recently&lt;/a&gt; and I think it&amp;rsquo;s brilliant! Also went ahead and signed up for Rhonda&amp;rsquo;s podcast.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb705c2235124.51234929&#34;&gt;Tracking using ultrasound frequencies&lt;/a&gt;: Whoa! This totally blew my mind! If google uses it to connect your devices with chrome cast, what&amp;rsquo;s really stopping them from using it to track what you are watching? And now how do you block that invasion?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb6f8cbd8a783.67620597&#34;&gt;Workplaces in the era&lt;/a&gt;: Firms will have additional pressure from (or will be incentivised by) their insurance companies to have monitoring in place. Over the span of few months, this will be the new normal. Looking back, haven&amp;rsquo;t we all got used to keying-in and out at our workplaces?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb700e76826f2.47966883&#34;&gt;We kill people based on metadata&lt;/a&gt;: Quite a lot is changed since 2014. What hasn&amp;rsquo;t though is how fragmented and withdrawn several government and private entities are even in times of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb7034fba3519.79379071&#34;&gt;The mystic veil of End-to-End encryption&lt;/a&gt;: Interesting read on the data sharing between these apps.  The other day I was wondering how &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bark.us/&#34;&gt;Bark&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s able to access messages from these apps. Likely they have something on these lines drifting underneath? While I love the concept of the app and the benefits it provides, I did cringe and walk away because I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how they&amp;rsquo;d be handling the data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating over to Trilium notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/07/migrating-over-to-trilium-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/05/07/migrating-over-to-trilium-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS: For step-by-step instructions read &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/06/installing-trilium-notes/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post instead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had my eyes on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium&#34;&gt;Trilium notes&lt;/a&gt; since last year. Having setup a robust docker framework &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/24/weeknote-17-covid19-webmentions-and-migrations/&#34;&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to test Trilium out. Gave it a test run this morning and am way impressed with its&amp;rsquo; functionalities! With docker, installation was super easy and I am strongly leaning towards using Trilium as my primary note application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The yml file to get this running on docker (swarm) is in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/60323d29922069887f627ccedc65bad3&#34;&gt;github gist&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;d obviously need to have docker installed, docker swarm running with the traefik container and the domain mapped as needed. My &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/19/self-hosting-jitsi-video-conferencing/&#34;&gt;Jitsi post&lt;/a&gt; has this outlined further.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I haven&amp;rsquo;t spent a fair amount of time diving deep into the setup, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick first impression:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beautiful interface that can be as sparse or as detailed as you&amp;rsquo;d like it to be&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Encrypted by default and further protected sessions for sensitive notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A note-info section that details attributes and link-maps&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notes can be &amp;lsquo;cloned&amp;rsquo; under multiple places in a tree&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Code scripting, tables, markdown, images, files - It&amp;rsquo;s got it all!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Web clipper for quick screen and context grabs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Export and Import functionalities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No mobile apps yet! However, it does have a mobile front-end which should be a good alternative&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No multi-user support yet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was exploring Joplin as an alternative initially but decided to stick with Trilium since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://joplinapp.org/&#34;&gt;Joplin app&lt;/a&gt; currently has limited functionality (Creating nested trees in the mobile app). Meena&amp;rsquo;s been looking at switching over from her current Evernote setup and I think this might be a terrific replacement for her. Was never really a fan of Evernote and that dislike strengthened further when I had to install the app either on a Mac or PC to export my content! I am so glad we have the strength of open-source to weigh against these silo&amp;rsquo;ist setups!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Known on a docker stack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/04/28/deploying-known-on-a-docker-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/04/28/deploying-known-on-a-docker-stack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To migrate my php applications that did not have a handy docker-compose available, I needed a vanilla setup for my stack-based docker environment. &lt;a href=&#34;https://withknown.com/opensource/&#34;&gt;Known&lt;/a&gt; is one of those apps and so the first step was to build that PHP environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting up a Dockerhub repository and building a custom PHP image&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[If you decide to use my image, you would not have to build this yourself. Skip ahead to the Deploying Known section]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most php based apps also need specific extensions built-in. While I am sure they&amp;rsquo;re out there on the Docker hub repository, I was not able to easily find any images that met my specific needs [php extensions for gd, zip, pdo_mysql etc]. So I went ahead and &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/sriperinkulam/php-7.4.3-apache-buster-plus&#34;&gt;setup my own repository on Docker Hub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Something I learnt today was that a docker stack only accepts pre-built images. Which essentially means you cannot use the regular &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/commandline/build/&#34;&gt;build command&lt;/a&gt; on the fly in your docker-compose file. A quick work-around to that is to build the image locally and then publish it to a public repository from where the stack can easily access it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a dockerfile: &lt;code&gt;sudo nano dockerfile&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Copy over contents from &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/26d8702d946a8bad22d7623892be816c&#34;&gt;my dockerfile gist&lt;/a&gt;. Edit or update if you need any additional extensions. Do note that I am pulling a debian buster image here. An alpine image would be optimal but lets&amp;rsquo; run with this for now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Build the image locally: &lt;code&gt;docker build -t sriperinkulam/php-7.4.3-apache-buster-plus:latest .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edit the image and tag name as needed. If your gist file is defined correctly, the image should be ready in a few minutes. It took me a few iterations to get this working with all the extensions I needed and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t give you any errors during the build process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Login to your Dockerhub repo: &lt;code&gt;docker login&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Push your image over to your repository: &lt;code&gt;docker push sriperinkulam/php-7.4.3-apache-buster-plus:latest&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Within a few minutes, your image should be available for easy fetch whenever needed!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting up and deploying the Known install&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a folder for the known installation:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir known &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd known&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Copy over my &amp;lsquo;known.yml&amp;rsquo; gist from &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/9ea9b57a052629ed5b75071c2bafdb00&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and paste into a known.yml file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano known.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is where we use the image we built earlier! Make sure you update the passwords there-in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create an &amp;lsquo;app&amp;rsquo; folder. This is where we will copy in the core known package.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir app &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd app&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marcus-povey.co.uk/known/&#34;&gt;Marcus Povey&lt;/a&gt; does the heavy lifting of packaging the known install &amp;lsquo;unofficially&amp;rsquo;. Download his latest pre-packaged release from &lt;a href=&#34;https://withknown.marcus-povey.co.uk/&#34;&gt;his portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget https://withknown.marcus-povey.co.uk/&amp;lt;package&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally unzip/untar the package.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Step back into the main &amp;lsquo;known&amp;rsquo; directory and deploy the stack that we defined in the known.yml file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ..&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;DOMAIN=known.domain.org SCHEME=https docker stack deploy -c known.yml known&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Assuming you&amp;rsquo;ve already setup the traefik container, as mentioned in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/19/self-hosting-jitsi-video-conferencing/&#34;&gt;Jitsi post&lt;/a&gt;, you should now have Known up and running. Navigate to the domain and you should see the warmup page.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key in the db credentials that you setup in the &lt;em&gt;known.yml&lt;/em&gt; file. The database would need to be set as &lt;em&gt;mariadb,&lt;/em&gt; since that&amp;rsquo;s how we&amp;rsquo;ve defined it in the known.yml file. Also make sure you have the &lt;em&gt;Uploads&lt;/em&gt; folder writable by www-data:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo chown -R www-data /var/www/html/Uploads/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Setup your user account and proceed with the regular administration controls!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 17 - Covid19, Webmentions and Migrations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/04/24/weeknote-17-covid19-webmentions-and-migrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/04/24/weeknote-17-covid19-webmentions-and-migrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few articles, podcasts, tools, videos and music that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week I got a better handle at deploying and maintaining docker images. With that squared out, I decided to decommission the Digital Ocean servers that I had setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/03/02/migrations-workflows/&#34;&gt;back in 2017&lt;/a&gt; and migrate the applications over to my Hetzner server. I no longer have to rely on ServerPilot. All my applications are now deployed as docker containers fronted by #Traefik as a reverse proxy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The jitsi server instance I &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/19/self-hosting-jitsi-video-conferencing/&#34;&gt;deployed last week&lt;/a&gt; has been serving pretty well so far! I tweaked it further to enable &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.radiumz.org/en/article/local-recording-jitsi-meet&#34;&gt;local recording&lt;/a&gt;. Meena has been using it to run her online Yoga sessions and she can now also use it to record the podcast that she soon plans to start! Session recording and live-streaming is something I still need to configure in my current setup. The logs indicate it&amp;rsquo;s failing on the Jibri handshake and that&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ll need to figure out once I have a bit more time in hand.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other actionable tasks on the tech front include figuring out a swift way to deploy PHP based applications on Docker. I still need to port over my Known and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixel.srkn.org/sriperinkulam&#34;&gt;PixelFed&lt;/a&gt; applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.philipbrewer.net/&#34;&gt;Philip&lt;/a&gt; nudged me to look into my webmentions. The theme I previously had wasn&amp;rsquo;t displaying them as comments. I needed a bit of a &amp;lsquo;creativity boost&amp;rsquo; and decided to use a new theme. Really liked the McLuhan theme by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.andersnoren.se/teman/mcluhan-wordpress-theme/&#34;&gt;Anders Noren&lt;/a&gt; and decided to give it a spin. Noticed &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/support/topic/mcluhan-comments-fetched-are-from-a-different-post/#new-topic-0&#34;&gt;a minor issue with the comments section&lt;/a&gt; and was easily able to fix it. I do however want to make a few tweaks to it, which I hopefully will get around attending to over the next few weeks. I also have my eye on &lt;a href=&#34;https://prtksxna.com/&#34;&gt;Prateek&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/themes/zuari/&#34;&gt;Zuari theme&lt;/a&gt; which is deeply &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/&#34;&gt;indieweb&lt;/a&gt; compliant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last evening, &lt;a href=&#34;https://atchuth.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Atchuth&lt;/a&gt; mentioned he&amp;rsquo;s now using his RPi4 as a full fledged desktop machine. He&amp;rsquo;s moved over from DietPi to the Raspbian OS. Makes sense given his current use-case. Sharath on the other hand is still using his RPi 4 predominantly as a Nextcloud server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week has been great in terms of re-connecting with some good old friends! We&amp;rsquo;re planning a re-union sometime next year. 20 year since we finished school! Phew!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Khat-pat makers group that I am part of is now getting more traction and it&amp;rsquo;s awesome just hearing out the cool things that other folks are doing. This week&amp;rsquo;s session was on building drones from scratch!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also got around connecting with the kids I taught 10 years ago! They&amp;rsquo;ve all moved on to college and are into various things now. One kid wanted to become a stellar teacher and this  is one of the best messages I&amp;rsquo;ve received so far!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last night we played a few good rounds of Pictionary/Dumb-charades with the kids. Shasta had a terrific time just watching the &amp;lsquo;adults&amp;rsquo; in their elements. You never get too old for this game!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting podcasts this week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Picturing Data: Monocle&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://monocle.com/extensions/monocle/bin/mp3&#34;&gt;https://monocle.com/extensions/monocle/bin/mp3&lt;/a&gt;_downloader.php?file=https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/788260468/download/&amp;amp;filename=monocle_on_design_442.mp3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting tools this week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://termux.com/&#34;&gt;Termux app&lt;/a&gt; has been an amazing value-add to my phone for those quick server check-in&amp;rsquo;s!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outline.com/agNcAx&#34;&gt;‘We can’t go back to normal’: How will coronavirus change the world?&lt;/a&gt;: 2020 will be etched in the memories of most people living today as one that drastically changed how we as humans functioned. As Covid19 spreads across various countries, it&amp;rsquo;s influencing and compelling dire actions. What was considered to be impossible at various level, is now just a quick decision point - Financial stimulus, vaccine production, remote work and schooling to name a prominent few. As we build resistance to the virus as a society and consequently as the adrenaline that&amp;rsquo;s currently rampant drains out, we&amp;rsquo;re going to see the fallout&amp;rsquo;s of our actions or several inaction&amp;rsquo;s thereof. Assuming another event of this magnitude does not occur over the next decade, the world is going to need a major overhaul to recover from the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ea2f0cbab1fa1.31532716&#34;&gt;Beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide to PGP&lt;/a&gt;: A simple and easy read on PGP with actionable guidance for non-tech folks out there. It&amp;rsquo;s given that over the next few months most countries are going to erode into the privacy of its citizens. Policies that are brought into effect now for surveillance and tracing will overarchingly become the norm and will be almost impossible to retract. It&amp;rsquo;s critical that we act now to safeguard what little privacy we can. It&amp;rsquo;s never been about - &amp;lsquo;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing that I have to hide.&amp;rsquo; Ignorance can and will heavily be mis-appropriated for someone else&amp;rsquo;s benefit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5e9ecbae16ccb0.15652872&#34;&gt;Why one Neuroscientist started blasting his core&lt;/a&gt;: Neural pathways, stress control systems and of course the adrenal medula. Yet another fascinating read on how amazing the human body is!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ea68cce89b171.88947262&#34;&gt;How Saudi Arabia&amp;rsquo;s religious project transformed Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;: Religion, politics and power are so damned intertwined. If anything, its one of those defining necessities and vices of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ea68e112d5251.85133599&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to build&lt;/a&gt;: So beautifully phrased! It&amp;rsquo;s high time we dusted those tarp sheets and get to build from ground-up. Over time we&amp;rsquo;ve become complacent as a society and we need one strong re-boot!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving files from all subdirectories without the tree structure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/04/19/moving-files-from-all-subdirectories-without-the-tree-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/04/19/moving-files-from-all-subdirectories-without-the-tree-structure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Appa, who&amp;rsquo;s very active on Facebook, recently wanted an easy way to sift through his old videos and photos that were up on his account. I decided to take a dump of his data from the network using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/dyi/&#34;&gt;download your information&lt;/a&gt; section. I initiated the process with just a few clicks and after a few days, I was able to download the zipped files of all the content he had posted on FB. including the likes, messages, shares etc. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, I would strongly recommend you get a copy of your data. I rarely interact on Facebook these days so it was even more interesting to see all the information they collect on you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, once I had the zipped files, I wanted to sift through the folder structure and copy over all the media from it to a specific location. Using a combination of the tree and find commands this was pretty straightforward. Logging them here for later reference:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;List files with tree hierarchy:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;tree&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find all files within the current directory and nested sub-directories and move them to specific folder:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;find . -print -name &amp;quot;*_.*_&amp;quot; -type f -exec mv -n {} /path/to/destination/directory/ \;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once I had the files [Totally about 25Gb], I realised I had to move them over to my dad&amp;rsquo;s machine. Good old &lt;a href=&#34;https://syncthing.net/&#34;&gt;Syncthing&lt;/a&gt; came to use here to send over the files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
