<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2017-05-04 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/date/2017-05-04-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2017-05-04 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/date/2017-05-04-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Place to Belong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/05/04/a-place-to-belong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/05/04/a-place-to-belong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three years ago, folk singer &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/2p0XD5n&#34;&gt;Joel Shupack&lt;/a&gt; set off from Portland, Oregon on his bicycle. The plan was to ride across the entire U.S., all the way to New Hampshire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Joel&amp;rsquo;s dream was to escape a life that wasn’t filling him up.  He wanted to travel, to give himself space to think, to make sense out of things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On this episode, he shares his story. It’s a story about leaving behind a comfortable life at home, in order to follow your heart. It shows us what a cross-country bike tour is really like – not just the glamorous idea, but the tough reality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And finally, it’s a story about figuring out how to belong.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just listened: &lt;a href=&#34;https://overcast.fm/+EUpgoEYD0&#34;&gt;liked-A Place to Belong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Centralized publishing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/05/04/centralized-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/05/04/centralized-publishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Early in 2017, I consciously decided to consolidate all my social accounts and use my website as the main &amp;lsquo;vehicle&amp;rsquo; for online interactions. While exploring options, I chanced upon the &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/principles&#34;&gt;Indieweb philosop&lt;/a&gt;y which seemed to resonate quite a lot with my thoughts. Over the next few weeks I started taking steps to eventually migrate my publishing platform to a more robust framework. Below is a rough outline of what I have in place so far. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep this article live with updates as I work on enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core framework:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This website is built with Wordpress and is currently hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/&#34;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; [DO] fired-up by &lt;a href=&#34;https://serverpilot.io/&#34;&gt;ServerPilot.&lt;/a&gt; I upgraded to DO early in 2017 from a shared server and I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying the tremendous benefits that comes with it. More on that is &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/03/02/migrations-workflows/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Interaction with Silos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m not quite an online dweller on social networks, I do post once a while on Instagram, Twitter and Facebook. Over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve syndicated my posts to these networks on and off using various plugins. But none of those had features to fetch the interactions or responses back to my portal. Something that I really &amp;lsquo;craved&amp;rsquo; for. While looking for better alternatives, I chanced upon the concept of &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/Webmention&#34;&gt;webmentions&lt;/a&gt;. Meandering through the gamut of options, I eventually found a few tweaks that would work best for my publishing workflow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first step was to get my wordpress install talk indieweb. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/WordPress&#34;&gt;WP starter&lt;/a&gt; page and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/Advanced_WordPress_Set_Up&#34;&gt;Advanced WP setup&lt;/a&gt; page on the Indieweb wiki were good places to get the wheels rolling and setup a base framework. Since I predominantly publish or draft articles while commuting, I was exploring options to post from a mobile device (iPhone). I lost my trust on the official wordpress app after it lost a couple of my drafts. And then I chanced upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://workflow.is/&#34;&gt;Workflow&lt;/a&gt; which looked reliable and seemed to fit all my needs. Outlined below is a rough note on how I interact with the three silos using the workflow app on my iPhone and some custom functions in my WP install.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The general idea was to collect, process and publish. Based on the desired action (Post a status or activity update, Bookmark a link, Reply to a post and Publish a photo) I designed workflows to process the information and push it over to the Wordpress action. One minor issue was that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/indieweb-post-kinds/&#34;&gt;post-kinds plugin&lt;/a&gt; sets up and uses a wordpress taxonomy called &amp;lsquo;kind&amp;rsquo; to hand-shake with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/Micropub&#34;&gt;micropub&lt;/a&gt; server. Since the WP action in Workflow did not accept entries for taxonomies, I had to create a &amp;rsquo;latch&amp;rsquo; to identify the posts that I create via my workflows and map them to the corresponding &amp;lsquo;kind&amp;rsquo; taxonomy. A few trials and I figured I could use a &amp;lsquo;custom field&amp;rsquo; in the workflow app with some custom code in my functions plugin to map this out for me. The other minor tweak was to make my posts &lt;a href=&#34;http://microformats.org/&#34;&gt;microformat&lt;/a&gt; compliant for the webmentions to work their magic. To get this working all I had to do was to feed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://brid.gy/about#webmentions&#34;&gt;requisite html&lt;/a&gt; corresponding to that specific action into markdown just before passing it to the wordpress action in workflow.  Once that was done posting from my phone became a lot more easier (and fun!).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I chose to rely on a couple of slick plugins to post to the silos. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/social-networks-auto-poster-facebook-twitter-g/&#34;&gt;SNAP&lt;/a&gt; helps me push notes out to twitter and I use a tag &amp;rsquo;trigger&amp;rsquo; in my workflow to decide which posts I do not want publish on to twitter. I also use some custom code to add &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/webactions&#34;&gt;webactions&lt;/a&gt; to my twitter specific posts.  And then followed &lt;a href=&#34;http://boffosocko.com/2017/04/15/mentions-from-twitter-to-my-website/&#34;&gt;Chris Aldrich&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; tweak to collect twitter mentions on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/knocks/&#34;&gt;specific page&lt;/a&gt;. To handle Instagram, I use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/dsgnwrks-instagram-importer/&#34;&gt;Dsgnwrks Instagram Importer&lt;/a&gt; to consume photos (and their reactions). &lt;a href=&#34;https://ownyourgram.com/&#34;&gt;Ownyourgram&lt;/a&gt; for some reason wasn&amp;rsquo;t pushing photos to my server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intents and desires:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the current publishing workflow works like a charm, I do need to do a few more tweaks to make this a more seamless process. Few things to note in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;Sync&amp;rsquo; desktop and mobile workflows. Currently I&amp;rsquo;ve different workflows while posting from these platforms. I use the Indieweb Pressthis bookmarklet while on the desktop and the &amp;lsquo;workflow&amp;rsquo; app while posting from my iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Design a platform independent workflow. With workflow&amp;rsquo;s recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/22/apple-has-acquired-workflow-a-powerful-automation-tool-for-ipad-and-iphone/&#34;&gt;acquisition by apple&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m skeptical of the outcome and need to come up with something that&amp;rsquo;s more resilient. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be dang difficult to spin a quick PWA or tweak some of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/Micropub/Clients&#34;&gt;nifty tools&lt;/a&gt; that folks have already built.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make my PeriRSS feed reader &amp;rsquo;talk&amp;rsquo; to my portal. Basically enhance it with webactions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Talk better with microformats.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Publish my code / workflows so others can easily tweak or adapt them for their use.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/favorite?tweet_id=859951821950943232&#34;&gt;like&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?tweet_id=859951821950943232&#34;&gt;reply&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/retweet?tweet_id=859951821950943232&#34;&gt;repost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/favorite?tweet_id=859951821950943232&#34;&gt;like&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?tweet_id=859951821950943232&#34;&gt;reply&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/retweet?tweet_id=859951821950943232&#34;&gt;repost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
