<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wapack-and-Back on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/wapack-and-back/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wapack-and-Back on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/wapack-and-back/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TARC Camp 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/06/12/tarc-camp-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/06/12/tarc-camp-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://trailanimals.com/&#34;&gt;TARC&lt;/a&gt; running camp all smitten with bug and mosquito bites. And it feels terrific! Logged a good sixteen odd miles back in the trails after a month’s rest and met a good bunch of folks. It’s always so inspiring to attend these TARC meets. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/srikanth_perinkulam/albums/72157669983500465&#34;&gt;Last year&lt;/a&gt; at the camp, it was my first ever deep exposure to TARC and I was blown away by the positivity, humbleness and expanse and depth of knowledge these (ultra)runners and other campers brought in. What really makes TARC outstanding is its inclusivity and support framework. They’re open to anybody who is remotely interested in the outdoors and just let the sheer culture of this community take over the reins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, that experience at camp last year deeply impacted my outlook towards running. From barely training for any of the half and full marathons and winging them for the most part, I diligently trained for a 50 miler early this year. The primary intention was to understand my body better and get into a better fitness regimen. Pretty ironic that I ended up spraining my ankle badly during the main event and had to drop out. A run for which I’d logged &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/category/channel/training/&#34;&gt;more than 300 miles&lt;/a&gt; in training! Endurance has always been my forte and however arduous it be, I have never ‘given-up’ during a run/hike over the last ten or so years that I’ve been exploring outdoors. As I was walking back to the car that day, I was in second thoughts if I should have pushed it and completed the run. Something that I didn’t have a definitive answer for then and neither do I have now. All I knew was that my morale did take a beating for sure. Wapack and Back remains an unfinished business and I will have to get back on those rolling peaks to make peace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The camp this weekend was a much needed fix. Just being there surrounded by folks who have DNF’d before consciously for practical reasons and physical limitations took some load off my shoulders. Overall I believe I also had good quality runs this weekend. I felt much stronger on the trails and my average pace definitely seems to have gone up. I can’t wait to get back to a good training regimen again. I definitely do want to make it to more of the weekly runs at the Fells and should also probably join the Blue Hills group whenever feasible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a more tangible target, I have my eyes on the StoneCat 50 miler this November. The India trip may be a mild deterrent but I think I should be able to find a way around that…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/cropped-cropped-SP01-550afdebv1_site_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com&#34;&gt;Srikanth Perinkulam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s time!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/05/12/its-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/05/12/its-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;D-1 day! Hoping the weather system stays just like today&amp;rsquo;s. All set and packed for the run. Tomorrow by this time I should be somewhere near the finish!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/FullSizeRender.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;FullSizeRender.jpg&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wapack Trail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/05/09/wapack-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/05/09/wapack-trail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;likes &lt;a href=&#34;http://hopsonrocks.com/hikes/wapack.html&#34;&gt;Wapack Trail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 to the 50</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/01/31/31-to-the-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/01/31/31-to-the-50/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good 31 miler weekend to close out the third training week. And with that I&amp;rsquo;ve met Miss Me&amp;rsquo;s mandated clause of sticking to the training plan at least till the end of January (I&amp;rsquo;ve never really trained for any of my long runs this far!)  and bought myself an entry to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wapacktrailrace.com/&#34;&gt;Wapack and Back&lt;/a&gt; 50 miler this May. Psyched!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[sgpx gpx=&amp;quot;/wp-content/uploads/gpx/01282017_033241.gpx&amp;quot;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With a family event planned for this weekend, I had to fit in my 20mile saturday run early in the day. Given my last weekends pace at Middlesex fells, I wanted to bucket at least 5 hours for the run. Got to bed at around 08:30pm on Friday night, was up by about 03:00am on Saturday and started the run by 03:30am. Mild showers and pretty comfortable temperatures (20-30F) had me going pretty good and I covered the first loop (8 miles) in about 01:40mins. Miss Me was already up and had an Orange shot (Orange juice with some chat masala!) and PBJs ready for me. A quick pit-stop at home and I head back towards Brookline to cover the rest of the miles. I knew the Brookline loop would give me an easy 10 miles, so decided to run further on to Fenway to get the extra 2 miles. Even before I knew, I was on my way back and was home by 07:30am. This was probably my fastest 20 miler so far. Also a great morale boost after my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/01/21/middlesex-17-miler/&#34;&gt;deplorable 17 miles&lt;/a&gt; last weekend.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Miss Me managed to go for a Yoga class while I was running and once she was back, we hit the road to Southborough and then towards NJ. 40mins into the drive, the left rear tire blew up and with that our plans to head to NJ went kaput. We eventually make our way back home by noon. A lazy rest of the day gives me enough rest for the 11 miler next day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/32577512896_568cce6320_o-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;All of us head to Callahan State park and as I rake in the miles, the rest of the folks head back home after an hour. I weave into trails I&amp;rsquo;ve been on before and spruce it up with sections that I&amp;rsquo;ve not explored so far. The sheer number of trails out here so close to the city limits blows my mind every single time I chance upon uncharted sections. As I&amp;rsquo;m just about to finish my run in about 2.5 hours, I have a scooping fall. A good one at that. Talk about being &amp;lsquo;down to earth&amp;rsquo;!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/32495311001_53021f54c0_o-e1486005361769-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today is a stark reminder that I&amp;rsquo;m much, much slower on the trails and should be using this pace as benchmark to push and improve. As I build my miles, hopefully the pace improves. My Garmin clocked 116 miles totally this month. 2017 is off to a phenomenal start!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
