<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marina on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/marina/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marina on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/marina/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Marina</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/09/30/marina/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/09/30/marina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Took Appa to the Marina this morning. The beach was open but it was a terrible experience. Trash strewn all over, lingering overnight dwellers, and of course open defecation by the shore ..yeah, that still happens! It wasn&amp;rsquo;t this bad a few years ago. We could then run barefoot on the sand for a good distance (~5Kms) without having to dodge trash.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agreed it&amp;rsquo;s a big beach but how complicated is it really to maintain this public space? Of what use is all the digital cameras and equipment if you let people trash the place recklessly? And then add to it the complacence and heavy lack of follow-through on the implemented policies. Most solutions end up being short term and every once in a while a random not-for-profit group shows up on the beach, clean up a section of it (Thank you for that!), click their photos and supposedly get back to their business of &amp;lsquo;raising awareness&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Between vote-bank politics, scattered awareness, heavy lack of follow-through and an essential lack of stringent penalty and consistent implementation; Absolutely nothing is going to change.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;End of pessimistic rant!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marina rain run</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/09/20/marina-rain-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/09/20/marina-rain-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A wonderful morning run on the Marina today. Barefoot as always!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With a &amp;lsquo;gloomy&amp;rsquo; weather and not many visitors this early morning, we had most of the beach all for ourselves! As S and I were just about turning around after reaching Ice House, the slight drizzle very soon turned into a full fledged rain. Pouring rain, early morning waves and an empty beach is something I could take in every single day! Shasta seemed to have a terrific time too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meena happened to click this picture of us running from the distance. So glad she got around capturing this moment!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
