<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/misc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sixth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/11/11/sixth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/11/11/sixth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;Sixth.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S celebrated her 6th today.  Unicorn themed - of course - and had her first and probably last ever Piñata. But for a mega meltdown initially she did great all through the event.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, we signed up for a Diwali party organized by the Indian Association in Mexico. Primarily on a whim and maybe for the food? The event was last evening and boy, it was a terrible disappointment! It started late as expected. And obnoxiously loud for no reason. Not quite sure if it was the acoustics at the venue or just the MC shouting into the mic.  Maybe both? I love some good rock and metal. I love some good loud music. But I guess not all loud is the same. Also, this day and age, who even does a looping slideshow of pictures of people organizing the event? Dinner was supposed to be served by 1900. Servers said they had orders to serve only at 2030. Maybe the organizers wanted the food to be served only after the main event? When we rechecked at 2030, they said it was pushed to 2130. Had enough of it and walked out.  People were still on the dance floor and there was a good turn out. I guess this kinda boisterous social mayhem is just not my jam?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We head out to a Japanese (?) restaurant in Polanco since Nimi&amp;rsquo;s, Mei Mei and Manaw were all closed for service. Sushi was &lt;em&gt;meh&lt;/em&gt;. S did great all through the evening though despite the loud music and the crowd. That &amp;lsquo;Sticker by number&amp;rsquo; book that she received as a gift from Maddy kept her fully occupied!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Monday morning here and S is off for school. She was mildly upset that I get to stay at home while she needs to go to school. Fair world logic, I guess. We drop her and get to spend a couple hours together watching &lt;em&gt;Spenser Confidential&lt;/em&gt;. Enjoyed it all the more because we recognized quite a few locations where the movie was shot. M&amp;rsquo;s got some brunch out with the ladies in a bit and then a couple more hours before I need to pick up S. Maybe I should tweak that 3D printer?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dumbing down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/12/24/dumbing-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/12/24/dumbing-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few things I&amp;rsquo;d really like to dumb down or sort out over the next few weeks:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site&lt;/strong&gt;: This site runs on WordPress, has facets of the indieweb, has ActivityPub and a crude implementation of self engineered micropost interface. All cool but needs quite a trim to make the best use of all these features.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware/Infra&lt;/strong&gt;: VPS, VPN, Odroid for reverse proxy, NCP, NUC, Moose, External hard disks&amp;hellip;Love the current implementation for the various utilities they serve. However, I see myself spending lesser and lesser time in front of the PC. Which is good? But which also means I need to find a better way to manage these in the little time I want to spend.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPX&lt;/strong&gt;: Go on a hike or ride? Automatically log this on my site. Gotta have that super neat Stamen map. I did get really close to setting this up &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/02/09/garmin-plugin-2/&#34;&gt;sometime back&lt;/a&gt; but got left on the wayside. Also time to update my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/garmin-stats/&#34;&gt;Outdoors plugin&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firefly3&lt;/strong&gt;: Love this tool for finance tracking. Need to build that rule engine to automate some of those imports and reports.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snikket/Matrix/Slidge&lt;/strong&gt;: Need to get this sorted out to be part of those groups that still rely on WhatsApp. I setup a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/02/20/bridged/&#34;&gt;bridge&lt;/a&gt; sometime back but deleted it because I was rarely using it. More of a nice-to-have so may not quite get to this anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memories&lt;/strong&gt;: Selective photo sharing with family or friends. Send a link instead of sharing photos individually. Love the nextcloud setup so far. Would be neat if I can take this up a notch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music&lt;/strong&gt;: Kinda like my current Navidrome setup. Would like a bit more flexibility in terms of song or folder access though. Smarter playlists? Also multidevice sync? Music system?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes Sync&lt;/strong&gt;: Currently relying on Signal notes to self and Trilium send for bookmarks. Need to automate this for self sorting with tags in Trilium notes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart sceen&lt;/strong&gt;: On demand and power efficient display for Calendars, Adana, Gallery, dashboard display, news updates etc. Thinking MagicMirror but a bit more optimized. Repurpose that RPi or Odroid once it&amp;rsquo;s all integrated into the NUC?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cable talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/22/cable-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/22/cable-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple weeks, a colleague and I have been trying to clean up the cable mismanagement behind our racks. To work on the equipment you&amp;rsquo;re literally standing on about 1 feet of coiled cable mess. This issue has probably been there over the last several years and nobody has paid much attention to it. Likely because it does not affect the actual functioning of the equipment? And also, this is painstakingly unrewarding work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every single day we&amp;rsquo;ve been behind those racks, we keep thinking - why would someone leave so much of surplus cable and more importantly leave it so disorganized? I believe the reasons are multi-fold. Experience (or lack thereof), workmanship issues, time constraints, personnel turnovers and culmination of several unintentional judgement calls is what comes to mind. And then it also strikes me that I&amp;rsquo;m probably making a heavy judgement without having exposure to the situation my predecessors were dealing with? There was probably a solid reason why they had left so much slack in the cable. We will never know. Ultimately we&amp;rsquo;re here and we&amp;rsquo;re working on this ‘mess’. A few years down the lane my successors would probably think why the cables were so short and didn&amp;rsquo;t have much surplus. I guess you just take a call on what&amp;rsquo;s right at this moment and hope it works for the next few years…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In work environments where there&amp;rsquo;s heavy turnover - either because of the nature of the job or because of the team dynamics, how do you set the bar for quality workmanship?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notas de mitad de año</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/04/notas-de-mitad-de-a%C3%B1o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/04/notas-de-mitad-de-a%C3%B1o/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With quite a few things constantly evolving over the last several months, I haven&amp;rsquo;t actively paid much attention to this space. I&amp;rsquo;ve posted a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/micro/&#34;&gt;micro posts&lt;/a&gt; now and then, but nowhere close to chronicling things as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to. This is a quick run down of a few things occupying my mind space:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been about four months since we moved to Mexico City. We absolutely love it here. People are terrific, weather is just right, and this city&amp;rsquo;s got a dash of almost every city we&amp;rsquo;ve lived in so far! M&amp;amp;S have been able to explore the regular tourist spots thanks to the CLO trips. I&amp;rsquo;ve joined them for a few, but what I really enjoy is just experiencing the city for what it&amp;rsquo;s got to offer - And there&amp;rsquo;s no dearth to that. Absolutely blown away by the city planning and the presence of so many parks. The city is spectacularly clean for the number of people living here. Every Sunday one of the main avenues is closed out to vehicular traffic and opened out to runners, cyclists and essentially anybody who wants to enjoy the roads. Amazed at the resources that the local government is able to draw from to sustain this every single weekend! We haven&amp;rsquo;t been that lucky to find decent vegetarian food here. Most local restaurants offer some form of meat in almost all dishes and the vegetarian items are rarely tasty. Dining out definitely leaves a lot to be desired - unless of course you try out other cuisines. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s good food out there - yet to find it though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s exactly a year since I took on the current position. Best career move I&amp;rsquo;ve made so far, and I absolutely love every part of my job. There&amp;rsquo;s not one day that&amp;rsquo;s akin to another and I&amp;rsquo;m constantly learning every day. Most days just whizz by with constant troubleshooting on systems and processes. I&amp;rsquo;m barely at my desk for an hour a day. Tracing power and logic is so refreshing - The adrenaline rush that comes when you&amp;rsquo;ve found that nuanced fault in the system is addictive. The closest I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to this in the past was while writing code for enhancing functionality in one of my side projects. Ironic that it took me fifteen years to realize what I&amp;rsquo;m really good at - fixing things! And now I get paid to play with toys and travel the world. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to travel to Matamoros, Nuevo Laredo and Hermosillo so far. These cities are so different from CDMX and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I get a chance to experience these regions of the country too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been biking to work most days and doing the Reforma ride on the weekends. So good to be back on the saddle so regularly. Met a couple folks from a trail running group here last weekend and would love to join them whenever time permits. Over the next few months I would also like to visit the National parks around the city. Not having a car is kinda limiting but definitely not a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a family, we&amp;rsquo;ve really gotten into playing Zelda - Breath of the Wild. We each have our own profiles and are at different stages of the game. This is fascinating, engaging and such a good way to spend time together while indoors. S enjoys the challenges and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see how good she&amp;rsquo;s gotten at the game. Definitely getting the Tears of the Kingdom really soon!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been actively tinkering with my home-lab. Mostly doing the bare essentials to keep it updated and running. I&amp;rsquo;ve started using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.firefly-iii.org/&#34;&gt;FireFly III&lt;/a&gt; more actively to keep track of our expenses and for general budgeting. Since internet and power are decently reliable, I should probably move part of my home-lab over from MD to here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022-02-02 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/02/retrospectives-and-flukes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/02/retrospectives-and-flukes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/morganhousel&#34;&gt;@Morganhousel&lt;/a&gt; wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/61faa02775c029.76416307&#34;&gt;fantastic post yesterday&lt;/a&gt; outlining how each person&amp;rsquo;s trajectory is riddled with ‘flukes’. Humanity constantly evolves from a quagmire of possibilities and there&amp;rsquo;s very little merit in looking in retrospect. I think the likelihood of a successful forecast can only be enhanced if we work with the factors in the &lt;strong&gt;present&lt;/strong&gt; - not the past, not the future. The past is barely helpful and you&amp;rsquo;d rather not rely on those from the future. (Odd I say that after all those years I spent churning numbers as an actuarial analyst.) Ultimately what trumps is that humans find it really hard to delineate emotions from decision making. As much as you&amp;rsquo;d like to disagree, you see it in every realm - Medicine, Finance, Sports, Academics, Health just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2016, we had a fascinating &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/04/26/the-grand-cherokee/&#34;&gt;close call on I-15 S&lt;/a&gt; while heading towards New Haven. (Fascinating because, I learnt it the hard way and everyone who drives a car and has a floor-mat should be aware of this.) Accidents tend to give you that moment for retrospect and back then I jotted something similar to the thoughts I have today:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proverbial – ‘Everything happens for a reason’ is just not true. I believe the human brain does a wonderful job in assigning a reason to the cause and quite conveniently this is always subtly and retrospectively done. In its quest to find reason, it ends up triggering neural connections that emotionally and logically seem reasonable. So when and how do we draw the line while making choices and how do you substantiate the choices you’ve made? Or is the whole premise that as a logical and emotional machine you’re feeding good and bad data (choices) as a stimulus to train the body to better react to unforeseeable situations in the future?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2010/01/21/gut-instinct-twitter-and-my-career/&#34;&gt;quite&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/08/10/for-good-for-now/&#34;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/11/23/weeknote-47-shastas-first/&#34;&gt;risky&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/10/21/flight-down-south/&#34;&gt;shifts&lt;/a&gt; in my career over the last decade. Most driven by what I felt at that very moment - Gut instinct. Absolutely none that I regret. And most have been very rewarding. So when it comes to making a choice at that critical moment, I try and keep retrospectives at bay. Every once in a while, I do catch myself careening from this golden rule. That&amp;rsquo;s when I take a good pause, stop connecting the dots and look at just that isolated dot at that moment. It&amp;rsquo;s worked wonders before and I trust that streak to continue. Irony being, my previous statement moots everything I said before! What can I say, we&amp;rsquo;re a good bunch of optimistic morons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building the end plan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/08/06/building-the-end-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/08/06/building-the-end-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leave a comment if any of this doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense. I&amp;rsquo;ll be more than happy to help.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to setup a comprehensive and secure ‘handover’ document for my family - In case I cease to exist. My key priorities were it should :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;be easy to update and maintain when I am alive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;be easy to reference and access when I am dead&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;have multiple fall-back points&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, the most straightforward way to do this would be to have all the information on a secure spreadsheet or document. But that&amp;rsquo;s not fun! So I decided to use Trilium Notes for it. When it&amp;rsquo;s time, my wife has three options to access the support checklist a) Online via a secure portal/app b) Using a secure flash-drive c) Old school printed sheets&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Screenshot-from-2021-08-06-15-05-32-1200x600.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think this is something super easy to replicate. Leaving this out here should someone find it useful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get up and running:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grab the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.electronjs.org/apps/trilium-notes&#34;&gt;Trilium desktop app from here&lt;/a&gt; and install it on your machine. If it&amp;rsquo;s the first time you are using it, it should prompt you to create a local account. You can sync this with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/06/installing-trilium-notes/&#34;&gt;server app&lt;/a&gt; later if you need one.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On first install, Trilium also installs a demo document. This is super helpful to understand how Trilium works. But for now, collapse the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Trilium Demo&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; folder in the left sidebar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Download my  &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sriperinkulam/closeout/raw/main/Closeout%20Template.zip&#34;&gt;Closeout html&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; template zip file. Right click on the &amp;lsquo;root&amp;rsquo; folder on the left sidebar and click &amp;lsquo;Import into&amp;rsquo;. Select the zip file you just downloaded and click on &amp;lsquo;Import&amp;rsquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s it! Update the template to your needs and export for backups.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maintaining and backups:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To encrypt the folder, just right click on  and select &amp;lsquo;protect subtree&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Trilium provides you three modes of export - Zipped HTML, Zipped markdown and OPML. I prefer the HTML export since it can be used in isolation. Do note however that all notes lose their encryption when they&amp;rsquo;re exported out!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generic notes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used Trilium notes since it fits into my workflow. You should be able to import the template into any note-taking app.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The template is obviously bare minimum and generic. Tweak/add based on your personal situation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve intentionally kept my guidance instructions and passwords isolated since I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be printing them on paper. You could have them all in one place here in Trilium and secure the folder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If saving the files/backups on a flash drive, I&amp;rsquo;d strongly recommend you use &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/11/01/encrypting-drives/&#34;&gt;VeraCrypt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am a reasonably healthy person with no alarming issues. But hey, you never know! I think it&amp;rsquo;s critical that your family has good guidance on how best to pick up where you left off. Think of this as the last parting gift. It took me about four years of procrastination and few spurts of action to get here. And I am so glad I did. If not anything, it&amp;rsquo;s helping me document these critical pieces in one place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your life closeout plan?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021-07-30 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/07/30/july-30-2021-1124/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/07/30/july-30-2021-1124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not sure how I came across this, but I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did bookmark it to watch-later. A beautiful film with terrific snow mountain videography and kids!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having Shasta probably makes me appreciate this a lot more. Meena and I started taking Shasta out on hikes since she was about 3 weeks old. We expose her to sharp tools and fire under close supervision. I still think there&amp;rsquo;s so much more we could do with her once we overcome our fear of exposing her to the elements. And this video was a much needed terrific reminder of how short we were falling on that metric!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/574547591&#34;&gt;https://vimeo.com/574547591&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021-04-22 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/22/tonic-immobility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/22/tonic-immobility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Overheard at NatGeo recently produced a great podcast on Orcas and I learnt about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sharktrust.org/tonic-immobility&#34;&gt;Tonic Immobility&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shasta was watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.octonauts.com/&#34;&gt;Octonauts&lt;/a&gt; and guess which episode she ends up watching? - The one in which they talk about TI. Now that&amp;rsquo;s some coincidence!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jabbed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/16/jabbed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/04/16/jabbed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since March 2020, I&amp;rsquo;ve had this internal debate of getting the Covid Vaccine mostly underlined by the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3d3bb2ac73.65468826&#34;&gt;science behind mRNA&lt;/a&gt; is fascinating and so is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5fea3c8962f2a2.96282489&#34;&gt;engineering of the vaccine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every strand of mRNA is made up of four molecular building blocks called nucleosides. But in its altered, synthetic form, one of those building blocks, like a misaligned wheel on a car, was throwing everything off by signaling the immune system. So Karikó and Weissman simply subbed it out for a slightly tweaked version, creating a hybrid mRNA that could sneak its way into cells without alerting the body’s defenses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statnews&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We unfortunately &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/vaccinesafety/concerns/concerns-history.html%5D&#34;&gt;have not had a spectacular history&lt;/a&gt; with vaccines. With humans involved and the ensuing politics, money and power-plays; vaccines are built for the average human being. Then with anything manufactured and delivered at scale, we&amp;rsquo;re prone to Logistics and Supply chain Management issues.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Covid19 vaccines are not a once and done deal. The effects &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/607a14edb61f01.57427531&#34;&gt;last apparently at most a year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did cave in and got the first ‘jab&amp;rsquo; of the Moderna vaccine today at the Consulate. As with all vaccines and medical interventions, this was not quite an easy decision. The decision was probably 40% gut, 40% trusting the mechanics of the mRNA vaccine and 20% of &amp;lsquo;Why am I even considering it&amp;rsquo;. The drivers for the gut-feeling likely being:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Getting the vaccine would possibly break the link in transmitting the virus to an immune-compromised person. We live with our in-laws and that&amp;rsquo;s the least I can do for them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I consider myself to be a fairly young and healthy person and absolutely do not mind wearing masks and exercising social distancing. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve shamefully caught myself pulling down the mask during brief interactions with people. Despite best efforts, the masking system alone is not fool-proof.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; to be outdoors to stay healthy and be sane. Travel and Freedom are my primary &amp;lsquo;movers&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From an extremely exaggerated perspective, I see C19 as the Smallpox / Polio of this century. Few folks in the family are still reeling with the brutal after-effects of these diseases. I think I can take the risk of the possible side-effects for the marginal leg-up the vaccine might give my immune system in case I contract the virus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Folks in the family are leaning towards getting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/607a1f2977e8c3.93743514&#34;&gt;Covaxin&lt;/a&gt; vaccine. India is having it&amp;rsquo;s worst wave so far and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping we swing back downwards as sharply as we rose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stimulus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/03/11/stimulus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/03/11/stimulus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting point on M1 and M2 [Measures of money]. With the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.allsides.com/story/biden-signs-19-trillion-covid-19-relief-bill-law&#34;&gt;signing of the 1.9T$ bill today&lt;/a&gt; in the US, we&amp;rsquo;ve essentially created 6T$ over the last 10 months. Just like that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Covid19 has brought  unprecedented suffering to many. Deaths, Unemployment, Medical complications, lifestyle changes, Social unrest and several other ramifications which we are yet to experience. If anything, it has taught us highlighted how abysmally poor we are in collectively addressing pressing issues. It has also shown us that when disaster strikes, we only take care of our own and we are selectively biased even at that. Nature gave us yet another opportunity to show how we could better ourselves and elevate us to the next stage of evolution and we miserably failed. With our myopic non-collaborative actions, pushing politics and power over general good, we&amp;rsquo;ve defined a new low. Mileage on isolated or individual efforts unfortunately does not carry the ripple effect that can scale. Nothing surprising there - Humans are selfish creatures. We of course needed something to balance all the &lt;em&gt;intelligence&lt;/em&gt; and cognitive advances we supposedly have over other living things. Humanity rests is constant chaos and Covid19 was continues to fuel that chaos.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quite a digression, eh?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health Insurance woes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/03/09/health-insurance-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/03/09/health-insurance-woes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pleasantly surprised to read this piece from ProPublica/NPR. Michael Frank was my professor for a Health Insurance course I took while at Columbia and he was a terrific one at it. Though I moved on to Property and Casualty Insurance as an Actuarial Analyst, I continue to be intrigued by Health. Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be - Such an entangled mess that the U.S. Insurance space is!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. I am a strong proponent of Insurance. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent years mining through claims data and have seen the tremendous benefits, a well structured Insurance plan provides - for both parties involved. Where we&amp;rsquo;re actually faltering is the policies and regulations that govern the Insurance markets. Profits drive decisions and the U.S. healthcare system is on an abysmal downward spiral latching on to just the monetary front. Why in this day and age is it unclear how much I might owe when I visit my Physician or undergo a procedure? I&amp;rsquo;d much rather pay higher taxes than live in eternal uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not going to happen anytime soon and till we even see that silver lining, all one can do is rely on things like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.healthcarebluebook.com&#34;&gt;Healthcare Bluebook&lt;/a&gt; and make triple-sure every single doctor who&amp;rsquo;s going to be getting any close to you is in-network on your health plan!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>March 4, 2021 21:05</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/03/04/march-4-2021-2105/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/03/04/march-4-2021-2105/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A fascinating talk by Jonah Edwards to the Internet Archive staff. They manage ~200PB of data in-house!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/download/jonah-edwards-presentation/jonah-edwards-presentation&#34;&gt;https://archive.org/download/jonah-edwards-presentation/jonah-edwards-presentation&lt;/a&gt;_720p.mp4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lifting the veil</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/16/lifting-the-veil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/16/lifting-the-veil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/signal-2021-01-17-045708_002-scaled.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;Just about a decade ago, we leased a property on a pristine and desolate beach. The house didn&amp;rsquo;t have robust walls - It just had a few curtains to protect us from the elements. The rooms internally had walls full of transparent glass. It was a beautiful property with lots of cross-ventilation and something that was just right for our family. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over time, more people moved in around us and it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel all that secluded. Visitors to the beach, neighbors and more so the property owner started getting more interested in our mundane lives. At times we felt, they were interested more in us than the pristine beach. The property owner started hiking the rent overtime and started charging us for random things. At one point, he even started deciding when we could actually use the beach. As much as we&amp;rsquo;d wanted to stay at that place and enjoy the neighbors company, we decided it was time to take things in control. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We got out of the lease and built our own property in the adjacent lot. This time though we had beautiful bamboo walls and lots of open windows with blinds. We had complete control on whom we could connect with and more importantly when we really wanted to. We still had nothing to hide. However we did have everything in the world to protect. Times have changed and it&amp;rsquo;s no outsiders business to benefit from your matter of regular affairs. Changing our lifestyle a bit was a small price to pay and though inconvenient at times, we&amp;rsquo;ve mastered the ropes and are now in a much better place. And quite honestly, we weren&amp;rsquo;t alone. Lots of people have made that shift and we&amp;rsquo;ve learnt a ton from each other&amp;rsquo;s experience. It&amp;rsquo;s in fact a lot more easier now than before. You just need to ask if your stuck!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve read this far, you&amp;rsquo;d obviously realize for the most part, I&amp;rsquo;m referring to my digital life. No actually yours too. It&amp;rsquo;s high time we take more control and move out of these information sucking centralized systems. In this day and age there&amp;rsquo;s no reason why you should be tethered to the pseudo social construct of facebook, twitter, instagram and what-not. I urge you to revert to the old-school world of blogging. Use an &lt;a href=&#34;https://miniflux.app/&#34;&gt;RSS reader&lt;/a&gt; - let the information come to you on your terms and not on algorithms that mine your data for someone else. Privacy in the current form is a hoax and it is time we lift the veil and make those small changes for the network-effect to take place. And trust me, it is so absolutely worth it once you clear the veil. Over the last decade there have been fabulous movements [&lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/&#34;&gt;Indieweb&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://fediverse.party/&#34;&gt;fediverse&lt;/a&gt;] that have risen to give you more control over your data. And then there are a ton of terrific options out there:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;E-mail: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastmail.com/&#34;&gt;Fastmail&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonmail.com/&#34;&gt;Protonmail&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://postale.io/&#34;&gt;Postale.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Messaging: &lt;a href=&#34;https://delta.chat/en/&#34;&gt;Delta-chat&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://signal.org/&#34;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://blabber.im/en/&#34;&gt;Blabber.im&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.org/&#34;&gt;Element&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://wire.com/en/&#34;&gt;Wire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Files: &lt;a href=&#34;https://nextcloud.com/&#34;&gt;Nextcloud&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.seafile.com/en/home/&#34;&gt;Seafile&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://syncthing.net/&#34;&gt;Syncthing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Video calls: &lt;a href=&#34;https://jitsi.org/jitsi-meet/&#34;&gt;Jitsi&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://jami.net/&#34;&gt;Jami&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Youtube: &lt;a href=&#34;http://invidious.snopyta.org/&#34;&gt;Invidious&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://joinpeertube.org/&#34;&gt;Peertube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Evernote: &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/07/migrating-over-to-trilium-notes/&#34;&gt;Trilium Notes&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://joplinapp.org/&#34;&gt;Joplin&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://standardnotes.org/&#34;&gt;Standard notes&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://orgmode.org/features.html&#34;&gt;Org-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Facebook: &lt;a href=&#34;https://micro.blog/&#34;&gt;Microblog&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://withknown.com/&#34;&gt;Known&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://diasporafoundation.org/&#34;&gt;Diaspora&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://mewe.com/&#34;&gt;MeWe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://joinmastodon.org/&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.minds.com/&#34;&gt;Minds&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://gnu.io/social/&#34;&gt;GNU Social&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://friendi.ca/&#34;&gt;Friendica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reddit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://getaether.net/&#34;&gt;Aether&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://lemmy.ml/&#34;&gt;Lemmy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blogs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://write.as/&#34;&gt;Write.as&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Instagram: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixelfed.org/&#34;&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://sunlit.io/&#34;&gt;Sunlit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GoodReads: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.librarything.com/&#34;&gt;Librarything&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thestorygraph.com/&#34;&gt;StoryGraph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Phones: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sustaphones.com/&#34;&gt;Sustaphones&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pine64.org/pinephone/&#34;&gt;Pinephone&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://puri.sm/products/librem-5/&#34;&gt;Librem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the above apps work right out of the box. There&amp;rsquo;s so little that you really need to change or setup. If you&amp;rsquo;re still concerned about moving your extended communities over to the platform - Take that plunge and make the move. People who do want to stay in touch with you will follow!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And if anything seems ever barely daunting - Just ask! I&amp;rsquo;ll be super glad to set something up for you or point you in the right direction. &lt;strong&gt;What is it that is holding you back from making the switch?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ephemeral devices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/06/ephemeral-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/06/ephemeral-devices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is fascinating! A few GPS devices apparently had a mild(?) &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ff48e143fb7f0.93623598&#34;&gt;path offset issue&lt;/a&gt; few days ago:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The issue has to do with the ephemeris data file, also called the EPO file (Extended Prediction Orbit) or Connected Predictive Ephemeris (CPE). Or simply the satellite pre-cache file. That’s the file that’s delivered to your device on a frequent basis (usually every few days). This file is what makes your watch near-instantly find GPS satellites when you go outside. It’s basically a cheat-sheet of where the satellites are for the next few days, or up to a week or so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice this on my Forerunner 235 but I find it super intriguing to read about the &amp;lsquo;inner workings&amp;rsquo; of the background handshake. When I first got the Forerunner 235, I was amazed at how quickly it latched on to the satellites in contrast to the Forerunner 305 that I was actively using then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple decades ago when you bought a new &amp;lsquo;gadget&amp;rsquo;, you would get not only a &amp;lsquo;how-to&amp;rsquo; but also a technical sheet outlining the inner workings of the device. I miss seeing those sheets now!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reimann Hypothesis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/06/reimann-hypothesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/06/reimann-hypothesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say I understood all of it, but this &lt;a href=&#34;https://invidious.snopyta.org/embed/zlm1aajH6gY&#34;&gt;video from Quanta Magazine&lt;/a&gt; is one of the best explanations I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so far that attempts to connect prime numbers with the Reimann Hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
