<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2011-10-27 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2011-10-27-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2011-10-27 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2011-10-27-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Three doctrines of Transitional Leadership</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/10/27/the-three-doctrines-of-transitional-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/10/27/the-three-doctrines-of-transitional-leadership/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[Pun intended]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Event management team in the Epiphany Dynasty decided to raise funds for their third unit projects. Besides organizing a movie showcase they also ran a sale of important commodities. Through these activities - under the hood- they formulated and exhibited the three doctrines of Transitional Leadership. Readers are advised to read through the doctrines first and then watch the videos for a comprehensive understanding.These are extremely profound and intellectual thoughts and are being shared by the rulers with nothing but a humble gesture to levitate humanity to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first doctrine of Transitional Leadership:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Event management team executing the first doctrine of Transitional leadership [Market for all its worth!] during a dry run in the classroom. To be a transitional leader in just two minutes watch as these rockstar leaders execute what they&amp;rsquo;ve learnt. If you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed something funny/something off the norms of regular business, You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to join the exclusive discussion forum in our classroom - We&amp;rsquo;re working on refining the doctrines.Who knows you could be the next guru in Transitional Leadership!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[vimeo &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vimeo.com/31186794&#34;&gt;http://www.vimeo.com/31186794&lt;/a&gt; w=398&amp;amp;h=299]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second doctrine of Transitional Leadership:&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rulers of the Epiphany dynasty figured that once you market your product you need to be up to speed in selling it. Time and timing is excruciatingly important and you need to be on your heels and watch out for competition. Integrity is vital and discipline makes or breaks your business. This short video encapsulates this doctrine in action. Of course this is a debatable topic and you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to thrash it out with the rulers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[vimeo &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vimeo.com/31187120&#34;&gt;http://www.vimeo.com/31187120&lt;/a&gt; w=398&amp;amp;h=299]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third doctrine of Transitional Leadership:&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are always just three rules that govern everything in this world. So it is with Transitional Leadership. Performance under pressure is something that&amp;rsquo;s really important and you need to be on the top of things despite the constraints and limitations. The rulers figured out that deadlines are always round the corner and when you&amp;rsquo;re a top performer pressure is inevitable. Watch as the ruler of the Cholas empire leads by example in conveying this point. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[youtube &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b&lt;/a&gt;_vXIuG1EY8]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following the newly formulated rule book, the rulers made a whooping &lt;strong&gt;negative&lt;/strong&gt; profit of 498.00 INR.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is something that they&amp;rsquo;ve never done before and the hardwork and the lessons they&amp;rsquo;ve learned would immensely help them in formulating a new &amp;lsquo;biziness&amp;rsquo; theory. Well, isn&amp;rsquo;t that how you become a stalwart bania?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
