<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021-04-30 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2021-04-30-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021-04-30 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2021-04-30-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>April 30, 2021 18:07</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/30/april-30-2021-1807/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/30/april-30-2021-1807/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Switched over to consuming Twitter via RSS feeds. For now I am using Yarns on WP to collect the feeds and the Indigenous app / Monocle-web social reader to read/interact with tweets. With this setup, I get to stay clear of the tracking and ads [Last time I checked uBlock Origin blocked 90 trackers/ads in 3 minutes!] and more importantly use my website as the primary place where I post. While I am not quite active on twitter, this should be a great go-between to reconnect with folks who use it for their primary digital presence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breezy shadows</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/30/breezy-shadows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/30/breezy-shadows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most evenings when her mom heads downstairs to the gym for a yoga class, this little munchkin and I, head over to the terrace for some &amp;lsquo;outside&amp;rsquo; time. She insists on getting her tricycle along - handlebars all donned with Christmas ornaments and the rear storage bin full of random trinkets and toys. Rarely does she really ride it. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ascertaining that the Sun&amp;rsquo;s still where it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be and checking-in with the rising moon, she gets on with her daily business of running behind the crows. Time flies as she fills this unstructured play time with random activities - chasing shadows, sprinting laps, counting birds, verbal diarrhea (&lt;em&gt;What color you like? You see balloon? You like it, Appa? 5,4,2,1..run&lt;/em&gt;) and then keeping me on my toes. As the evening beach breeze sets in and the sun dusk&amp;rsquo;s down, she makes her way downstairs casually forgetting all about the bike. When she does remember it, she wants to be carried downstairs with her sitting on it. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20210429_191648-900x1200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If not for Covid, we&amp;rsquo;d be out in the woods, making the best use of whatever little this city has to offer. But for now, I absolutely cherish this time outdoors with her.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
