<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2019-10-12 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2019-10-12-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019-10-12 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2019-10-12-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 41 - Networks and Carnatic notes</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/10/12/weeknote-41-networks-and-carnatic-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/10/12/weeknote-41-networks-and-carnatic-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State of the network:&lt;/strong&gt; With better access to the router and some re-wiring in the house, I got around rejigging my server setup. This will change once I get my Odroid shipped over. For now though, here&amp;rsquo;s my current setup:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ownyourbits.com/nextcloudpi/&#34;&gt;NexcloudPi&lt;/a&gt; installed on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/products/raspberry-pi-3-model-b-plus/&#34;&gt;Raspberry pi 3B+&lt;/a&gt; board&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dietpi.com/&#34;&gt;Diet-Pi&lt;/a&gt; installed on another Raspberry pi 3B+ board running the pi-hole&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The SBCs and the modem are now connected to the UPS inverter, so hopefully that gets rid of the hard shutdowns. Might consider getting a stabilizer at some point in time. I am also leaning towards a more robust homelab system. Yet to whet the core setup and will probably explore that a year down the lane.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fitness:&lt;/strong&gt; Yet another good week spending time outdoors! A 5k barefoot beach run on Tuesday, 5.5k lap runs at the YMCA on Wednesday, 25mins breaststroke swim at MBC and 30min MAS training at YMCA on Thursday, and a 2k barefoot beach run on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music:&lt;/strong&gt; Spent friday evening listening to a Veena instrumental performance at Narada Gana Sabha. A family friend was playing with 107 other artists and I also ran into a college friend with whom I was out of touch for about 10 years now! The performance was a tribute to his grand-father. Small, small world! Below is a shoddy recording of one of the pieces they performed. One of my favorites.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/365893142&#34;&gt;https://vimeo.com/365893142&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting tools this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you need to find what other devices are connected to the wifi network that your device is connected to, and a whole lot of other details, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fing.com/&#34;&gt;Fing app&lt;/a&gt; is wonderful place to start. The free app is pretty slick! I use it to identify IP addresses (and use that to update my pi-hole hosts file for a more human-friendly &amp;lsquo;client listing&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s Sycamore quantum computer apparently achieved &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1203.5813.pdf&#34;&gt;quantum supremacy&lt;/a&gt;. John Preskill had a good &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quantamagazine.org/john-preskill-explains-quantum-supremacy-20191002/&#34;&gt;article on this on Quanta Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. The next few decades is arguably going to be about computing prowess and the results thereof, and quantum supremacy is a huge move in that direction. Exciting times ahead!&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Just read this brilliant Nat-Geo piece on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/magazine/2017/09/holland-agriculture-sustainable-farming/&#34;&gt;Netherland&amp;rsquo;s sustainable farming practices&lt;/a&gt; and how that&amp;rsquo;s setting them to success as the world&amp;rsquo;s second largest exporters despite being a really small country!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An intriguing post on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/news/2019/feb/19/palm-oil-ingredient-biscuits-shampoo-environmental&#34;&gt;Palm oil&lt;/a&gt;. A cousin who was visiting us last month mentioned how he&amp;rsquo;d moved away from all packaged foods since they extensively use Palm oil. While I agree with the sentiment of not using packaged food, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite aware of the influence of Palm-oil and how deeply ingrained it was in the asian food manufacturing ecosystem till I read this piece from the Guardian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
