<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Houston on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/houston/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Houston on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/houston/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025-01-05 21:30:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/05/houston-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/05/houston-calling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We wanted to make it to Houston during S&amp;rsquo; Christmas break, because we very well knew we might not come here during our home leave. Oh boy, what a trip this has been in terms of travel snafus! On our way there we got routed to San Antonio and got grounded for a couple hours because of inclement weather en-route.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/houston.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the way back, we thought we missed our connection in Dallas because of a delayed departure from Houston, and re-booked for a later flight from Dallas. However, our connecting flight was delayed too and when I checked at the counter in Dallas if we could get switched back to our previous booking, the attendant said that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible. M however was adamant and worked her magic. Looks like they had a &amp;lsquo;weight restriction&amp;rsquo; on the flight and M was able to convince them to flip back our reservations since we didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything to check-in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trip otherwise was pretty uneventful. Some good time with family, speckled with delicious home cooked food and some oh-so-okay outside food. Also note-to-self to make these trips shorter to just about two nights instead of week-long.&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/05/houston-calling/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
