<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2014-12-31 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/date/2014-12-31-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2014-12-31 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/date/2014-12-31-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2014 Highlights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/12/31/2014-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/12/31/2014-highlights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Took some time out today to make sure I post a year-end update for 2014. I somehow seem to have missed doing this for the past three years.  Looking back, this year has been extremely fulfilling - both professionally and personally. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick rewind:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interned at Deloitte for two months. My first actuarial internship and a great start to the year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;February:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Attended the SOA Hartford Student Connect. Great drive to the &amp;lsquo;Insurance capital of the world&amp;rsquo; and a good day spent meeting practicing actuaries.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bought a new bike - my first ever road bike! [icon name=&amp;ldquo;bicycle&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interned at Atikus Insurance. Wonderful bunch of folks and great learning insights. Dabbled with macros the first time on a major project.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Went Seal watching and met an &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/adventure-travel/meeting-paul-swinburne&#34; title=&#34;Meeting Paul | Swinburne&#34;&gt;incredible champion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bike ride around Central Park.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Drove to Toronto during the spring break. Ithaca en-route, was a pleasant surprise.[icon name=&amp;ldquo;road&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fun road trip to Florida with the Bhaskars and a good time with the Nandurs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/adventure-travel/adirondacks-it-is&#34; title=&#34;Adirondacks it is!&#34;&gt;Back to running&lt;/a&gt; after a long break. Ankle feels good but not yet ready for a Half.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Decided not to run my first registered half-marathon in the US. Though extremely disappointed, I&amp;rsquo;ll learn later the sacrifice was worth it.  Meena runs a 10k and a few in the familia run halfs. If reactions post-run are any indicative, looks like I missed a lot of good-pain. Nevertheless, had a fun time just being there.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Baltimore family moves. Daphne welcomes us earlier than anticipated!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meena moves to Chicago for the TFA institute. Atikus and serious exam prep keeps me busy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Passed the second actuarial exam. This one was long due! [icon name=&amp;ldquo;flag&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flew to Chicago for our second anniversary. The windy city doesn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint us! Drove the Jeep to NY. Ohio stretch was a pain with heavy road maintenance and blinding trucks. Loved the Philly stretch though! [icon name=&amp;ldquo;car&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Family drives over a weekend to Florida for nephew&amp;rsquo;s first birthday. Crazy yet happening weekend!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Probably one of my best running moments. Ragnar was &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/adventure-travel/appalachians-next&#34; title=&#34;Appalachians next!&#34;&gt;such an experience&lt;/a&gt;! My first ever relay run over 200 miles. These pristine routes call for a revisit!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fall session creeps in with project deadlines almost every other day. Boy, this semester has been relentless!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Family is going places, this time to Jason.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/book-review/deep-freediving&#34; title=&#34;Deep: Freediving and What the Ocean Tells Us about Ourselves&#34;&gt;Deep: Freediving and What the Ocean Tells Us about Ourselves&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by James Nestor. The urge to scuba dive&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The runners group [read Ragnar team] decides to go all in for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/running/philadelphia-half&#34; title=&#34;Philadelphia Half&#34;&gt;Philly Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. Cave-in to the &amp;lsquo;runner&amp;rsquo;s pressure&amp;rsquo; and sign-up. Had a pretty decent run but decided not to run any more city runs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Swimming sessions at the Y. With the wife as the coach, life can be a bit under-water!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Philly run ends with news on the line on a new entrant in the family. Nieces galore! This one seems to be born with a bunch of butterflies. Exciting times ahead!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The graduation heat is On!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wait, the family is not yet done moving. This time to Ambiance!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Burning the midnight oil (The heater?) for the finals. You can&amp;rsquo;t really avoid those last-minute surprises. Can you? All said and done, I now hold a Master of Science! - One long-held desire, Checked.[icon name=&amp;ldquo;university&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Last minute Christmas packing frenzy. Love this time of the year. Gifting is fun! [icon name=&amp;ldquo;gift&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Signed off Christmas in Boston with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/233479444&#34;&gt;5mi run along the Charles river&lt;/a&gt; and rang in the new year at Ambiance.[icon name=&amp;ldquo;tree&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
