<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Year-Notes on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/year-notes/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Year-Notes on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/year-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023 Year end note</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/01/02/2023-year-end-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/01/02/2023-year-end-note/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;JAN&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M&amp;amp;S did a whirlwind trip to Abu dhabi, Dubai, Chennai. Weddings and why-not?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FEB&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M,S &amp;amp; I hiked up Shenandoah National Parks highest point - Hawksbill summit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The three of us did a flying visit to Houston&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Took Aarav out on a little hike to Little Bennet regional park. Poor kid trusted me enough to wade freezing cold waters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Farewell to the 165/211 STS/SEOs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;MAR&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FACT Training&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Moved to CDMX&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pappaji was able to spend a good few weeks with us&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;APR&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The 4 of us went to the Teotihuacan Pyramids!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work trip to Matamoros.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;MAY&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Miss V and Amma visit us. V explores snooker&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Family visits Basilica de Guadalupe, Xochimilco and the other touristy spots in and around the city&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spend a terrific day in Las Estacas. S surprises me with wanting to jump into the frigid waters!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S continues zipping on her scooter to El Angel on Reforma Sundays. Gave M a mild scare when she zoomed ahead all the way to the Panda and didn&amp;rsquo;t bother waiting for M.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prerna visits for a week&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work trip to Nuevo Laredo&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;JUN&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M&amp;amp;S visit Delhi, Parbani for Vinay&amp;rsquo;s wedding&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work trip to Hermosillo&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;JUL&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quick trip to Baltimore for Nancy&amp;rsquo;s Arangetram&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beautiful walking trip to Centro Historico, M runs into one of her school friends out of the blue&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S enjoys her Elaneer near the Frida Kahlo Museum.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lucha Libre. Meh!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M&amp;amp;S visit good ol&amp;rsquo; Boston!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Joined CLO for a trip to Puebla. Also Africam Safari!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work trip to Matamoros&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S has started using her cycle with training wheels a lot more&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AUG&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bostonians visit us for a week&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work trip to Tegucigalpa, Honduras. Next time around, I should stay here for a bit longer!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Visit Las Estacas again. The kids pool was a major disappointment. Not coming back here&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meena goes on the PLP trip to Cuetzalan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ballet Forklorico - Kinda nice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S starts roller-skating classes and school!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sep&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hike El Ocotal. Oh, so beautiful!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M&amp;amp;I explore the rail trail on the bike&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flying weekend visit to Baltimore for Sharath&amp;rsquo;s 50th!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Joing CLO for a trip to Merida. Chichenitza and Cenotes!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work trip to Merida&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;OCT&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work travel to Fort Lauderdale. M&amp;amp;S were able to join too. Great 1 week right on the beach in Pompano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M&amp;rsquo;s parents visit us for a week&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lead the Girl scouts fall hike in El Ocotal. Too many kids and families. Ouch. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have opened this to the whole group.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appa and Athai visit us for a couple weeks. So glad they came together!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;NOV&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shebani visits us for a week&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ashu Bhabhi visits us for a day. She got some terrific green coffee beans&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M and Athai visit Chingahuapan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Took Appa and Athai to El Ocotal. Super impressed with how much appa&amp;rsquo;s able to walk! Wheelchair helped quite a bit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work travel to Managua. Didn&amp;rsquo;t get to visit the volcano. Next time around maybe?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Marine Ball. Check.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Took Appa and Athai to Teotihuacan and Basilica de Guadalupe. They loved it!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Missed being with the extended family … for a few moments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Visited the National Cemetery for Dia de Muertes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DEC&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Malinalco Camping with the daisies. Mesmerized by the mountains all around!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sneha visits us for a month&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arvind and Patti visits us for about a week&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hiked up San Miguel - Such a terrific birthday gift!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pub crawl with the ESC folks. Great evening!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We bid and got our top pick. Yaounde it is in 2025!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started roller skating. This is so much fun!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I write this year-end note I realize how much I&amp;rsquo;ve not really documented. Some day I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to being more active in this space! Feliz Año Nuevo!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All of 65 lbs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/09/all-of-65-lbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/09/all-of-65-lbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With quite a few developments on the personal front, the last few months has kept me quite &amp;lsquo;busy&amp;rsquo;. Despite Covid, I did a bunch of travel which is always nice! Last August, Appa kinda lost his patience and wanted to make a trip to India. We figured September was the most optimal time and I flew over to MD to accompany him back. With just a day off work, I was able to finagle a whirlwind weekend trip to the US and back. M and S head over to the states in October to be a bit of a help in MD while I looked after two grand old men here in India. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while that I&amp;rsquo;ve done this and but for a few rough days, I loved spending time helping them accomplish what they wanted to over the course of three months. Appa was able to get most of his &amp;lsquo;admin&amp;rsquo; stuff done and more importantly got to spend time with his younger brother.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In December I made a quick trip to Delhi to meet folks at work. Was good catching up after all of these months of telework! Mid December and just before the Omicron wave hit the Asian region, we were asked to report into work on premises. Obviously made sense to take Appa back to MD since we didn&amp;rsquo;t want him to be living alone - more so when we started seeing the Omicron effect in the US, Israel and UK. I accompanied him back on the 31st and used this opportunity to also take some time off to spend with M &amp;amp; S! It was a much needed break and we did get to do a bunch of stuff in the short time that I was there: Got the Moderna booster - In tandem with Jet-lag, the next day fatigue was a killer, Went on a nice date with M to a Thai restaurant - but for the jasmine spray hand sanitizer..UGH!, Took S our for &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/01/trolley-trail/&#34;&gt;a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/05/patapsco-thru-trail/&#34;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/06/oregon-ridge-park/&#34;&gt;hikes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/05/january-6-2022-0609/&#34;&gt;Built a scooter&lt;/a&gt; for S, Migrated my servers over to MD, packed my belongings in all of 65lbs and moved to Delhi. The return leg was quite happening with American transferring my booking to BA and transiting  me via Heathrow. Called for a lot of last minute Covid digital paperwork. Thank goodness to smartphones and free WiFi access in Airports!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For now I&amp;rsquo;m super excited to be in Delhi! Still too many variables at play and oddly that seems to be the constant in our lives. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to explore this fascinating city and then head further up north during the weekends. Omicron is going to hugely shape the next few months and I&amp;rsquo;m going to make best use of the wrenches it&amp;rsquo;s gonna throw.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy (Belated) New Year!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covelong riders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/01/covelong-riders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/01/covelong-riders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20210102_040028.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/12/28/sea-la-vie/&#34;&gt;muted attempt last year&lt;/a&gt;, we were able to ring in 2021 with an early morning Surfing class at Covelong. The girls loved it and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have asked for a better start. Exhilarating, to say the least. And oh, salt water does BURN your eyes!&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20210102_040028-1200x675.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shasta enjoyed her time on the beach with her grand-parents. Dainty princess that she is, she apparently had her shoes on - for the whole two hours. Nevertheless she did enjoy the early breezy morning, watching us fall umpteen number of times. When asked later, she did mention she thought we were exercising. We&amp;rsquo;ll go with that!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2020 was obviously a rough year for many. I&amp;rsquo;m extremely fortunate and thankful that C-19 had minimal impact on us and our extended family. Hoping that this &amp;rsquo;new&amp;rsquo; year brings in closure on many fronts and at the very least gives us resilience to rebound stronger. Here&amp;rsquo;s to riding those waves and taking time to connect with others during those lulls. Happy 2021!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;image-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;ul class=&#34;photo-list &#34;&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;             &#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&#xA;                &lt;img src=&#34;./images/20210102_040028.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20210102_040028.jpg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;             &#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&#xA;                &lt;img src=&#34;./images/20210102_040253-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20210102_040253-scaled.jpg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;.photo-list {&#xA;    display: flex;  &#xA;    flex-wrap: wrap;  &#xA;    margin: -1px;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list &gt; li {&#xA;    height: 40vh;  &#xA;    flex-grow: 1;  &#xA;    list-style-type: none;  &#xA;    margin: 1px;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list li img {&#xA;    max-height: 100%;  &#xA;    min-width: 100%;  &#xA;    object-fit: cover;  &#xA;    vertical-align: bottom;  &#xA;    border: 2px solid gray;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list li:last-child {&#xA;    flex-grow: 10;  &#xA;    border: none;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA; &#xA;.photo-list.single-image &gt; li {&#xA;    height: auto;  &#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 01 - Memories, Liberty and freedom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/05/weeknote-01-memories-liberty-and-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/01/05/weeknote-01-memories-liberty-and-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few articles, podcasts, tools, videos and music that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Convincing their parents last minute, Divyaa and Raaghuv drove up to Maryland with us. The kids had a ball of a time in the last row of the Sienna. We stopped over at Durham for the night and met Uncle Lou the next day for breakfast. Of course also visited Fuqua school of Business. Rajesh graduated from here and we so wished he was alive to show us around this campus. A gentle reminder to check-in with everyone near and dear every once in a while&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meena and I took the kids Skiing at Liberty on Thursday night. This has become more of a tradition now at year-end(beginning). A first for Raaghuv and Divyaa though. Just before we left, the boys decided to take on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.libertymountainresort.com/interactive-map#close&#34;&gt;Lower blue streak&lt;/a&gt;, and I joined them. Absolutely reminded me of my first day at skiing! Need to work on that nuanced braking!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oh and of course, Happy New Year! Last year I chose to be a bit more free, a privilege I am so glad I had and thankful for. Looking forward to what we chart in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Listening to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://genius.com/Maroon-5-memories-lyrics&#34;&gt;Memories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting podcasts this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The great American tax haven: why the super-rich love South Dakota&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Episode 216: How Four Drinking Buddies Saved Brazil&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting tools this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/&#34;&gt;OBS Studio&lt;/a&gt;: Video recording and live-streaming&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outline.com/EtuykY&#34;&gt;Why more kids are learning — and enjoying — yoga&lt;/a&gt;: While yoga has become a fad now in the western world, I&amp;rsquo;d go further out to expand it to any activity that gets them out of a &amp;lsquo;controlled&amp;rsquo; space. My dream classroom would be one out in the open with minimal teacher intervention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outline.com/sBdxWP&#34;&gt;Why the French Don’t Show Excitement&lt;/a&gt;: While I like the idea of “&lt;em&gt;on est bien, là&lt;/em&gt;”, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have a tough time getting that perceived cold shoulder in response.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outline.com/eHNn4g&#34;&gt;‘For five years we dreaded every meal’: my infant son’s struggle with food&lt;/a&gt;: They&amp;rsquo;re just so many things that could go wrong&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m so thankful Meena and Shasta are doing terrific.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outline.com/krJguV&#34;&gt;Don’t just criticise the police. They’re constrained&lt;/a&gt;: As the world&amp;rsquo;s largest democracy comes to grips with the weight of the existence of more than a billion people, more so now as the youth are engaging and reacting to state and national politics, It&amp;rsquo;s key that funding and training is adequately increased to maintain law and order. And then there&amp;rsquo;s corruption to deal with&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2014 Highlights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/12/31/2014-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/12/31/2014-highlights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Took some time out today to make sure I post a year-end update for 2014. I somehow seem to have missed doing this for the past three years.  Looking back, this year has been extremely fulfilling - both professionally and personally. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick rewind:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;January:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interned at Deloitte for two months. My first actuarial internship and a great start to the year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;February:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Attended the SOA Hartford Student Connect. Great drive to the &amp;lsquo;Insurance capital of the world&amp;rsquo; and a good day spent meeting practicing actuaries.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bought a new bike - my first ever road bike! [icon name=&amp;ldquo;bicycle&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interned at Atikus Insurance. Wonderful bunch of folks and great learning insights. Dabbled with macros the first time on a major project.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Went Seal watching and met an &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/adventure-travel/meeting-paul-swinburne&#34; title=&#34;Meeting Paul | Swinburne&#34;&gt;incredible champion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bike ride around Central Park.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Drove to Toronto during the spring break. Ithaca en-route, was a pleasant surprise.[icon name=&amp;ldquo;road&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;April:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fun road trip to Florida with the Bhaskars and a good time with the Nandurs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/adventure-travel/adirondacks-it-is&#34; title=&#34;Adirondacks it is!&#34;&gt;Back to running&lt;/a&gt; after a long break. Ankle feels good but not yet ready for a Half.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Decided not to run my first registered half-marathon in the US. Though extremely disappointed, I&amp;rsquo;ll learn later the sacrifice was worth it.  Meena runs a 10k and a few in the familia run halfs. If reactions post-run are any indicative, looks like I missed a lot of good-pain. Nevertheless, had a fun time just being there.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Baltimore family moves. Daphne welcomes us earlier than anticipated!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meena moves to Chicago for the TFA institute. Atikus and serious exam prep keeps me busy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Passed the second actuarial exam. This one was long due! [icon name=&amp;ldquo;flag&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;July:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flew to Chicago for our second anniversary. The windy city doesn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint us! Drove the Jeep to NY. Ohio stretch was a pain with heavy road maintenance and blinding trucks. Loved the Philly stretch though! [icon name=&amp;ldquo;car&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;August:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Family drives over a weekend to Florida for nephew&amp;rsquo;s first birthday. Crazy yet happening weekend!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Probably one of my best running moments. Ragnar was &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/adventure-travel/appalachians-next&#34; title=&#34;Appalachians next!&#34;&gt;such an experience&lt;/a&gt;! My first ever relay run over 200 miles. These pristine routes call for a revisit!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;October:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fall session creeps in with project deadlines almost every other day. Boy, this semester has been relentless!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Family is going places, this time to Jason.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/book-review/deep-freediving&#34; title=&#34;Deep: Freediving and What the Ocean Tells Us about Ourselves&#34;&gt;Deep: Freediving and What the Ocean Tells Us about Ourselves&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; by James Nestor. The urge to scuba dive&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The runners group [read Ragnar team] decides to go all in for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/running/philadelphia-half&#34; title=&#34;Philadelphia Half&#34;&gt;Philly Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. Cave-in to the &amp;lsquo;runner&amp;rsquo;s pressure&amp;rsquo; and sign-up. Had a pretty decent run but decided not to run any more city runs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Swimming sessions at the Y. With the wife as the coach, life can be a bit under-water!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Philly run ends with news on the line on a new entrant in the family. Nieces galore! This one seems to be born with a bunch of butterflies. Exciting times ahead!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The graduation heat is On!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;December:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wait, the family is not yet done moving. This time to Ambiance!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Burning the midnight oil (The heater?) for the finals. You can&amp;rsquo;t really avoid those last-minute surprises. Can you? All said and done, I now hold a Master of Science! - One long-held desire, Checked.[icon name=&amp;ldquo;university&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Last minute Christmas packing frenzy. Love this time of the year. Gifting is fun! [icon name=&amp;ldquo;gift&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Signed off Christmas in Boston with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/233479444&#34;&gt;5mi run along the Charles river&lt;/a&gt; and rang in the new year at Ambiance.[icon name=&amp;ldquo;tree&amp;rdquo; class=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking back at 2010...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2010/12/30/looking-back-at-2010.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2010/12/30/looking-back-at-2010.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot thats been happening; but for some reason I just didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time out to visit this space. With the school closed down for the Christmas break and keeping up with the self imposed rule of updating my blog every year-end, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick snapshot  of &amp;lsquo;my&amp;rsquo; 2010.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year has been quite interesting from various perspectives. Looking back, the major checkpoints[not necessarily listed in order] this year  would be:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ran the infamous &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/blog/2010/02/running-through-the-woods/&#34;&gt;Auroville half marathon&lt;/a&gt; and vowed never to stop running!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/blog/2010/03/crossing-the-rickety-bridge/&#34;&gt;Resigned from Infosys&lt;/a&gt; to join TeachforIndia. [leaving an awesome team behind and making one profound shift in my career.]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Met Paruammai, attended a close friends wedding and more importantly explored Kerala like never before.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Joined TFI and reveled in the five week long induction programme.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the temptation to do the Katraj-Sinhagad night trek [Twice on successive weekends!] amidst the rigour of he institute.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Missed spending quality time with family!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reported to Epiphany School where I&amp;rsquo;ve been teaching IInd grade kids for the past six months and probably continue to do so for the next 1.5yrs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paid obeisance to the rain god by trekking the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/album.php?aid=179352&amp;amp;id=796079081&amp;amp;ref=pb&#34;&gt;Kenjalgad fort&lt;/a&gt; [First monsoon trek by DH.]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hiked up to the Ahupe village to take some time out and celebrate yet another important milestone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Visited the Khadakwasla dam.[Failed executing  the rock band idea though!]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Revisited[Hiked] Koraigad, Rajmachi and Ratangad.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rode to Khadakwasla dam [Got back to the byke after a long break of 5 months!]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Registered for the MBL course by Distance education mode from NLSIU.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Visited the Korlai fort [Didn&amp;rsquo;t byke this time!]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Registered for the Standard Chartered Mumbai Marathon[My first Full Marathon!] and raised about 9500Rs. for TFI.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ran the Pune Half marathon.[ Well, actually ran a 25!]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turned 25 Years! Woohoo!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ran the Goa River Marathon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Witnessed Shreks&amp;rsquo; [a co-fellow] wedding in Vizag.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Was gifted a Hookah, a mobile speaker , some invaluable coupons and a heart rate monitor!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Realised that I could afford to save more than I thought I could.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Squared in and took some real important decisions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vowed to stick on to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; TOTALLY.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well that kind of summarizes the year that&amp;rsquo;s been till date. Tomorrow hopefully I would run a sweet 30k to siphon off 2010  and usher in 2011 and for some reason, I have this gut feeling that the next year would be even more eventful than this year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wishing you [And myself!] an awesome and happening year ahead&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections from 09...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/31/reflections-from-09.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/12/31/reflections-from-09.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reached home quite late after an active day at work. Scrapped the &amp;lsquo;New year party&amp;rsquo; plan and decided to crash after a quick dinner. A perfunctory check of my e-mail throws about twenty &amp;lsquo;greeting&amp;rsquo; mails. I invariably tend to shift+delete such e-mails as I prefer talking over the phone to e-mails/SMS/IM. But one particular mail from my sister just swept me off my feet..- &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;may this new year bring you closer and closer to everything you want to do&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; These simple words are something that have stood by me all through. Miles away, she&amp;rsquo;s someone who&amp;rsquo;s been such a wonderful source of motivation for each and everything I do - day in and day out and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see any better way of thanking her than warding off my sleep to take snapshot of the amazing year 0f 2009!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since I graduated, I decided I would do something starkly different or interesting every two to three years and this year very much stands as a testimony to that conviction.Over time I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt to set my priorities straight and involve in activities that I think really stand for what truly represents me. I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt to trust my gut instinct more than anything else and live by my passions irrespective of what others think of me. On a personal front this year has been one of pursuing my passions like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Byking:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve cumulatively ridden 1500kms the whole last year. That really isn&amp;rsquo;t much compared to what other serious bikers do but I&amp;rsquo;m more than happy with the progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made. Transitioning from a trekker to a biker has been one hell of an experience and has got me to see a whole lot of wonderful places.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Enduro3 national level adventure race was one humbling learning experience where I really got to see what I was made of and what I could achieve. It sort of  wedged out a window to judge my capabilities vis-a-vis expectations set by people.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t snow here anymore!&amp;rsquo; This is what a villager up there in the lofty Himachal town of Jibhi had to say when we asked her about the weather there. Those innumerable climate change articles never really had any impact on me till I went up there on those mountain peaks. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/blog/2009/06/the-moron-the-bike-and-the-himalayas-jalori-pass-biking-expedition/&#34;&gt;Jalori Pass Mountain Biking&lt;/a&gt; expedition slammed me right on the face and got me thinking on what damage we &amp;rsquo;enlightened&amp;rsquo; people are causing. We snub our noses when we see someone damaging our property. Think of those people up there in the himalayas who&amp;rsquo;re bearing the brunt because of our insensible activities.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/blog/2009/09/the-korlai-ride/&#34;&gt;Korlai Ride&lt;/a&gt; was yet another stupendous ride that I would cherish for years to come. 205kms spanning three days in the mystical sahyadri ranges. It was just the man, the machine and nature!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Freedom Ride on the other hand was clearly something that cut across the point - It&amp;rsquo;s just not about the bike! 180+ riders riding together on Roadsters, Targets, Meridas and what not for 63kms on the roads of Hyderabad for the kids of Akshaya Akruthi. Boy, that was one hell of  a ride!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Running:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started running seriously sometime early in August and have clocked about 120kms till now. When I ran my first half marathon this November, the only goal I had in mind was to complete it without any glitches. I ended being ranked 100 out of the 220+ runners. For me personally, it&amp;rsquo;s not the distance or time that really matters. It&amp;rsquo;s more about the thought process that goes on in my mind during the run that I&amp;rsquo;m really interested in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2009 hasn&amp;rsquo;t really been a year of travel for various reasons. But then in those seasoned escapades, there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of takeaway.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Bidar ride - 20 riders, 10 bikes all set to explore the ramparts of the Bidar fort!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Kalsubai Conquest - As I scaled up Maharashtra&amp;rsquo;s highest peak, a friend acquainted from a bus ride plopped off the Chembra peak. Life&amp;rsquo;s so unpredictable!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/blog/2009/05/kawal-wildlife-sanctuary-the-moron-vs-wild/&#34;&gt;Kawal Wildlife Sanctuary&lt;/a&gt; - Stuck miserably for five grueling hours with four people I&amp;rsquo;d never met before in a wild life sanctuary with temperature  soaring to 40 deg.  Real testing times&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Junglethlon - Three days of Jungle survival course with a bunch of real interesting people. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t ask for a much better way to close the 2009 chapter!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Career:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That day simply changed my outlook towards things and eventually my career. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably save this for another post but in the nutshell, a solid seed was borne early this June and I&amp;rsquo;m more than excited about things&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about 01:15am here and the &amp;rsquo;new year&amp;rsquo; has already sprung in. Messages and e-mails are still swarming the networks and servers. Here&amp;rsquo;s wishing you folks a cheerful and happening new year! Fingers crossed on what 201o has in store&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As I turn 21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2006/12/11/as-i-turn-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2006/12/11/as-i-turn-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d written this long post on my 21st Birthday when I didn&amp;rsquo;t even have a blog. Happened to come across this when sifting through my e-mails and thought I&amp;rsquo;d save and back post this for records&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 12th 2006:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost six months that i&amp;rsquo;ve been placed in Infosys. But still at times, I find it hard to digest the fact that I hit the bull&amp;rsquo;s eye, right in the first shot! Having ideally no much expertise in coding languages, leave alone my own technical field, It&amp;rsquo;s been an admixture of both shock and surprises for me all the way through. If there had to be a core reason for me being placed, I would primarily attribute it to my Dad&amp;rsquo;s choice of enrolling me in the university that I am presently in. The reasons of enrolling me were way much different then. But does&amp;rsquo;nt  everything happens for a reason?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Studying in a college of pretty low repute, not a single thought had even occured to me all through the last three years about being placed in a firm through campus placements.I had just got back to the room after my GRE, when I heard rumours of  our college being invited to Tagore Engineering college for an offcampus placement. This was the first time we heard of prospective placements, and not one of us believed it. Just one day before, the Off campus was confirmed and none of us were prepared for it, neither mentally nor intellectually! Just one reconcilement was, we got to hear that Infosys does not emphasize on technical expertise; but then sources were pretty much unreliable!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 20th 2006&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The day before the interview (rather the night before the interview!)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only a handful of us had our resumes in hand. Formal wear and other requisites was an alltogether different question&amp;hellip;this was only our seventh semester beginning and placements was no where in sight! We had only a handful of systems operative and around fifty guys running berseck to get their resumes done first. A handful of guys prepared a rough draft of the resume and the rest of the pack just edited the same to develop theirs..the wierdest part of it! And when finally after a gruelling three hour tryst with our eye&amp;rsquo;s pondering over the resumes, we realized we needed hard copies and soft copies alone would do no good! We rushed over to a nearby cafe to get hold of a printer..a few of us got our resumes printer and a few couldn&amp;rsquo;t - The printer buckled! There was nothing more that we could do but go and purchase the formal wear&amp;hellip;10:00 at night.Finally we got back to our rooms buying what good clothes  we could buy from the one and only one reasonable store in the silk town&amp;hellip;All set and done,we got back to our rooms and tried to finish off our last minute arrangements for an interview&amp;hellip;certificates, photographs, mark sheets and other papers.All the requisite documents set right ( oh yeah!! BUT for the Resume..) we just hit the bed..Not one of the faces of my friends showed any sort of jittery feeling &amp;hellip;after all who cared!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 21st, 2006&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First day of the recruitment drive&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The college where the interview was about to be held was a good two and a half hours away from kanchi, so we had to start atleast four hours in advance.And then we had to scout out for DTP or Cafe&amp;rsquo;s for the resumes&amp;hellip;.Alarm&amp;rsquo;s started hooting at about four in the morning&amp;hellip;and there was a mad rush of people trying to first rush to the bath room and get ready.The frenzy settled in about an hour and a half and all of us were set to leave.A batch of about six guys (Calvin, Collin, Doggy, Gotman, Bruce lee and PLN )who got ready first left about half an hour early. The remaining battalion (including Me, Abhi, Doms ,Jamanujava, and Sexiter) left slowly at around 6:30.Had a hell of a time in the bus exchanging our thoughts on Infosys, major part of it out of our imagination! Placed calls to so called knowledgeable  people to find out things about the firm and all that junky stuff&amp;hellip;Finally got a break when  we got a call from Calvin telling us that he could trace out a cafe in Tambaram , enroute Vandalur. All pack of nuts finally met there and got the resume&amp;rsquo;s done.It was already 9:00 by then and the interview was supposed to start at around 9:30.We called up a few of our friends who had already reached the  college and asked them directions.Ten of us hurled into two auto&amp;rsquo;s and finally happened to reach the college just on time..Once we were there..it was as if the whole SCSVMV campus had been there to receive us&amp;hellip;.we were the last set of guys to reach the center.We settled in the room allotted to us and the scrutinizing of people began. There was one gruffy person checking people&amp;rsquo;s attires and their certificates and filtering out people who did not satisfy the basic requirements. The drill was over in about an hour and we had to wait for about two hours for the aptitude test to begin. The test began at about 12:00 and in almost one and a half hour we were done with our test…Basic Puzzles and a very simple Verbal section. All students were requested to wait for the test results, which they said would be released in around two hours. Most of us had an unpalatable meal in the College canteen and just kept whiling away time for the next two hours. Gotman, Abhi, Doggy, Munna and myself walked over to the room where we had first sat and after the sumptuous meal almost entered into a refreshing siesta almost simultaneously. Probably a few minutes after we started swooning, the gruffy guy banged on the class room door and literally ordered us to get over to another class room where results of the written test would be declared. We managed to reach the room, still partially asleep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Things changed drastically after this. Looking at people in the seminar room, I suddenly experienced the butterfly syndrome!! The fear of  failure!! Though I tried best to hold my composure, things didn&amp;rsquo;t really help…I just waded down to the rest room and got back only to find a larger troop inside…People seemed to be so very optimistic of being selected, I felt I was the odd one out. My inner feelings were so very averse , that I literally thought of spanking the guy beside me who was screwing me with his software language expertise. Fortunately, a couple of my college mates happened to take the seats in my row and things got better then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The results were announced alphabetically college wise. When names from our college were read…I, for no apparent reason, felt the urge to hear my name in the list….who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t… the thought of a job in hand, a job in one of the reputed firms in India. Just out of college life… one of not much repute…Placement mattered. It would be like missing the treasure, right when the key is given to you…My grey cells were literally flushing with unnecessary thoughts ….Those, I believe are the moments and feelings that I would never forget in my life. My feelings gave way when I heard the name &amp;lsquo;Srikanth S Perinkulam&amp;rsquo; being read out. From then, I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt to respect the name…respect the way it is spelt .No doubt I was on cloud nine when I heard my name being read out…but then reactions had to be controlled to a very large extent as not many of my close friends were filtered in. Around fifteen of us were selected in the written test from about 180 from our University (170 and odd from the overall 2000). It was almost 6:30 by the time all the results were announced and the details of the next day&amp;rsquo;s Interview were given.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The college was in a quite remote location and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any proper conveyance mode to the main city. A few lucky of us happened to hop into a bus and managed to reach the City. We reached back kanchi at about 12:00 midnight. I was the only one in my room to be selected and had an excruciating time facing my other roomies. Bruce lee was the one to tell me that quite a few of my batch mates had walked all the way back to the city from the remote college (around 4kms) literally crying over their ill luck. Only then did I realize how lucky I had been, and how much being placed in a company means to final years from a non reputed institute.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 22nd 2006&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Second day of the recruitment drive&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early morning again at around 4:00 in the morning the alarm rang. But then I was the only one who had to get up. Was up and ready by around five. I knew having cleared the written test, getting through the HR shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a big hurdle. I had also heard Infosys HR rounds are a cake walk. Now, the ball was in my court and I knew it was up to me to give it the best short. Every word that I talk in the interview would decide my future and I had to do my homework. For one solid hour I sat and posed myself all probable questions I would face, prepared irrefutable answers, and rehearsed my body language mentally, visioning myself before the HR. That brief  spell of ten to fifteen minutes would transform the way people look at me. The way I look at life,  more so because I had  to dismiss all allegations set up on me and this was one wholesome opportunity. That one hour is the only hour in my life till date that I have devoted hundred percent concentration to…This had to be a zero and a one…the result HAD to be a 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With spirits high, but still shell nervous, I walked over to the bus stand at around 6:30. Collin and Abhi had stayed back at Chennai the previous night at their relatives place and planned to come down directly the next day. Met Ravi Bhattrai and Alpana there and from then on had a quick journey to the college. Reached the college at about 9:00 am .The scrutinizing of certificates began again and we were asked to wait for our turn of HR. The SCSVMV batch was called to the first floor of the College building .The HR session was being held in different labs in the same floor. Most of us were seated adjacent to the Computer Lab. There was a camera on each corridor ceiling and I started wondering if at all videos were being streamed to some location in Alaska. My senses brought me back to reality and with this brief imagination started the damn jittery feeling again..…the fear of losing!! I realized unless I shred all unnecessary thoughts my one hour of hard work would take me no where. Just to divert my attention I roped in Ravi Bhattrai to a conversation and we started talking about every damn thing in the world…movies ,games, places, novels, tourist spots, girl friends and what not…and that did help us to a very large extent. Meanwhile Tiwari and Satish joined the conversation and things got quite relaxed. Turn by turn, people were called in to the Lab and interviewed. From what I heard from people coming after the interview, I pictured the room and the location of the HR. Plan B had to be rolled out now. I had to get acclimatized to the environs mentally. Just a few minutes after the dust in my mind settled, my name was called ….Srikanth S Perinkulam.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Course of the HR Interview:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The moment I was led into the Lab, I had a quick survey of the seating arrangements of the HR&amp;rsquo;s. There were about six of them, all ladies, totally seated in three rows one behind the other and spaced equally all through the expanse of the lab. There was no means of one HR being able to listen to another HR&amp;rsquo;s conversation. Realising this did wonders to my confidence levels and my morale was boosted. It&amp;rsquo;s always easy to tackle one single person than two…Plan C need not be evoked!! I was requested to proceed to one HR seated in the left corner just as I entered the Lab.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The HR was facing the expanse of the hall, so I would not have to, during the interview phase&amp;hellip;just another morale booster!! I walked over to the table, turned around  gave her a gentle false smile, asked her permission to sit and gently sat down, all the while having a sub conscious eye on my body language. She was the one to break the silence first and asked me for my resume. I took all my time in the world to gently remove my resume, giving her time to atleast have a glimpse of my well ordered and indexed set of certificates in the royal folder that I was carrying. The Table is not yours!! I had read in quite a few CSR interview booklets that my bro. had subscribed to for his preparation for CAT. Mindful of that I gently handed over the resume to her hand. The remaining major part of my interview was wholly dependant on my resume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first question she asked was why I&amp;rsquo;d joined a University somewhere in the outskirts of Chennai when we had wonderful colleges at hyderabad. I was well prepared for this question I have been answering it for the past three years to almost every Tom Dick and Harry I end up having a conversation and each time I&amp;rsquo;ve given an almost different reason. But this time I had to give an answer that could change the course of the interview to my side. All that I said was a direct blatant answer…I wasn&amp;rsquo;t academically strong in my 11th and 12th grade…gave a gasp for about three seconds and then said.. But then once getting exposed to the really competitive world in the course of my engineering I&amp;rsquo;ve turned stones. I&amp;rsquo;m probably not good at answering questions oriented theoretically, which require by rote knowledge. But I am pretty good in the practical point of view. All through the last three years I&amp;rsquo;ve been consistently receiving an S Grade in my Labs. Not to mention my good grades in other Theoretical subjects. Thanks to my mastery of the art of answering theoretical questions that my schooling has taught me…and we all know how examinations in India are held. With such a response I could explicitly bring out three main points of my personality a) My ability to learn from my experiences b) My Practical orientation in life c) My realization of the way of the society functions. With the very look on her face I could see I had given a justifiable answer and that the ball was still in my court….&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second question that she&amp;rsquo;d asked me was regarding my choice of Career. Why ECE ? I knew I had to keep in mind that I was applying for a software company and my long term goals that I would be mentioning soon should be in line with the requirements of the software industry. I very well knew this wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be a technical interview so I planned my response on those lines. My response was…I&amp;rsquo;ve always been interested in Computer Science and the primary reason for me joining ECE was because I felt I had the ability to learn the intricacies of coding In parallel to my regular course of study. I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt working with SQL and am quite conversant in UNIX commands. I do have a good understanding of the basics of coding languages like C and can work with HTML commands with ease. With such a response, as previously mentioned I&amp;rsquo;ve strengthened my stand as a good prospective software engineer and have exploited her question to the most possible extent besides revealing the languages or scripts that I am familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next question was quite a common one that is generally asked in almost any Interview. Why Infosys? I responded saying it had the best Work culture, being both Social and competitive. I&amp;rsquo;ve got quite a few of my relatives working in Infosys and from what I hear from them and their previous experiences, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized it to be the best company to work with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then she asked me a few questions on my industrial training sessions, what was taught there, and other questions such as Your Positive features,  Negative aspects , Long term goals, Future plans , Hobbies and the like. The interview had been running for almost around thirty minutes for now and things weren&amp;rsquo;t looking like as if they were going to end. Finally she turned my resume over to the second page. I had listed myself as being a member of IEEE.. She asked me what role I played as an IEEE member. To this I responded as saying that I was an active member of the IEEE Chapter in organizing technical events and have met several prominent personalities (Doled out quite a few names…brought in people who never existed ! Boy, I still don&amp;rsquo;t believe I did that!) . I also emphasized on the skills that I had learnt whilst being a member such as working in a team, leading a group of people and the like…..The very expression on her face spelt that she had taken the bait. And that gave me further confidence…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then finally she gave a smile and told me to solve a small puzzle..I had to find a triangle in a maze of circles or something of that sort.Done with that she said &amp;lsquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve come to the end of the Interview. So Perinkulam do you have any questions?&amp;rsquo; I was on cloud nine, when I heard that the interview had come to an end but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really prepared for an answer to this question. So just to buy time I asked her when I could get to know about the results. She responded saying it should be out in an hour or so. Not able to frame any more questions impromptu, I just smiled and thanking her quit the lab gently and as soon as possible….and this is where I felt I could have taken a beating.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now all said and done, my Interview was done with and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really sure of the outcome. Machi, Sami and Ravi had to still complete their interview. Sami was thundered with a lot of Technical questions and was pinned by two HR&amp;rsquo;s. and Machi was&amp;rsquo;nt really confident in his approach. Ravi was chilling out and things were pretty calm after the HR session….We had a grueling three hour wait and finally at around 6:30 the results were declared. Abhi, Ravi, Madhu,Tiwari,Collin, Jai anand, Animesh, Hippo and I had cleared the HR. Aravind, Machi, Sami and Alpana were screened out. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t much of an elated air, for reasons mentioned before, but the moment we were segregated from them…Man!! You should have seen the ruckus that was created…people literally kicking each other like predator and prey!!! We had a post placement talk wherein they informed us about the offer letter, passport etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After such a tensed day, only at the end did I experience the real throbbing heart inside me. The feeling.. Mamoo tho bhi kuch banega life mein…crept in. I had developed a feeling that  I&amp;rsquo;ve shattered all possible inhibitions in my mind , that I &amp;rsquo;ve overcome something that&amp;rsquo;s been a hindrance all through my schooling and college life. I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got at least one salient point on my list and the thought of the black mole in the family being me is weeded out. If there&amp;rsquo;s something that my success is to be attributed to, it would be to that solid one hour that I had spent in the morning. That one hour paid off!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Retrospect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And on this day when I turn 21, if I look back at my life in the year 2006, I realize how lucky I&amp;rsquo;ve been. On July 7th when I escaped unscathed after a horrible accident (involving the bus in which I was traveling and an Oil Tanker on NH7) which scooped 16 lives; On July 17th when I was almost sure I had to redo the GRE test and all through the test I was intent on clicking the EXIT button without even completing the test and on July 22nd when the Infy thing happened…I am sure Luck&amp;rsquo;s played a horribly vital role. Things have changed quite a lot this year….and with things, even I&amp;rsquo;ve changed….Or is it that Darwin&amp;rsquo;s theory - Survival of the fittest is being reinstated in my life…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
