<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2007-05-21 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2007-05-21-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2007-05-21 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2007-05-21-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>License and Global Warming!</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2007/05/21/license-and-global-warming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2007/05/21/license-and-global-warming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the WordWeb Dictionary for almost two years now. Well, this is an application which gives you the meaning of almost any English word that you ping in ( a bit of an exaggeration, but believe me, It&amp;rsquo;s extremely good! :-) )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coming to the main part now, I happened to install a newer version of it a month back. Yesterday, when I opened the application a message popped up telling me that my trial version had expired. Hey, but this was not any common license validation request that one generally comes across! I&amp;rsquo;ve paraphrased their statement here. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t help controlling my laughter having read the clause! :-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free version licence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You have just crossed the 30 day trial period. WordWeb may be freely used only by people who meet the conditions below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You may use the program free of charge indefinitely only if&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;You take at most 4 flights (2 return flights) in any 12 month period&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;AND you do not own or regularly drive an SUV (sports utility vehicle).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you do not qualify you must uninstall the program after the 30-day trial period or purchase &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordweb.info/&#34;&gt;WordWeb Pro&lt;/a&gt;. The licence is designed to provide a small incentive for people with massively unsustainable emissions to cut down.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whenever a user no longer meets the above requirements, and they have installed the product for more than 30 days, they must uninstall the product or purchase WordWeb Pro; otherwise it is software theft.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are two exceptions to the above: not-for-profit educational establishments may install WordWeb for the use of their students (regardless of whether their students meet the &amp;ldquo;sustainable user&amp;rdquo; requirement), and the registered disabled who require an SUV for transport may use the program freely if they take at most four flights per year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, both the clauses do not apply to me and I continue to use the application without any licensing done :-) . Nevertheless, it did drive the point home regarding Global warming at least for a few moments!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
