<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SGV on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/sgv/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in SGV on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/sgv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brake fade</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/GrandVitaraCuernavaca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downhill and no brakes, what fun! Definitely not at that moment though. Somewhere near Cuernavaca, The Grand Vitara had a brake fade &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; this morning on our way to Las Estacas. The brakes would just not work and it felt like I had to pump it to get even a bit of traction.  Got  super close to hitting the car in front of us but thankfully, I found a small lane (ditch?) to veer off from the traffic and engine braked it to a stop. Super lucky none of us were hurt and we were able to veer away from traffic just in time. Also lucky that this happened just about 100m from a mechanic shop! What are the odds? Took them about three hours to do a &lt;del&gt;thorough&lt;/del&gt; check on all four wheels and fix the oil reservoir tray - which they broke while jacking the car up. Oh boy, what a start to this years&amp;rsquo; Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Immediately after we were able to get the vehicle to a stop, M asked if it was the floor mat that was the culprit. Nope - I&amp;rsquo;d removed them a few days after we bought this car. All thanks to another &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/04/26/the-grand-cherokee/&#34;&gt;dreadful experience&lt;/a&gt; several years ago in the Grand Cherokee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ignorance and oversight only make sense in hindsight.  About fifteen minutes before this incident,  I did notice the brakes feeling soft and remember thinking - that&amp;rsquo;s odd the brakes worked just fine so far. Also maybe I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice the smoke from the tires because we were driving through quasi dirt roads? All signs of the brakes giving in - had I known about brake fade then. Wee bit wiser now I guess? &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apparently that is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brake_fade&#34;&gt;technical term&lt;/a&gt; for a failed brake.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
