<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>India-Travel-Options on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/india-travel-options/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in India-Travel-Options on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/india-travel-options/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What it takes to travel...</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2009/06/07/what-it-takes-to-travel.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2009/06/07/what-it-takes-to-travel.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One very common question that I&amp;rsquo;m asked when I meet people in person who&amp;rsquo;ve come across my blog is how and why I travel so frequently. Today I received two e-mails from people whom I&amp;rsquo;ve not even met asking me the same question. I&amp;rsquo;ve never really given much thought to this per se, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d chalk this out here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passion:&lt;/strong&gt; I travel because I need to! Ever since my graduation, I&amp;rsquo;ve trained my brain to reject monotony in any form. And travel happened to be one major part of it! As you start venturing out, you realise how much you&amp;rsquo;ve missed and that there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to &amp;rsquo;living life&amp;rsquo; than the regular 8 to 5 job. Travel in a way gives you a different perspective to look at things and believe me, solutions at times too!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diversity:&lt;/strong&gt; If there&amp;rsquo;s one reason why I transformed from an introvert moron to an extrovert[ Still a moron!]- It&amp;rsquo;s travel. You end up meeting so many different people from different places that the diversity at times threatens to take you off your roots. Okay, thats more of an exaggeration - But you get it. The best part is, you get to relate to things much better once you&amp;rsquo;re exposed to a different groups culture and habits. It&amp;rsquo;s basically understanding  history through a different person&amp;rsquo;s perspective! My latest escapade was to the north - &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/blog/2009/06/the-moron-the-bike-and-the-himalayas-jalori-pass-biking-expedition/&#34;&gt;Himachal Pradesh&lt;/a&gt;. And boy, what a learning it was!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finance:&lt;/strong&gt; I travel on a meager budgets. I set a constraint and see to it that I stick to it as far as possible. Most of the treks[Close to 25] in Pune that I did last year, you won&amp;rsquo;t believe was each done on a budget varying from 100Rs. - 300Rs. - Food, transport, accommodation all incl. The central idea is to travel in groups. When I say groups, that could range anywhere between say 10 to 30 for one trip. Well, this is also one of the reasons why couple of my colleagues and I started HydVentura- The Hyderabad adventure club. It gives us a big platform to group up and wind out on weekends whenever possible. For long trips on the other hand, I save over a period of time [six to seven months] specifically for this. This could mean cutting my expenses on things that are not really essential [Movies/Branded clothing for instance]. Also, It&amp;rsquo;s been close to a year that I&amp;rsquo;ve bought petrol [ I have a beast - The lumala which I ride on wherever I need to go]. So that fund gets allocated to this bucket. Effectively you do not end up burdening yourself at the fag end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leave:&lt;/strong&gt; Needless to say, this is one important thing that can botch all your plans. It pays to inform your team and lead that you would be off for a vacation as early as you start saving for it!And if you think your project would doom if you&amp;rsquo;re off for a few days, Think again!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This world is full of myriad complexities. And then, there&amp;rsquo;s something called life. Live it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On similar lines:  Of things you chose to miss&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
