<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2019-12-01 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/date/2019-12-01-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019-12-01 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/date/2019-12-01-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 48 - Thanksgiving and Ezekiel drive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/12/01/weeknote-48-thanksgiving-and-ezekiel-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019/12/01/weeknote-48-thanksgiving-and-ezekiel-drive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few articles, podcasts, tools, videos and music that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Between Shreya&amp;rsquo;s birthday party in CT, the usual thanks-giving meet in NJ and Ankur&amp;rsquo;s wedding in NY; this week has been pretty busy with lots of domestic travel. We had winter storm Ezekiel right by our tail, as we made our way back from Albany on Sunday!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meena sent in her cheek swab to get added to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bethematch.org/about-us/&#34;&gt;Marrow donor registry&lt;/a&gt;. Another family member did the same with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dkms.org/en&#34;&gt;DKMS&lt;/a&gt;. Manni mentioned she might sign-up for that too. Might need a nudge few days later, but I think we&amp;rsquo;re there!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fit in a good 5 mile run on Tuesday morning and a short 2.5 mile hike near Rutgers Gardens on Saturday morning. A high on intake and mild on workout kinda week!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting tools this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eerotal/LibreSignage/blob/next/README.rst&#34;&gt;LibreSignage&lt;/a&gt; : FOSS digital signage solution for multiple displays.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/11/24/smarter-living/privacy-online-how-to-stop-advertiser-tracking-opt-out.html&#34;&gt;You’re Tracked Everywhere You Go Online. Use This Guide to Fight Back.&lt;/a&gt; : There is always someone(thing) lurking round the corner to get hold of your data!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://caseyhandmer.wordpress.com/2019/11/02/starlink-is-a-very-big-deal/&#34;&gt;Starlink is a very big deal&lt;/a&gt;: A deep-dive into SpaceX&amp;rsquo;s satellite internet plans. On my recent trip to India, I was pleasantly surprised by the internet plans and pricing. Heavy competition has driven the prices down and speeds way up. One could easily access super-fast internet speeds on hand-held devices paying just about $2 a month! Starlink does sound like a refreshing and promising competition to the regular internet providers here in many states in the U.S.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/2019/11/26/782890646/2-months-after-failed-moon-landing-india-admits-its-craft-crashed&#34;&gt;2 Months After Failed Moon Landing, India Acknowledges Its Craft Crashed&lt;/a&gt;: While Chandrayaan-2 was a minor setback, ISRO seems to have an exciting line-up over the next few years!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
