<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2011-07-10 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2011-07-10-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2011-07-10 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2011-07-10-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of the playground…</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/dynamics-of-the-playground/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/dynamics-of-the-playground/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Couple of  hours back I opened my student tracker,  just sat back and started mulling over how each of my kids have changed over the past few months. As I went through the list reading each of the kids names, images of the kid kept flashing in and out of my mind and most of them, so turned out to be of those moments when they were being ecstatic or really happy. This made me wonder how we as humans tend to capture/remember only the positives or the cheerful part in our relationships. But as a teacher, am I not failing my kids in not noticing their negative behaviour and working to get them back to their normal self? Am I doing justice to them by not stopping what I’m doing and not taking that extra time to pay attention to that minuscule behavioral change? How many times have I swept a behavioral change under the blanket and continued with my class/session? How many times have I ‘neglected’ a kid in the rush to finish off a topic/objective?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sadly in retrospect I seem to recollect more than one occasions where I’ve failed noticing/paying heed to the change. This could probably be one of those reasons why a particular kid did not perform well in a particular objective; a reason why a particular kid did not receive me with the same enthusiasm as he otherwise would have and this is something I’m really beginning to appreciate in this role as a teacher. Every moment in the classroom you end up dealing with the emotions of 46 kids out there. Human to human interaction is the utmost priority. When I go back to my classroom in twenty days for the second term, this is one thing that I have to keep in mind always.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Talking by numbers, my kids have progressed from a class average of 25% to 56% in Math, from 17% to 59% in Grammar and from 28%[-0.1 Grade] to 85%[1.5 Grade] in RC. Thats some significant progress that the class has made. But again, the class average does not necessarily represent the overall growth of the classroom. There still are kids like – Sarfaraz, Nabil, Aditya More, Meghana and Yash Pawar who need to make tremendous progress if they have to be on par with the other kids. I guess that is where the main challenge lies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, I visualize my classroom as a circular board resting on a pivot. I being the pivot and the circular board,  a playground where my 46 little ones decide the dynamics of the classroom from inside. My responsibility is to  maintain the equilibrium and I need to be extremely flexible so as to adjust and re-position to the external stimuli and the dynamics created by my kids so that the whole system remains in equilibrium &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt;. The next fortnight I guess is all about figuring out how to maintain that equilibrium, about how I push myself to my limits of being flexible and making that transformation something sustainable…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections by the roadside…</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/reflections-by-the-roadside/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/reflections-by-the-roadside/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I take one last gulp of hot tea from a roadside stall, Ronnie wickedly smiles and brings his hand forward with a congratulatory gesture. He just says – ‘One month’ and grins wildly! I wink back, pay for the tea and walk back towards the school gate. As we quickly make our way through the puddles and pits in the slight Pune drizzle, my mind wanders out in search of those small moments that I could call ‘achievements’ of the month thats been from my one month of teachers life. Sadly I get to recollect just a couple of them. And then it looms on me again how important it is to appreciate minuscule milestones in this journey – Something which I’ve been working hard on ever since the summer school.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today for some reason, I’m not really as happy as I should have been. Administered a diagnostic test today and a perfunctory look at the sheets sunk me deeper in the gravel. These kids are just not able to answer even bare simple questions. I’ve spent about 23 whole days with these 46 kids and things do not really seem to be on the green side. Classroom and Behavior management still seems to be an issue and objectives wise I haven’t progressed much. They seem to understand Math concepts but for some reason that is just not translating onto the answer sheets. Collectively they seem to know how to reach to the solution but when asked individually they just put up a poker face. English for them seems to be a magnanimous monster lurching right round the corner. I’m yet to figure out where that small invisible spark exists so that I can magically tap it on and fire them up to speed. A couple of strategies to be implemented and a lot more are to be learnt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow marks a new beginning of looking back and taking the best of what worked; of paying attention and appreciating the minute ‘eureka’ moments in the classroom and not to forget – of understanding how close I could get to build the bridge between possibility, predictability and uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The battle so far</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/the-battle-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/the-battle-so-far/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just about a month that the second academic year has started. The past four weeks have been really hectic juggling the plethora of tasks left on the table. The kids have slowly started getting back to the regular schedules and attendance is almost touching 100 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The much needed break that I took hiking up the Himalayas and the internship at the TFI Summer institute gave a fresh perspective to the second academic year that I would be spending with the kids. Back in the holidays I was both optimistic and jittery about the maturity factor that I was expecting to see in the kids. Compared to last year they now seem to be much more on their toes and have got quite restless.It takes much more patience and effort to get their attention and even more a challenge to retain it. Wondering why, I could corner upon a couple of reasons - They&amp;rsquo;ve just not yet got out of their holiday mood, the afternoon summer camp is taxing them out or the more worrying concern - something is just not working in the classroom properly. The second year, at least the first quarter seems to be much more demanding in terms of investment and classroom management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On another front, this year we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to push them in both academics and extra curricular as far as possible. We&amp;rsquo;re rolling out &lt;a href=&#34;http://theepiphanydynasty.wordpress.com/projects/&#34; title=&#34;Projects&#34;&gt;several projects&lt;/a&gt; for them and holding them accountable to three supreme goals that we&amp;rsquo;ve set. Exposing them to various opportunities available and training them to be self dependent is something that&amp;rsquo;s bang up on the list.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Funnily, the year has just started.but every time I walk into the classroom reality looms in as to how little time [Just about 8 months!] we&amp;rsquo;re left with to accomplish all that we&amp;rsquo;ve planned out for them. As time progresses, hopefully things would get a bit more concrete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates from Epiphany</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/updates-from-epiphany/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/updates-from-epiphany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End of Year Showcase:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today was the last day of the academic year for the kids. We got them to put up a small act as an End of Year showcase and invited their parents to come witness it. The idea was to get parents to be more invested in their kids education besides building the confidence of the kids. The kids were amazing on stage and put up a real pricey show! You should be able to access the video through this link: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/22119752&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/22119752&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academics:&lt;/strong&gt; On the academic front, We&amp;rsquo;ve finished administering and tracking the kids final papers. At the beginning of the year the target was to gain a 1.5year growth on Reading Fluency, Reading Comprehension, Speaking &amp;amp; Listening, Grammar, Writing and Math. Our class average was at a mid KG level.[ Meaning, most of my kids who just entered second grade were just at the KG level].&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The final diagnostics put them at a  1.2yrs growth in RF, 0.5yrs growth in RC, 1.2yrs growth in S&amp;amp;L, 1.5yrs growth in Writing and 1.0 yrs growth in Math. Though we haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to strike the targeted goal, guess this year would be a sound foundation for their growth next year. This summer should give the necessary time to plan and strategize for the oncoming academic year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parting gifts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;- Aditya More - the weakest kid in the class[Who till now hasn&amp;rsquo;t spoken even a simple complete sentence in english in class ] stood up in front of the 70 odd parents and 90 odd kids and spoke three sentences! Couldn&amp;rsquo;t have asked for a better gift&amp;hellip; - Khushi nudged me aside and handed over this thank you note!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all the support you folks have provided till date. Will keep you posted once the next academic year starts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have a great weekend ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When a Dynasty is born...</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/when-a-dynasty-is-born.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/when-a-dynasty-is-born.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yet another day was coming to an end and the people of the land were tending their chores. It was all one peaceful ambiance with just minor disruptions here and there.  To help manage the affairs, the architect of the land decided to pull up a few responsible men and women and give them the authority to administer sections of the land..Well, ‘Decentralization of power’ as they call it. And then, things changed. With just one word, rose eleven kingdoms all powerful and energetic. And within minutes, the Kings and Queens swore at the altar to uprise their just formed kingdoms. Ministers, Treasurers and Soldiers were deputed and responsibilities bestowed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since then, things have drastically improved. The men and women now have something really concrete to look forward to – a structure, a pattern and above all rejoice in the powers that they otherwise would not have. There’s now an aura of peace in the empire and the subjects seem to be showing quite some interest in strengthening their kingdoms.  As days progress, the architect is still working out the finer details as to how the empires could be allowed to rule in mutual peace and still compete with each other for mutual benefit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Class of IIA at Epiphany- Where we play the Age of Empires with real Kings, Queens and Ministers!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking back, it’s kind of funny how just a random idea seems to be making so much of an impact on the kids. Ever since we divided the classroom into groups and gave them this theme to build upon, things have quite changed. Behavior management in the classroom has tremendously improved and almost every objective that is taught, once related to the theme even in some abstract form is investing the kids so much. It has also given scope to introduce an awesome value system in the class, which I’ve been trying in vain for the past 8 months to integrate in my regular classes. This coming friday, if things work well, I hopefully would be able to introduce them to the barter system and eventually trade and commerce. The options seem endless…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While biking back home today, I wonder why this idea didn’t strike me when I was scouting for a proper theme for my class late June, last year. There’s just about 25 instructional days left for this academic year to come to an end and I probably could have invested them a bit more had things ‘clicked’ before. But well, I guess thats just the feeling of not doing enough, that every teacher experiences every single day in his/her life. Really hoping this new system evolves into a robust framework and also if nothing works, I still can now be proud of founding eleven dynasties, not just in my dreams but in reality!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windowed Illusions…</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/windowed-illusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2011/07/10/windowed-illusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yesterday-was-one-of-those-real-interesting-days-couple-of-friends-and-i-had-been-to-thekorlai-forthttpssrikanthperinkulamcomblog200909the-korlai-rideand-were-heading-back-from-alibag-late-in-the-evening-seated-in-the-rear-of-the-bus-im-not-really-sure-how-this-conversationdebate-ensued-for-about-an-hour-or-so-the-six-of-us-had-a-heated-conversation-on-various-policies-practices-ideologies-and-biases-probably-one-of-the-best-ever-deliberations-since-my-infy-days-in-introspection-it-kind-of-gave-me-some-food-for-thought-on-how-id-like-to-proceed-with-the-rest-of-my-fellowship-or-for-the-next-two-years&#34;&gt;Yesterday was one of those real interesting days. Couple of friends and I had been to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/blog/2009/09/the-korlai-ride/&#34;&gt;Korlai fort&lt;/a&gt; and were heading back from Alibag late in the evening. Seated in the rear of the bus, I’m not really sure how this conversation/debate ensued. For about an hour or so the six of us had a heated conversation on various policies, practices, ideologies and biases. Probably one of the best ever deliberations since my Infy days. In introspection, it kind of gave me some food for thought on how I’d like to proceed with the rest of my fellowship or for the next two years.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; Since I last wrote, things have quite changed in my classroom and otherwise.  TFI has this concept of having two teachers in one class room if the number of students is more than 30. Kavitha, My co-teacher formally chipped in in July. With this things slowly seem to come under control. The kids receive more personal attention and we’re able to address issues in a much better fashion. Couple of kids who never even open their mouths are slowly opening up and and are showing interest in the classroom. The class dynamics has changed and kids are slowly learning to appreciate English.  Community visits seem to make an impact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; Going by last weeks assessments the class per se has shown significant improvement. But looking holistically I still do not see myself doing justice to the kids. Two years down the lane when I move out of this role, I would like to see my kids be able to speak for themselves, have the confidence to stand for what they really feel about and be able to take appropriate decisions given a set of choices. I personally believe, all that these nimble minds needs is exposure to the world out there and a pathway that would help them generate a practical solution to  problems.  They’re more than smart to figure out things for themselves.  Teaching them Arithmetic and Grammar probably would be in the last of the priorities list.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; Drawing the dividing line between catering to the parents and schools mandates of ‘completing’ the syllabus, and really imparting what I truly believe would help the kids overtime is something I still need to get a knack of . It is so heartening and overwhelming to see what a few fellows out here are able to accomplish in their classrooms. I guess only time would tell how things unfold…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
