<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macro on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/macro/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Macro on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/macro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024 Year end note</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/31/2024-year-end-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/31/2024-year-end-note/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;jan&#34;&gt;JAN&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hiked up Izta via &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/01/28/la-joya-izta-volcan-hike/&#34;&gt;La Joya&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quick work trip to Monterrey. Loved that those hills are right there in the city! Next time I&amp;rsquo;m back here, I should plan to get here around a weekend. Food was great. Traffic was meh. Would strongly consider bidding for a position here - if/when one opens up!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M,S &amp;amp; S went to Oaxaca. They loved it!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;feb&#34;&gt;FEB&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work travels took me to Merida and Managua. Managua had the vibes of any second tier southern Indian city.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anton&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/02/05/prieto-y-prieta/&#34;&gt;Whiskey tasting&lt;/a&gt; was uber fun!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Girl scouts hike to Desierto Leones. Mike led the group. Was good to take a step back and be just a regular participant!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Piedra Herrada Monarch butterfly trip. Barely got to spot any Monarchs. Looks like they made their way up north a bit sooner this year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;mar&#34;&gt;MAR&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Aparna and Vuday visit us for a few days. Joined them on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/04/globo-aerost%C3%A1tico/&#34;&gt;hot air balloon up the Teotihuacan Pyramids&lt;/a&gt;. Such a cool experience!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Back in Managua for a longish trip. Those wire pulls were painful but so much fun!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M &amp;amp; S went to Las Estacas for the Girl Scouts Camping trip. Missed being there with them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We took our R&amp;amp;R in Maui for about a week. So much fun being in the water! But boy, oh so pricey! &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/03/leleiwi-overlook-trail/&#34;&gt;Haleakala&lt;/a&gt; was neat. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/06/maui-whales/&#34;&gt;Missed the whales&lt;/a&gt; though!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;apr&#34;&gt;APR&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/12/izta-attempt/&#34;&gt;Hallucinations up on the Izta&lt;/a&gt; were surreal.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Family visited Cancun. We took a rain-check. Just didn&amp;rsquo;t make financial sense.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jothi patti and the Wierer&amp;rsquo;s visited us for a week.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/23/nevado-de-toluca/&#34;&gt;Nevado de toluca&lt;/a&gt; hike would probably be one of the highlights of our Mexico posting!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hiked up &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/14/pico-de-%C3%A1guila/&#34;&gt;Pico de aguila cerro cruz&lt;/a&gt;. The descent was - oh so painful - but super fun!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work trip to Hermosillo.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;may&#34;&gt;MAY&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yet another epic Bourbon tasting evening.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M took a salsa making class and she said she loved it!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A quick whirlwind trip to NJ, NY, MD for Rohita&amp;rsquo;s wedding.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S went for a weeklong &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/05/18/pipiol/&#34;&gt;school trip to Pipiol&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;d see the effects of it over the next few weeks&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Managed to fit in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/05/17/nextcloudpi/&#34;&gt;NextcloudPi migration&lt;/a&gt; and setup the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/05/23/digital-photo-frame/&#34;&gt;Digital Frame&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work took me back to Monterrey for a short project and then to Merida for a routine visit. Good bunch of travel this month.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;jun&#34;&gt;JUN&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appa, Manni and Miss Bama whip out a super successful India trip.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M,S and I went to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/06/03/bmg/&#34;&gt;Blue Man Group performance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jinesh &amp;amp; Soony visit us in CDMX for a few days.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tinkered a bit with &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/06/08/tasmota/&#34;&gt;Tasmota&lt;/a&gt; and HomeAssistant to setup a few smart-plugs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Freehold fly visit us for a couple weeks. Kids were amazing but boy, it was one loud household!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;jul&#34;&gt;JUL&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M&amp;amp;S visit New Braunfels and spend a week with the Hancocks. Absolutely floored by the Schlitterbahn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M takes a PLP trip to Hidalgo.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yet another work trip to Merida.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;aug&#34;&gt;AUG&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A&amp;amp;A move in to their new house!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work travel to Hermosillo for the NCC move. Super productive but tiring couple weeks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M&amp;amp;S come visit me in HMO over one of the weekends.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wierer&amp;rsquo;s visit CDMX for another short visit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daphne&amp;rsquo;s and WhiteBagley&amp;rsquo;s visit us for a few weeks. We make it to Nevado de Toluca for a short hike.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sep&#34;&gt;SEP&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/09/18/moving/&#34;&gt;Hermosillo trip&lt;/a&gt; continues.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M goes to Vancouver for the girls&amp;rsquo; trip. S&amp;amp;I have a good three nights by ourselves. S does pretty good!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/09/28/woken/&#34;&gt;CDMX monsoon&lt;/a&gt; is in full swing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;oct&#34;&gt;OCT&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yet another GS Hike. This time to &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/17/cascada-de-la-burbuja/&#34;&gt;Cascada de Burbuja&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I take the bike out for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/26/dia-de-muertos-ride/&#34;&gt;Dia de muerto&lt;/a&gt; bike ride&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth visits for a week. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/31/diwali/&#34;&gt;Diwali!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M&amp;amp;S visit Reino animal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We do a short road trip to &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/28/tula-and-tepozotlan/&#34;&gt;Tula and Tepozotlan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Back to Matamoros for a long standing project. A mild &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/14/mat-notes/&#34;&gt;cartel scare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/29/crisp-new-start/&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; goes kaput. Migrated this portal to Hugo after dabbling around a bit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;nov&#34;&gt;NOV&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Back to &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/16/spanglish/&#34;&gt;Merida&lt;/a&gt; for a prep trip.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M,S &amp;amp; I head to &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/18/bacalar/&#34;&gt;Bacalar&lt;/a&gt;. Some good time in the Yucatan peninsula.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brought out some ESC colleagues to &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/24/arista-de-humboldt/&#34;&gt;Nevado de Toluca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S celebrates her 6th with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/11/sixth/&#34;&gt;unicorn Pinata&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;dec&#34;&gt;DEC&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;M finally hears about her &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/06/ca-aefm/&#34;&gt;CA-AEFM position&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;V&amp;amp;D visit us for a week.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/20/merida/&#34;&gt;Merida cores trip&lt;/a&gt; goes great!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Visit Guadalajara for &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/29/carlos-wedding/&#34;&gt;Carlos&amp;rsquo; wedding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/05/houston-calling/&#34;&gt;Houston visit&lt;/a&gt; was riddled with travel issues. Fun nevertheless!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fun trip to &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/las-estacas/&#34;&gt;Las Estacas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s a wrap! &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/31/2024-year-end-note/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last mile closures</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/09/last-mile-closures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/09/last-mile-closures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of my free time over the last few days has been spent trying to implement the comments section on this site. Something that would have been super straightforward on a regular CMS is not quite so for a static site. Initially I tinkered with the idea of side-loading the comments feature over to the fediverse. It worked okay but it did feel quite choppy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking around a bit, I decided to give &lt;a href=&#34;https://isso-comments.de/&#34;&gt;ISSO&lt;/a&gt; a chance. It seemed to have all the features I was looking for and was reasonably easy to setup. As with most things tech though, I had quite some difficulty tweaking it to work the way I wanted it to. Taking a break and getting back to it after a few days, did get me to approach this from a different perspective and I think it&amp;rsquo;s super close to where I&amp;rsquo;d like it to be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On certain things, I am perfectly okay leaving things half baked and cutting my losses. On most things though, I do like seeing things to closure. There&amp;rsquo;s so much thrill in figuring out why something is not working the way it is supposed to. Most often it&amp;rsquo;s because of something ridiculously silly or because of minor oversights. Trials and tribulations of the last mile closures, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For now, this site has a basic commenting system and that gives me enough momentum to pursue other things to tweak. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/09/last-mile-closures/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arista de Humboldt</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/24/arista-de-humboldt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/24/arista-de-humboldt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I sent out a poll to the ESC group to gauge interest in a group hike at Nevado de Toluca. There was reasonable interest and we slotted this to be a family hike on the 24th. The Padilla&amp;rsquo;s and Johnston&amp;rsquo;s had to drop off last minute. It was just going to be Hadley and the Arturo&amp;rsquo;s now with the three of us. We reached the Shuttle point around 1015, hopped in a shuttle and got to the trail-head around 1100. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to hop off the shuttle - the gasoline stench coupled with the super dusty windy roads was more than churning my tummy. S did terrific with no complaints!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This time around we had to pay 65 pesos/person to enter the park. Very nominal and I guess it might be to control the crowd. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen Nevado de Toluca this busy! We trot up from the campamento towards Arista de Humboldt. I compromise with S before-hand that I&amp;rsquo;d carry her on sections when I can. Boy, she is getting heavy - &lt;em&gt;big and strong&lt;/em&gt; as M would like me to phrase it. We reach the viewpoint in no time.  This place is so freaking beautiful. Even with the almost ten fold crowd than usual.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;AristaDeHumboldt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Houss is definitely feeling the altitude ~14,060 ft. M is slowly warming up and S wants to head back to the trailhead. We decide to split the group here. The girls head over to scale one of the shorter hills on the right while the three of us head up the steepish peak on the left. In about twenty five minutes we reach to the top of this knoll and decide to turn around. At about 14,550 ft. oddly, it was way warmer than the lower elevations. A quick trot down to the rim and we decide to head back to the trail-head. The shuttle back from the trail-head is in a beaten Chevy pickup truck. We&amp;rsquo;re smothered with loads of fine dust as it zooms down the hill. S takes a mini-nap and wakes up just as we reach the car parking spot. A quick hour and a half and we&amp;rsquo;re home for a slow Sunday catch-up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bacalar</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/18/bacalar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/18/bacalar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;BacalarLagoon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cenote Negro&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bacalar has been on our travel list for quite sometime now. Between work travel, syncing our individual schedules and just getting around to actually booking the trip; we finally get around visiting this beautiful place this weekend in November.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we get off the plane, we&amp;rsquo;re immediately hit by a waft of the Yucatán humidity, soon followed by thick droplets of rain. Strikes me just then that we&amp;rsquo;re also right in the midst of the hurricane season. A quick lookup on the weather forecast reveals Hurricane Sara would be swinging past us and into the Gulf of Mexico in a bit. I slap myself on my wrist for not doing any research beforehand but also shrug this &lt;em&gt;minor&lt;/em&gt; oversight very quickly. How bad could it actually be? Maybe some showers here and there? We walk outside the Chetumal airport for about 500m and take a taxi from the main road to Bacalar. Oscar offers to take us there for 550 pesos. This was about 50 pesos shy of the amount the tour planner had quoted. M immediately accepts and we&amp;rsquo;re on our way. First impressions of this place immediately remind me of Trivandrum - lush green vistas with coconut trees strewn all around, narrow roads and barely any traffic. There&amp;rsquo;s construction for Tren Maya happening along the route but it barely impacts our drive. In about 50 minutes we reach the hotel and check-in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S immediately comments on the smell of wood as we enter our room. She&amp;rsquo;s ambivalent of the smell but seems to love the room setup. She goes around exploring the windows and shower. Once we get settled in, we head out to explore the property a bit. Hotel Carolina looks good with the woodsy feel and being right on the lagoon - but it definitely feels more commercial than I had imagined it to be. Yet another slap on the wrist. Note to self not to go by just pictures next time around. Maybe this trip planner thing is not quite working for us? This is the first time in all these years we&amp;rsquo;re using one - An embassy colleague&amp;rsquo;s wife runs a dive business and plans trips for folks across central America. We thought we&amp;rsquo;d give her a shot for this trip. Anyways, the stomach rumbles and we head over to Mango y Chile - a quaint vegan restaurant right by &lt;em&gt;Fuerte de San Filipe&lt;/em&gt; about 30 minutes walk from the hotel. The burgers and smoothies here are super delicious and we finish it off with some paletas. M&amp;rsquo;s restaurant picks barely go wrong! Back to the room and we settle down for the night.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around 0730 we stir awake and quickly get ready for the day. Plan is to head over to the fort to meet out boat captain who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to take us for a two hour ride in the lagoon. M messages the tour operator to check if the plan is still on since it&amp;rsquo;s super gloomy and heavy outside. She confirms and we head over to the fort. Just as we get to the fort, the skies let loose and the Boat captain gives us news that the police have closed the port for the day. We&amp;rsquo;re obviously disappointed and decide to grab a quick bite closer to the hotel. I offer to carry S on my shoulders as we make our way back in the pouring rain. The roads are flooded and the rain isn&amp;rsquo;t showing any signs of letting go. Love this walk back and it&amp;rsquo;s been quite sometime that we&amp;rsquo;ve actually done this! Some good breakfast at Noru&amp;rsquo;s and we make our way back to the hotel. M suggests we should probably consider getting back to CDMX that afternoon. Unfortunately, there are no tickets available on the flight. With that decision made for us, we decide to head back out for lunch at &lt;em&gt;Enamora&lt;/em&gt;. Food here&amp;rsquo;s okay. As we make our way back to the hotel, the weather clears up a bit. S wanted to head to the kids pool and we nudge her to try out the swing in the water. &lt;em&gt;Sara&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; effect lingers and the water is super choppy. We try getting the kayak out for a bit but aren&amp;rsquo;t quite successful. Back to the room and we spend some good time in the portico by the hammock. After we&amp;rsquo;re back from dinner at &lt;em&gt;Noru&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt;, I nudge S to head back to the wooden pier by the lagoon. We spend some time here as the sun sets and S plays with the idea of getting the kayak out. She flips it over in an instant and wants me to get in the water instead. The water does seem way calmer and I hop in to explore the waters. This impromptu wade in was probably one of the highlight&amp;rsquo;s for the day. We head back to the room. S spends some more time on the hammock and quickly falls asleep. M and I tinker with the idea of taking the kayak out the next morning to explore the lagoon by ourselves. As I type this at 0326 on Monday, I&amp;rsquo;m actually super psyched about this plan. Hoping S is game doing this in a few hours!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;BacalarSwing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And she is! We quickly change over in the morning and take to the waters. The weather is just right - Dark clouds hanging above and rays of sunshine creeping down. The water is much calmer and we&amp;rsquo;re near Cenote Negro in no time. We wade in the waters for about an hour and steal a few more minutes by the swing. Around 1030 we finally checkout and head to the airport after a brief breakfast stop at &lt;em&gt;Ajal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While we didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get to explore the whole lagoon, I&amp;rsquo;m so glad we ended up staying for the extra day. Overall S thoroughly enjoyed the water and just lazing in the hammock. Lesson learnt though that we are best at planning our own trips and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to head to Baja California later this December!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
