<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Week-Notes on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/categories/week-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Week-Notes on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/images/favicon/apple-touch-icon.png</url>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/images/favicon/apple-touch-icon.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 21:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/categories/week-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Sep 2025 21:30</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/09/01/august-endings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/09/01/august-endings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just about winding down from the long weekend. Last week at work was super productive but also left me pretty drained by Friday. Working in a smaller shop comes with its perks but also brings in all the logistic hurdles. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing most of it is also got to do with us being in Africa. Travel logistics are a pain and the amount of admin overhead for getting actual stuff done is beyond bonkers. Decision memos, note-verbale&amp;rsquo;s, single entry visas, travel ticketing - always something that needs to be followed up on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Family back in the states decided to rent a cabin in the Catskills and get some downtime. With photos coming in all weekend, definitely missed being there. Last time we did this in &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/09/04/poconos-fam/&#34;&gt;2022&lt;/a&gt;, it was a 50 odd group and we had such a good time overall. One of those moments when you feel this is the &lt;em&gt;tax&lt;/em&gt; you end up paying for choosing this career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exited a couple family WA groups that I&amp;rsquo;d joined in June/July to manage the air-ambulance for mummyjaan. Getting people off this wretched network is such a pain. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to find a decent interim - use it where absolutely necessary and GTFO as soon as the work is done. Feels like I&amp;rsquo;m beating the same drum to a deaf audience but I will &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/01/16/lifting-the-veil/&#34;&gt;stand my ground&lt;/a&gt; on this shit. Currently I have the app installed in my &amp;lsquo;work profile&amp;rsquo; on my personal phone and turn it on only when really necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made some decent decisions on the financial front. With some liquidity, I think we now have a game-plan for some investments. Playing the long-game does seem to be making returns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took some time this weekend to upgrade my Trilium instance to the &amp;lsquo;Next&amp;rsquo; version. Upgrade was painless. Major kudos to the new bunch of folks maintaining this real neat notes software. I do need to update a bunch of my notes here. Always an ongoing process!
&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/09/01/august-endings/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just about winding down from the long weekend. Last week at work was super productive but also left me pretty drained by Friday. Working in a smaller shop comes with its perks but also brings in all the logistic hurdles. I&rsquo;m guessing most of it is also got to do with us being in Africa. Travel logistics are a pain and the amount of admin overhead for getting actual stuff done is beyond bonkers. Decision memos, note-verbale&rsquo;s, single entry visas, travel ticketing - always something that needs to be followed up on&hellip;</p>
<p>Family back in the states decided to rent a cabin in the Catskills and get some downtime. With photos coming in all weekend, definitely missed being there. Last time we did this in <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/09/04/poconos-fam/">2022</a>, it was a 50 odd group and we had such a good time overall. One of those moments when you feel this is the <em>tax</em> you end up paying for choosing this career.</p>
<p>Exited a couple family WA groups that I&rsquo;d joined in June/July to manage the air-ambulance for mummyjaan. Getting people off this wretched network is such a pain. I&rsquo;m trying to find a decent interim - use it where absolutely necessary and GTFO as soon as the work is done. Feels like I&rsquo;m beating the same drum to a deaf audience but I will <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/01/16/lifting-the-veil/">stand my ground</a> on this shit. Currently I have the app installed in my &lsquo;work profile&rsquo; on my personal phone and turn it on only when really necessary.</p>
<p>Made some decent decisions on the financial front. With some liquidity, I think we now have a game-plan for some investments. Playing the long-game does seem to be making returns.</p>
<p>Took some time this weekend to upgrade my Trilium instance to the &lsquo;Next&rsquo; version. Upgrade was painless. Major kudos to the new bunch of folks maintaining this real neat notes software. I do need to update a bunch of my notes here. Always an ongoing process!
<a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/09/01/august-endings/" style="text-decoration: none !important;">🔗</a>
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 Nov 2024 00:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/11/sixth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/11/sixth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;Sixth.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S celebrated her 6th today.  Unicorn themed - of course - and had her first and probably last ever Piñata. But for a mega meltdown initially she did great all through the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, we signed up for a Diwali party organized by the Indian Association in Mexico. Primarily on a whim and maybe for the food? The event was last evening and boy, it was a terrible disappointment! It started late as expected. And obnoxiously loud for no reason. Not quite sure if it was the acoustics at the venue or just the MC shouting into the mic.  Maybe both? I love some good rock and metal. I love some good loud music. But I guess not all loud is the same. Also, this day and age, who even does a looping slideshow of pictures of people organizing the event? Dinner was supposed to be served by 1900. Servers said they had orders to serve only at 2030. Maybe the organizers wanted the food to be served only after the main event? When we rechecked at 2030, they said it was pushed to 2130. Had enough of it and walked out.  People were still on the dance floor and there was a good turn out. I guess this kinda boisterous social mayhem is just not my jam?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We head out to a Japanese (?) restaurant in Polanco since Nimi&amp;rsquo;s, Mei Mei and Manaw were all closed for service. Sushi was &lt;em&gt;meh&lt;/em&gt;. S did great all through the evening though despite the loud music and the crowd. That &amp;lsquo;Sticker by number&amp;rsquo; book that she received as a gift from Maddy kept her fully occupied!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday morning here and S is off for school. She was mildly upset that I get to stay at home while she needs to go to school. Fair world logic, I guess. We drop her and get to spend a couple hours together watching &lt;em&gt;Spenser Confidential&lt;/em&gt;. Enjoyed it all the more because we recognized quite a few locations where the movie was shot. M&amp;rsquo;s got some brunch out with the ladies in a bit and then a couple more hours before I need to pick up S. Maybe I should tweak that 3D printer?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="Sixth.jpg" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>S celebrated her 6th today.  Unicorn themed - of course - and had her first and probably last ever Piñata. But for a mega meltdown initially she did great all through the event.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago, we signed up for a Diwali party organized by the Indian Association in Mexico. Primarily on a whim and maybe for the food? The event was last evening and boy, it was a terrible disappointment! It started late as expected. And obnoxiously loud for no reason. Not quite sure if it was the acoustics at the venue or just the MC shouting into the mic.  Maybe both? I love some good rock and metal. I love some good loud music. But I guess not all loud is the same. Also, this day and age, who even does a looping slideshow of pictures of people organizing the event? Dinner was supposed to be served by 1900. Servers said they had orders to serve only at 2030. Maybe the organizers wanted the food to be served only after the main event? When we rechecked at 2030, they said it was pushed to 2130. Had enough of it and walked out.  People were still on the dance floor and there was a good turn out. I guess this kinda boisterous social mayhem is just not my jam?</p>
<p>We head out to a Japanese (?) restaurant in Polanco since Nimi&rsquo;s, Mei Mei and Manaw were all closed for service. Sushi was <em>meh</em>. S did great all through the evening though despite the loud music and the crowd. That &lsquo;Sticker by number&rsquo; book that she received as a gift from Maddy kept her fully occupied!</p>
<p>Monday morning here and S is off for school. She was mildly upset that I get to stay at home while she needs to go to school. Fair world logic, I guess. We drop her and get to spend a couple hours together watching <em>Spenser Confidential</em>. Enjoyed it all the more because we recognized quite a few locations where the movie was shot. M&rsquo;s got some brunch out with the ladies in a bit and then a couple more hours before I need to pick up S. Maybe I should tweak that 3D printer?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 Dec 2023 00:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2023/12/24/dumbing-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2023/12/24/dumbing-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few things I&amp;rsquo;d really like to dumb down or sort out over the next few weeks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site&lt;/strong&gt;: This site runs on WordPress, has facets of the indieweb, has ActivityPub and a crude implementation of self engineered micropost interface. All cool but needs quite a trim to make the best use of all these features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware/Infra&lt;/strong&gt;: VPS, VPN, Odroid for reverse proxy, NCP, NUC, Moose, External hard disks&amp;hellip;Love the current implementation for the various utilities they serve. However, I see myself spending lesser and lesser time in front of the PC. Which is good? But which also means I need to find a better way to manage these in the little time I want to spend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPX&lt;/strong&gt;: Go on a hike or ride? Automatically log this on my site. Gotta have that super neat Stamen map. I did get really close to setting this up &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/02/09/garmin-plugin-2/&#34;&gt;sometime back&lt;/a&gt; but got left on the wayside. Also time to update my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/garmin-stats/&#34;&gt;Outdoors plugin&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firefly3&lt;/strong&gt;: Love this tool for finance tracking. Need to build that rule engine to automate some of those imports and reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snikket/Matrix/Slidge&lt;/strong&gt;: Need to get this sorted out to be part of those groups that still rely on WhatsApp. I setup a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/02/20/bridged/&#34;&gt;bridge&lt;/a&gt; sometime back but deleted it because I was rarely using it. More of a nice-to-have so may not quite get to this anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memories&lt;/strong&gt;: Selective photo sharing with family or friends. Send a link instead of sharing photos individually. Love the nextcloud setup so far. Would be neat if I can take this up a notch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music&lt;/strong&gt;: Kinda like my current Navidrome setup. Would like a bit more flexibility in terms of song or folder access though. Smarter playlists? Also multidevice sync? Music system?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes Sync&lt;/strong&gt;: Currently relying on Signal notes to self and Trilium send for bookmarks. Need to automate this for self sorting with tags in Trilium notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart sceen&lt;/strong&gt;: On demand and power efficient display for Calendars, Adana, Gallery, dashboard display, news updates etc. Thinking MagicMirror but a bit more optimized. Repurpose that RPi or Odroid once it&amp;rsquo;s all integrated into the NUC?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few things I&rsquo;d really like to dumb down or sort out over the next few weeks:</p>
<p><strong>Site</strong>: This site runs on WordPress, has facets of the indieweb, has ActivityPub and a crude implementation of self engineered micropost interface. All cool but needs quite a trim to make the best use of all these features.</p>
<p><strong>Hardware/Infra</strong>: VPS, VPN, Odroid for reverse proxy, NCP, NUC, Moose, External hard disks&hellip;Love the current implementation for the various utilities they serve. However, I see myself spending lesser and lesser time in front of the PC. Which is good? But which also means I need to find a better way to manage these in the little time I want to spend.</p>
<p><strong>GPX</strong>: Go on a hike or ride? Automatically log this on my site. Gotta have that super neat Stamen map. I did get really close to setting this up <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/02/09/garmin-plugin-2/">sometime back</a> but got left on the wayside. Also time to update my <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/garmin-stats/">Outdoors plugin</a>?</p>
<p><strong>Firefly3</strong>: Love this tool for finance tracking. Need to build that rule engine to automate some of those imports and reports.</p>
<p><strong>Snikket/Matrix/Slidge</strong>: Need to get this sorted out to be part of those groups that still rely on WhatsApp. I setup a <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/02/20/bridged/">bridge</a> sometime back but deleted it because I was rarely using it. More of a nice-to-have so may not quite get to this anytime soon.</p>
<p><strong>Memories</strong>: Selective photo sharing with family or friends. Send a link instead of sharing photos individually. Love the nextcloud setup so far. Would be neat if I can take this up a notch.</p>
<p><strong>Music</strong>: Kinda like my current Navidrome setup. Would like a bit more flexibility in terms of song or folder access though. Smarter playlists? Also multidevice sync? Music system?</p>
<p><strong>Notes Sync</strong>: Currently relying on Signal notes to self and Trilium send for bookmarks. Need to automate this for self sorting with tags in Trilium notes.</p>
<p><strong>Smart sceen</strong>: On demand and power efficient display for Calendars, Adana, Gallery, dashboard display, news updates etc. Thinking MagicMirror but a bit more optimized. Repurpose that RPi or Odroid once it&rsquo;s all integrated into the NUC?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Jul 2023 00:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2023/07/04/notas-de-mitad-de-a%C3%B1o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2023/07/04/notas-de-mitad-de-a%C3%B1o/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With quite a few things constantly evolving over the last several months, I haven&amp;rsquo;t actively paid much attention to this space. I&amp;rsquo;ve posted a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/micro/&#34;&gt;micro posts&lt;/a&gt; now and then, but nowhere close to chronicling things as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to. This is a quick run down of a few things occupying my mind space:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been about four months since we moved to Mexico City. We absolutely love it here. People are terrific, weather is just right, and this city&amp;rsquo;s got a dash of almost every city we&amp;rsquo;ve lived in so far! M&amp;amp;S have been able to explore the regular tourist spots thanks to the CLO trips. I&amp;rsquo;ve joined them for a few, but what I really enjoy is just experiencing the city for what it&amp;rsquo;s got to offer - And there&amp;rsquo;s no dearth to that. Absolutely blown away by the city planning and the presence of so many parks. The city is spectacularly clean for the number of people living here. Every Sunday one of the main avenues is closed out to vehicular traffic and opened out to runners, cyclists and essentially anybody who wants to enjoy the roads. Amazed at the resources that the local government is able to draw from to sustain this every single weekend! We haven&amp;rsquo;t been that lucky to find decent vegetarian food here. Most local restaurants offer some form of meat in almost all dishes and the vegetarian items are rarely tasty. Dining out definitely leaves a lot to be desired - unless of course you try out other cuisines. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s good food out there - yet to find it though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s exactly a year since I took on the current position. Best career move I&amp;rsquo;ve made so far, and I absolutely love every part of my job. There&amp;rsquo;s not one day that&amp;rsquo;s akin to another and I&amp;rsquo;m constantly learning every day. Most days just whizz by with constant troubleshooting on systems and processes. I&amp;rsquo;m barely at my desk for an hour a day. Tracing power and logic is so refreshing - The adrenaline rush that comes when you&amp;rsquo;ve found that nuanced fault in the system is addictive. The closest I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to this in the past was while writing code for enhancing functionality in one of my side projects. Ironic that it took me fifteen years to realize what I&amp;rsquo;m really good at - fixing things! And now I get paid to play with toys and travel the world. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to travel to Matamoros, Nuevo Laredo and Hermosillo so far. These cities are so different from CDMX and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I get a chance to experience these regions of the country too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been biking to work most days and doing the Reforma ride on the weekends. So good to be back on the saddle so regularly. Met a couple folks from a trail running group here last weekend and would love to join them whenever time permits. Over the next few months I would also like to visit the National parks around the city. Not having a car is kinda limiting but definitely not a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a family, we&amp;rsquo;ve really gotten into playing Zelda - Breath of the Wild. We each have our own profiles and are at different stages of the game. This is fascinating, engaging and such a good way to spend time together while indoors. S enjoys the challenges and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see how good she&amp;rsquo;s gotten at the game. Definitely getting the Tears of the Kingdom really soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been actively tinkering with my home-lab. Mostly doing the bare essentials to keep it updated and running. I&amp;rsquo;ve started using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.firefly-iii.org/&#34;&gt;FireFly III&lt;/a&gt; more actively to keep track of our expenses and for general budgeting. Since internet and power are decently reliable, I should probably move part of my home-lab over from MD to here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With quite a few things constantly evolving over the last several months, I haven&rsquo;t actively paid much attention to this space. I&rsquo;ve posted a few <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/micro/">micro posts</a> now and then, but nowhere close to chronicling things as much as I&rsquo;d like to. This is a quick run down of a few things occupying my mind space:</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s been about four months since we moved to Mexico City. We absolutely love it here. People are terrific, weather is just right, and this city&rsquo;s got a dash of almost every city we&rsquo;ve lived in so far! M&amp;S have been able to explore the regular tourist spots thanks to the CLO trips. I&rsquo;ve joined them for a few, but what I really enjoy is just experiencing the city for what it&rsquo;s got to offer - And there&rsquo;s no dearth to that. Absolutely blown away by the city planning and the presence of so many parks. The city is spectacularly clean for the number of people living here. Every Sunday one of the main avenues is closed out to vehicular traffic and opened out to runners, cyclists and essentially anybody who wants to enjoy the roads. Amazed at the resources that the local government is able to draw from to sustain this every single weekend! We haven&rsquo;t been that lucky to find decent vegetarian food here. Most local restaurants offer some form of meat in almost all dishes and the vegetarian items are rarely tasty. Dining out definitely leaves a lot to be desired - unless of course you try out other cuisines. I&rsquo;m sure there&rsquo;s good food out there - yet to find it though.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s exactly a year since I took on the current position. Best career move I&rsquo;ve made so far, and I absolutely love every part of my job. There&rsquo;s not one day that&rsquo;s akin to another and I&rsquo;m constantly learning every day. Most days just whizz by with constant troubleshooting on systems and processes. I&rsquo;m barely at my desk for an hour a day. Tracing power and logic is so refreshing - The adrenaline rush that comes when you&rsquo;ve found that nuanced fault in the system is addictive. The closest I&rsquo;ve gotten to this in the past was while writing code for enhancing functionality in one of my side projects. Ironic that it took me fifteen years to realize what I&rsquo;m really good at - fixing things! And now I get paid to play with toys and travel the world. I&rsquo;ve had a chance to travel to Matamoros, Nuevo Laredo and Hermosillo so far. These cities are so different from CDMX and I&rsquo;m glad I get a chance to experience these regions of the country too.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been biking to work most days and doing the Reforma ride on the weekends. So good to be back on the saddle so regularly. Met a couple folks from a trail running group here last weekend and would love to join them whenever time permits. Over the next few months I would also like to visit the National parks around the city. Not having a car is kinda limiting but definitely not a big deal.</p>
<p>As a family, we&rsquo;ve really gotten into playing Zelda - Breath of the Wild. We each have our own profiles and are at different stages of the game. This is fascinating, engaging and such a good way to spend time together while indoors. S enjoys the challenges and it&rsquo;s amazing to see how good she&rsquo;s gotten at the game. Definitely getting the Tears of the Kingdom really soon!</p>
<p>I haven&rsquo;t been actively tinkering with my home-lab. Mostly doing the bare essentials to keep it updated and running. I&rsquo;ve started using <a href="https://www.firefly-iii.org/">FireFly III</a> more actively to keep track of our expenses and for general budgeting. Since internet and power are decently reliable, I should probably move part of my home-lab over from MD to here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Jun 2020 00:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/06/weeknote-23-breath-and-infento/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/06/weeknote-23-breath-and-infento/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few things that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://distanceathletics.com/trainer/david-bidler/&#34;&gt;David&lt;/a&gt; offered us a complementary sign-in to his &lt;a href=&#34;https://breathetoperform.mykajabi.com/catchyourbreath&#34;&gt;Breathing Workshop&lt;/a&gt;. Excited to get that rolling! He&amp;rsquo;s also released his first book - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebreathetoperformprogram.com/&#34;&gt;Breathe to Perform&lt;/a&gt;. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to get our hands on it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been strongly considering moving over from WordPress to a static site generator. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using WordPress for 15 or so years now and have had absolutely no issues. The minimalism factor of static site generators makes it quite appealing though and then there&amp;rsquo;s that constant nudge to try something new. Will have to weight that against the migration work involved and take a call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently bought a 2TB Seagate drive and connected it to my &amp;lsquo;Mothership&amp;rsquo; laptop. I split it into two partitions - one acts as the secondary backup of the files I save on my RPi+WD1TB drive and the other for files I do not necessarily need on NC. While at it, I also setup an rsync pull from my Hetzner Cloud server to backup my docker volumes. Keeping the backups manual for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text-plain&#34; data-lang=&#34;text-plain&#34;&gt;sudo rsync -nchavzP --delete --stats user@xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx:/path/to/docker/volumes/ 
&amp;#34;/media/Drive/partition2/Hetzner Backup/&amp;#34;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quite a few interesting developments since I sent in a blurb to the TFI alumni group. I&amp;rsquo;ve expanded my &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/services/&#34;&gt;services&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; a bit more now and I see it as a way of contributing to the educational ecosystem back in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meena suggested I build a bike for Shasta. I was initially looking at building a no-nonsense mobile platform - just a plank on three wheels and a pedal. While looking at options though, I chanced upon Infento. Looked very promising and loved the modular aspect of it. So we went ahead and ordered the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infento.com/product/explorer-kit/&#34;&gt;Infento Explorer kit&lt;/a&gt;. Should be delivered sometime today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US is going through some real dark times now. We&amp;rsquo;ve not even come out of the pandemic (which we grossly mismanaged). It feels like we&amp;rsquo;re back to square one and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be like this! What is it that drives humans to these abysmal depths?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Currently Reading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve finally gotten back to reading books! With so many things on the to-do list, reading in the past did take a back-seat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The adventurer&amp;rsquo;s son - A memoir by Dial and Roman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Wedge by Scott Carney&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Art of Invisibility by Kevin Mitnick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LikeWar – The Weaponization of Social Media by Emerson T. Brooking, P.W. Singer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Art of Thinking Clearly by Rolf Dobelli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Here to Kill Everybody by Bruce Schneier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting podcasts this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started listening to &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/book-review/the-wedge/&#34;&gt;Passenger List&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;. Atlantic Flight 702&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/dovetail.prxu.org/232/2005da8d-34e6-4b1b-bb0b-d9f34a6e8f77/PL&#34;&gt;https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/dovetail.prxu.org/232/2005da8d-34e6-4b1b-bb0b-d9f34a6e8f77/PL&lt;/a&gt;_PREVIEW_V1_COMING_SEP_JOHN_NEW_VERSION_PREMIERES_SUBSCRIBE_NOW_1_.mp3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec5a10cab73c1.22768810&#34;&gt;US investment in Next-gen nuclear power&lt;/a&gt;: From most perspectives, this makes sense. Would be interesting to see the developments as other countries catch-up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec5a7ceb47e30.28806443&#34;&gt;Yoga with Adriene&lt;/a&gt;: This one&amp;rsquo;s mostly for Meena!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ece30eca48b19.17551407&#34;&gt;Does Birth order affect personality&lt;/a&gt;: As a fourth in the birth order, I did find this quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pelorus_Jack&#34;&gt;Pelorus Jack&lt;/a&gt;: The dolphin that guided ships across the French canal. Also the first individual sea creature protected by law in any country!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>A glimpse of the past week and the few things that captivated my attention:</em></p>
<p><a href="https://distanceathletics.com/trainer/david-bidler/">David</a> offered us a complementary sign-in to his <a href="https://breathetoperform.mykajabi.com/catchyourbreath">Breathing Workshop</a>. Excited to get that rolling! He&rsquo;s also released his first book - <a href="https://www.thebreathetoperformprogram.com/">Breathe to Perform</a>. Can&rsquo;t wait to get our hands on it!</p>
<p>Over the last week, I&rsquo;ve been strongly considering moving over from WordPress to a static site generator. I&rsquo;ve been using WordPress for 15 or so years now and have had absolutely no issues. The minimalism factor of static site generators makes it quite appealing though and then there&rsquo;s that constant nudge to try something new. Will have to weight that against the migration work involved and take a call.</p>
<p>I recently bought a 2TB Seagate drive and connected it to my &lsquo;Mothership&rsquo; laptop. I split it into two partitions - one acts as the secondary backup of the files I save on my RPi+WD1TB drive and the other for files I do not necessarily need on NC. While at it, I also setup an rsync pull from my Hetzner Cloud server to backup my docker volumes. Keeping the backups manual for now.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code class="language-text-plain" data-lang="text-plain">sudo rsync -nchavzP --delete --stats user@xxx.xxx.xxx.xxx:/path/to/docker/volumes/ 
&#34;/media/Drive/partition2/Hetzner Backup/&#34;
</code></pre><p>Quite a few interesting developments since I sent in a blurb to the TFI alumni group. I&rsquo;ve expanded my &lsquo;<a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/services/">services</a>&rsquo; a bit more now and I see it as a way of contributing to the educational ecosystem back in India.</p>
<p>Meena suggested I build a bike for Shasta. I was initially looking at building a no-nonsense mobile platform - just a plank on three wheels and a pedal. While looking at options though, I chanced upon Infento. Looked very promising and loved the modular aspect of it. So we went ahead and ordered the <a href="https://www.infento.com/product/explorer-kit/">Infento Explorer kit</a>. Should be delivered sometime today!</p>
<p>The US is going through some real dark times now. We&rsquo;ve not even come out of the pandemic (which we grossly mismanaged). It feels like we&rsquo;re back to square one and it doesn&rsquo;t have to be like this! What is it that drives humans to these abysmal depths?</p>
<p><strong>Currently Reading</strong></p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve finally gotten back to reading books! With so many things on the to-do list, reading in the past did take a back-seat.</p>
<ul>
<li>The adventurer&rsquo;s son - A memoir by Dial and Roman</li>
<li>The Wedge by Scott Carney</li>
<li>The Art of Invisibility by Kevin Mitnick</li>
<li>LikeWar – The Weaponization of Social Media by Emerson T. Brooking, P.W. Singer</li>
<li>The Art of Thinking Clearly by Rolf Dobelli</li>
<li>Click Here to Kill Everybody by Bruce Schneier</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Interesting podcasts this week:</strong></p>
<p>Started listening to &lsquo;<a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/book-review/the-wedge/">Passenger List</a>&rsquo;. Atlantic Flight 702</p>
<p><a href="https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/dovetail.prxu.org/232/2005da8d-34e6-4b1b-bb0b-d9f34a6e8f77/PL">https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/dovetail.prxu.org/232/2005da8d-34e6-4b1b-bb0b-d9f34a6e8f77/PL</a>_PREVIEW_V1_COMING_SEP_JOHN_NEW_VERSION_PREMIERES_SUBSCRIBE_NOW_1_.mp3</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Interesting reads this week:</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec5a10cab73c1.22768810">US investment in Next-gen nuclear power</a>: From most perspectives, this makes sense. Would be interesting to see the developments as other countries catch-up!</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec5a7ceb47e30.28806443">Yoga with Adriene</a>: This one&rsquo;s mostly for Meena!</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ece30eca48b19.17551407">Does Birth order affect personality</a>: As a fourth in the birth order, I did find this quite interesting.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pelorus_Jack">Pelorus Jack</a>: The dolphin that guided ships across the French canal. Also the first individual sea creature protected by law in any country!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17 May 2020 00:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/weeknote-20-trails-and-switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/weeknote-20-trails-and-switches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few things that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the kids at home, weather mostly good and the lock-down lifted we did venture out a bit and got a lot of hikes in this week. We obviously had all masks on and avoided crowded spaces. Also had this sudden realization that most of the hikes I was doing over the past few years in Baltimore were on the banks of the Patapsco river. Would be wonderful to plan a good long 15-20 miler one of these days. Should be a good recce for the half-marathon that I said I would organize for Meena, Nancy and Sharath next month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonderful talk with Atchuth last night on servers and hosting content! On my end, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/switched/&#34;&gt;installed a small switch&lt;/a&gt; for my devices. Also ordered a 2TB external drive since the laptop that I backup my files on is slowly reaching full capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took appa out for a drive yesterday. His first outing in over three months now. I think it&amp;rsquo;s reasonably safe for him to head outdoors now. I do really want to take him to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/number-nine-trolley-trail-hike/&#34;&gt;Number nine trolley hike&lt;/a&gt; we did today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely loving the share article feature on Wallabag (And also Selfoss). It helps me share articles with family and friends without the annoying ads while providing a link to the source. I totally understand that certain publishers need ads to produce quality journalism. What I am not comfortable with is, them using that to track me. In the links that I share below, most are linked to &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;my wallabag instance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s public share. If I refer to an individual&amp;rsquo;s blog post however, I&amp;rsquo;ll link directly to the source. The only downside to that is, people tend to move across CMS or blogging software and links get orphaned&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting tools this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://e.foundation/&#34;&gt;The /e/ Foundation&lt;/a&gt;: My next phone is most likely going to be running this OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/optimizing-images/&#34;&gt;Jpegoptim&lt;/a&gt;: Linux tools to compress images on a whim&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting podcasts this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/radiolab/articles/octomom&#34;&gt;Octomom&lt;/a&gt;: The octopus species that broods its eggs for close to five years!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec1a002090d83.01810323&#34;&gt;What does your gaze reveal about you?&lt;/a&gt;: A ridiculous whole lot! Will have to get back to this later to explore more of the links. The amount of information that can be gleaned and analyzed is pretty intriguing. The age-old saying goes - &amp;lsquo;Eyes are the windows to a person&amp;rsquo;s soul&amp;rsquo;. Looks like we humans took a good note of that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5e9ecf5523a767.92611391&#34;&gt;Go squat!&lt;/a&gt;: Something that&amp;rsquo;s so common-place in India (And several other countries)&amp;hellip;It&amp;rsquo;s like coming back a full circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec06776757543.21835439&#34;&gt;Would you want your tax dollars to be invested in Public-Private partnerships?&lt;/a&gt;: When it comes to a choice between investing in humans and investing in technology, I&amp;rsquo;d rather invest in humans. I understand why it&amp;rsquo;s a hard sell though…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec1a3d17320a4.24739015&#34;&gt;Converting type A blood to type O&lt;/a&gt;: Applications for this are huge! Imagine not having to wait to find donors for a specific blood type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec0702437ae34.22105740&#34;&gt;Swiper, no swiping&lt;/a&gt;! Privacy.com relies on plaid, which was bought by Visa recently…The good old days of relying on cash ought to be back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>A glimpse of the past week and the few things that captivated my attention:</em></p>
<p>With the kids at home, weather mostly good and the lock-down lifted we did venture out a bit and got a lot of hikes in this week. We obviously had all masks on and avoided crowded spaces. Also had this sudden realization that most of the hikes I was doing over the past few years in Baltimore were on the banks of the Patapsco river. Would be wonderful to plan a good long 15-20 miler one of these days. Should be a good recce for the half-marathon that I said I would organize for Meena, Nancy and Sharath next month!</p>
<p>Wonderful talk with Atchuth last night on servers and hosting content! On my end, I <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/switched/">installed a small switch</a> for my devices. Also ordered a 2TB external drive since the laptop that I backup my files on is slowly reaching full capacity.</p>
<p>Took appa out for a drive yesterday. His first outing in over three months now. I think it&rsquo;s reasonably safe for him to head outdoors now. I do really want to take him to the <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/number-nine-trolley-trail-hike/">Number nine trolley hike</a> we did today.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m absolutely loving the share article feature on Wallabag (And also Selfoss). It helps me share articles with family and friends without the annoying ads while providing a link to the source. I totally understand that certain publishers need ads to produce quality journalism. What I am not comfortable with is, them using that to track me. In the links that I share below, most are linked to <a href="https://bag.srkn.org/">my wallabag instance</a>&rsquo;s public share. If I refer to an individual&rsquo;s blog post however, I&rsquo;ll link directly to the source. The only downside to that is, people tend to move across CMS or blogging software and links get orphaned&hellip;</p>
<p><strong>Interesting tools this week:</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://e.foundation/">The /e/ Foundation</a>: My next phone is most likely going to be running this OS.</p>
<p><a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/optimizing-images/">Jpegoptim</a>: Linux tools to compress images on a whim</p>
<p><strong>Interesting podcasts this week:</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/radiolab/articles/octomom">Octomom</a>: The octopus species that broods its eggs for close to five years!</p>
<p><strong>Interesting reads this week:</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec1a002090d83.01810323">What does your gaze reveal about you?</a>: A ridiculous whole lot! Will have to get back to this later to explore more of the links. The amount of information that can be gleaned and analyzed is pretty intriguing. The age-old saying goes - &lsquo;Eyes are the windows to a person&rsquo;s soul&rsquo;. Looks like we humans took a good note of that!</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5e9ecf5523a767.92611391">Go squat!</a>: Something that&rsquo;s so common-place in India (And several other countries)&hellip;It&rsquo;s like coming back a full circle.</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec06776757543.21835439">Would you want your tax dollars to be invested in Public-Private partnerships?</a>: When it comes to a choice between investing in humans and investing in technology, I&rsquo;d rather invest in humans. I understand why it&rsquo;s a hard sell though…</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec1a3d17320a4.24739015">Converting type A blood to type O</a>: Applications for this are huge! Imagine not having to wait to find donors for a specific blood type.</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec0702437ae34.22105740">Swiper, no swiping</a>! Privacy.com relies on plaid, which was bought by Visa recently…The good old days of relying on cash ought to be back.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 May 2020 00:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/10/weeknote-19-feeds-and-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/10/weeknote-19-feeds-and-sessions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few things that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weather&amp;rsquo;s been pretty erratic this week. We also had a mild dusting yesterday out of the blue! Might consider heading out for a hike later today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I nudged Meena to write more. We&amp;rsquo;ve had some interesting discussions on Yoga and other things over the past week and I do think she has a ton to share! She&amp;rsquo;s also planning to train for a 50miler which I am super excited about! Oh and beyond all that marketing ploy, Happy Mothers&amp;rsquo; day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shasta&amp;rsquo;s talking a lot more now. Pretty sure her verbal diarrhea is soon going to start soon too!  The other day, while sitting with Appa she said something to the effect of &amp;lsquo;i-pae&amp;rsquo; pointing to the ipad. Grandfather and daughter are totally connecting on these gadgets!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git: I agree on many levels with &lt;a href=&#34;https://kevq.uk/confession-i-have-no-idea-how-to-use-git/&#34;&gt;what Kev posted recently&lt;/a&gt; about Github. I enjoy working on and deploying software tools. What I do not enjoy is the whole git pull, push, fork thing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sessions: I am running a session later this week for the Khat-pat folks on self hosting. Planning to keep it mostly hands-on and crisp. The idea is to get them started on taking better control of their presence on the interwebs! I&amp;rsquo;d also love to join the Indieweb folks one of these days. They have &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.indieweb.org/2020/05/online-indieweb-meetup-nyc-vkY32vBfCTEJ&#34;&gt;one coming up on the 20th&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools: Earlier this week, I came across e-mail cloaking services - &lt;a href=&#34;https://simplelogin.io/&#34;&gt;Simplelogin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://anonaddy.com/&#34;&gt;Anondaddy&lt;/a&gt;. Love the idea and I might give them a shot the next time I subscribe or sign-up for a service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feed Readers: Over the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve used multiple feed readers - Netvibes, TheOldReader, FreshRSS and Fever. They were all good in specific aspects but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really find them to be that one tool which I could use to consume the inter-webs my way. Earlier this week I decided to self-host one and narrowed down to FreshRSS, miniflux and selfoss. After a few iterations of deploying and testing, I stuck with &lt;a href=&#34;https://selfoss.aditu.de/&#34;&gt;selfoss&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s super light-weight and has all the specific features I was looking for.  To deploy it on docker, I used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/28/deploying-known-on-a-docker-stack/&#34;&gt;boiler-plate template that I created earlier&lt;/a&gt; when setting up my &lt;a href=&#34;https://known.srkn.org&#34;&gt;known&lt;/a&gt; instance.  The gist file for the docker-compose is &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/bf31682e6d9805ac29d6e4ff02bacb28&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The install should take you at most 10 minutes assuming you have the base framework setup. What I do love about selfoss is the ability to push articles over to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;wallabag&lt;/a&gt; instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trilium: I&amp;rsquo;ve moved most of my notes over to Trilium and I am absolutely loving it! While it&amp;rsquo;s hierarchical, it is also setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium/wiki/Patterns-of-personal-knowledge-base&#34;&gt;not to be one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb322c0461ff3.59682906&#34;&gt;Time-restricted eating&lt;/a&gt;: Philip &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philipbrewer.net/2020/05/03/experiments-with-time-restricted-eating/&#34;&gt;referenced this article recently&lt;/a&gt; and I think it&amp;rsquo;s brilliant! Also went ahead and signed up for Rhonda&amp;rsquo;s podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb705c2235124.51234929&#34;&gt;Tracking using ultrasound frequencies&lt;/a&gt;: Whoa! This totally blew my mind! If google uses it to connect your devices with chrome cast, what&amp;rsquo;s really stopping them from using it to track what you are watching? And now how do you block that invasion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb6f8cbd8a783.67620597&#34;&gt;Workplaces in the era&lt;/a&gt;: Firms will have additional pressure from (or will be incentivised by) their insurance companies to have monitoring in place. Over the span of few months, this will be the new normal. Looking back, haven&amp;rsquo;t we all got used to keying-in and out at our workplaces?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb700e76826f2.47966883&#34;&gt;We kill people based on metadata&lt;/a&gt;: Quite a lot is changed since 2014. What hasn&amp;rsquo;t though is how fragmented and withdrawn several government and private entities are even in times of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb7034fba3519.79379071&#34;&gt;The mystic veil of End-to-End encryption&lt;/a&gt;: Interesting read on the data sharing between these apps.  The other day I was wondering how &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bark.us/&#34;&gt;Bark&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s able to access messages from these apps. Likely they have something on these lines drifting underneath? While I love the concept of the app and the benefits it provides, I did cringe and walk away because I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how they&amp;rsquo;d be handling the data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>A glimpse of the past week and the few things that captivated my attention:</em></p>
<p>Weather&rsquo;s been pretty erratic this week. We also had a mild dusting yesterday out of the blue! Might consider heading out for a hike later today.</p>
<p>I nudged Meena to write more. We&rsquo;ve had some interesting discussions on Yoga and other things over the past week and I do think she has a ton to share! She&rsquo;s also planning to train for a 50miler which I am super excited about! Oh and beyond all that marketing ploy, Happy Mothers&rsquo; day.</p>
<p>Shasta&rsquo;s talking a lot more now. Pretty sure her verbal diarrhea is soon going to start soon too!  The other day, while sitting with Appa she said something to the effect of &lsquo;i-pae&rsquo; pointing to the ipad. Grandfather and daughter are totally connecting on these gadgets!</p>
<p>Git: I agree on many levels with <a href="https://kevq.uk/confession-i-have-no-idea-how-to-use-git/">what Kev posted recently</a> about Github. I enjoy working on and deploying software tools. What I do not enjoy is the whole git pull, push, fork thing!</p>
<p>Sessions: I am running a session later this week for the Khat-pat folks on self hosting. Planning to keep it mostly hands-on and crisp. The idea is to get them started on taking better control of their presence on the interwebs! I&rsquo;d also love to join the Indieweb folks one of these days. They have <a href="https://events.indieweb.org/2020/05/online-indieweb-meetup-nyc-vkY32vBfCTEJ">one coming up on the 20th</a>!</p>
<p>Tools: Earlier this week, I came across e-mail cloaking services - <a href="https://simplelogin.io/">Simplelogin</a> and <a href="https://anonaddy.com/">Anondaddy</a>. Love the idea and I might give them a shot the next time I subscribe or sign-up for a service.</p>
<p>Feed Readers: Over the past few years, I&rsquo;ve used multiple feed readers - Netvibes, TheOldReader, FreshRSS and Fever. They were all good in specific aspects but I didn&rsquo;t really find them to be that one tool which I could use to consume the inter-webs my way. Earlier this week I decided to self-host one and narrowed down to FreshRSS, miniflux and selfoss. After a few iterations of deploying and testing, I stuck with <a href="https://selfoss.aditu.de/">selfoss</a>. It&rsquo;s super light-weight and has all the specific features I was looking for.  To deploy it on docker, I used the <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/28/deploying-known-on-a-docker-stack/">boiler-plate template that I created earlier</a> when setting up my <a href="https://known.srkn.org">known</a> instance.  The gist file for the docker-compose is <a href="https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/bf31682e6d9805ac29d6e4ff02bacb28">here</a>. The install should take you at most 10 minutes assuming you have the base framework setup. What I do love about selfoss is the ability to push articles over to my <a href="https://bag.srkn.org/">wallabag</a> instance.</p>
<p>Trilium: I&rsquo;ve moved most of my notes over to Trilium and I am absolutely loving it! While it&rsquo;s hierarchical, it is also setup <a href="https://github.com/zadam/trilium/wiki/Patterns-of-personal-knowledge-base">not to be one</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Interesting reads this week:</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb322c0461ff3.59682906">Time-restricted eating</a>: Philip <a href="https://www.philipbrewer.net/2020/05/03/experiments-with-time-restricted-eating/">referenced this article recently</a> and I think it&rsquo;s brilliant! Also went ahead and signed up for Rhonda&rsquo;s podcast.</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb705c2235124.51234929">Tracking using ultrasound frequencies</a>: Whoa! This totally blew my mind! If google uses it to connect your devices with chrome cast, what&rsquo;s really stopping them from using it to track what you are watching? And now how do you block that invasion?</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb6f8cbd8a783.67620597">Workplaces in the era</a>: Firms will have additional pressure from (or will be incentivised by) their insurance companies to have monitoring in place. Over the span of few months, this will be the new normal. Looking back, haven&rsquo;t we all got used to keying-in and out at our workplaces?</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb700e76826f2.47966883">We kill people based on metadata</a>: Quite a lot is changed since 2014. What hasn&rsquo;t though is how fragmented and withdrawn several government and private entities are even in times of crisis.</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb7034fba3519.79379071">The mystic veil of End-to-End encryption</a>: Interesting read on the data sharing between these apps.  The other day I was wondering how <a href="https://www.bark.us/">Bark</a>&rsquo;s able to access messages from these apps. Likely they have something on these lines drifting underneath? While I love the concept of the app and the benefits it provides, I did cringe and walk away because I just wasn&rsquo;t sure how they&rsquo;d be handling the data.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 Apr 2020 00:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/24/weeknote-17-covid19-webmentions-and-migrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/24/weeknote-17-covid19-webmentions-and-migrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few articles, podcasts, tools, videos and music that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I got a better handle at deploying and maintaining docker images. With that squared out, I decided to decommission the Digital Ocean servers that I had setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/03/02/migrations-workflows/&#34;&gt;back in 2017&lt;/a&gt; and migrate the applications over to my Hetzner server. I no longer have to rely on ServerPilot. All my applications are now deployed as docker containers fronted by #Traefik as a reverse proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jitsi server instance I &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/19/self-hosting-jitsi-video-conferencing/&#34;&gt;deployed last week&lt;/a&gt; has been serving pretty well so far! I tweaked it further to enable &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.radiumz.org/en/article/local-recording-jitsi-meet&#34;&gt;local recording&lt;/a&gt;. Meena has been using it to run her online Yoga sessions and she can now also use it to record the podcast that she soon plans to start! Session recording and live-streaming is something I still need to configure in my current setup. The logs indicate it&amp;rsquo;s failing on the Jibri handshake and that&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ll need to figure out once I have a bit more time in hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other actionable tasks on the tech front include figuring out a swift way to deploy PHP based applications on Docker. I still need to port over my Known and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixel.srkn.org/sriperinkulam&#34;&gt;PixelFed&lt;/a&gt; applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.philipbrewer.net/&#34;&gt;Philip&lt;/a&gt; nudged me to look into my webmentions. The theme I previously had wasn&amp;rsquo;t displaying them as comments. I needed a bit of a &amp;lsquo;creativity boost&amp;rsquo; and decided to use a new theme. Really liked the McLuhan theme by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.andersnoren.se/teman/mcluhan-wordpress-theme/&#34;&gt;Anders Noren&lt;/a&gt; and decided to give it a spin. Noticed &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/support/topic/mcluhan-comments-fetched-are-from-a-different-post/#new-topic-0&#34;&gt;a minor issue with the comments section&lt;/a&gt; and was easily able to fix it. I do however want to make a few tweaks to it, which I hopefully will get around attending to over the next few weeks. I also have my eye on &lt;a href=&#34;https://prtksxna.com/&#34;&gt;Prateek&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/themes/zuari/&#34;&gt;Zuari theme&lt;/a&gt; which is deeply &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/&#34;&gt;indieweb&lt;/a&gt; compliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last evening, &lt;a href=&#34;https://atchuth.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Atchuth&lt;/a&gt; mentioned he&amp;rsquo;s now using his RPi4 as a full fledged desktop machine. He&amp;rsquo;s moved over from DietPi to the Raspbian OS. Makes sense given his current use-case. Sharath on the other hand is still using his RPi 4 predominantly as a Nextcloud server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week has been great in terms of re-connecting with some good old friends! We&amp;rsquo;re planning a re-union sometime next year. 20 year since we finished school! Phew!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Khat-pat makers group that I am part of is now getting more traction and it&amp;rsquo;s awesome just hearing out the cool things that other folks are doing. This week&amp;rsquo;s session was on building drones from scratch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got around connecting with the kids I taught 10 years ago! They&amp;rsquo;ve all moved on to college and are into various things now. One kid wanted to become a stellar teacher and this  is one of the best messages I&amp;rsquo;ve received so far!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night we played a few good rounds of Pictionary/Dumb-charades with the kids. Shasta had a terrific time just watching the &amp;lsquo;adults&amp;rsquo; in their elements. You never get too old for this game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting podcasts this week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picturing Data: Monocle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://monocle.com/extensions/monocle/bin/mp3&#34;&gt;https://monocle.com/extensions/monocle/bin/mp3&lt;/a&gt;_downloader.php?file=https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/788260468/download/&amp;amp;filename=monocle_on_design_442.mp3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting tools this week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://termux.com/&#34;&gt;Termux app&lt;/a&gt; has been an amazing value-add to my phone for those quick server check-in&amp;rsquo;s!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outline.com/agNcAx&#34;&gt;‘We can’t go back to normal’: How will coronavirus change the world?&lt;/a&gt;: 2020 will be etched in the memories of most people living today as one that drastically changed how we as humans functioned. As Covid19 spreads across various countries, it&amp;rsquo;s influencing and compelling dire actions. What was considered to be impossible at various level, is now just a quick decision point - Financial stimulus, vaccine production, remote work and schooling to name a prominent few. As we build resistance to the virus as a society and consequently as the adrenaline that&amp;rsquo;s currently rampant drains out, we&amp;rsquo;re going to see the fallout&amp;rsquo;s of our actions or several inaction&amp;rsquo;s thereof. Assuming another event of this magnitude does not occur over the next decade, the world is going to need a major overhaul to recover from the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ea2f0cbab1fa1.31532716&#34;&gt;Beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide to PGP&lt;/a&gt;: A simple and easy read on PGP with actionable guidance for non-tech folks out there. It&amp;rsquo;s given that over the next few months most countries are going to erode into the privacy of its citizens. Policies that are brought into effect now for surveillance and tracing will overarchingly become the norm and will be almost impossible to retract. It&amp;rsquo;s critical that we act now to safeguard what little privacy we can. It&amp;rsquo;s never been about - &amp;lsquo;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing that I have to hide.&amp;rsquo; Ignorance can and will heavily be mis-appropriated for someone else&amp;rsquo;s benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5e9ecbae16ccb0.15652872&#34;&gt;Why one Neuroscientist started blasting his core&lt;/a&gt;: Neural pathways, stress control systems and of course the adrenal medula. Yet another fascinating read on how amazing the human body is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ea68cce89b171.88947262&#34;&gt;How Saudi Arabia&amp;rsquo;s religious project transformed Indonesia&lt;/a&gt;: Religion, politics and power are so damned intertwined. If anything, its one of those defining necessities and vices of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ea68e112d5251.85133599&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to build&lt;/a&gt;: So beautifully phrased! It&amp;rsquo;s high time we dusted those tarp sheets and get to build from ground-up. Over time we&amp;rsquo;ve become complacent as a society and we need one strong re-boot!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>A glimpse of the past week and the few articles, podcasts, tools, videos and music that captivated my attention:</em></p>
<p>This week I got a better handle at deploying and maintaining docker images. With that squared out, I decided to decommission the Digital Ocean servers that I had setup <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/03/02/migrations-workflows/">back in 2017</a> and migrate the applications over to my Hetzner server. I no longer have to rely on ServerPilot. All my applications are now deployed as docker containers fronted by #Traefik as a reverse proxy.</p>
<p>The jitsi server instance I <a href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/19/self-hosting-jitsi-video-conferencing/">deployed last week</a> has been serving pretty well so far! I tweaked it further to enable <a href="https://blog.radiumz.org/en/article/local-recording-jitsi-meet">local recording</a>. Meena has been using it to run her online Yoga sessions and she can now also use it to record the podcast that she soon plans to start! Session recording and live-streaming is something I still need to configure in my current setup. The logs indicate it&rsquo;s failing on the Jibri handshake and that&rsquo;s something I&rsquo;ll need to figure out once I have a bit more time in hand.</p>
<p>Other actionable tasks on the tech front include figuring out a swift way to deploy PHP based applications on Docker. I still need to port over my Known and <a href="https://pixel.srkn.org/sriperinkulam">PixelFed</a> applications.</p>
<p>Last week, <a href="http://www.philipbrewer.net/">Philip</a> nudged me to look into my webmentions. The theme I previously had wasn&rsquo;t displaying them as comments. I needed a bit of a &lsquo;creativity boost&rsquo; and decided to use a new theme. Really liked the McLuhan theme by <a href="https://www.andersnoren.se/teman/mcluhan-wordpress-theme/">Anders Noren</a> and decided to give it a spin. Noticed <a href="https://wordpress.org/support/topic/mcluhan-comments-fetched-are-from-a-different-post/#new-topic-0">a minor issue with the comments section</a> and was easily able to fix it. I do however want to make a few tweaks to it, which I hopefully will get around attending to over the next few weeks. I also have my eye on <a href="https://prtksxna.com/">Prateek</a>&rsquo;s <a href="https://wordpress.org/themes/zuari/">Zuari theme</a> which is deeply <a href="https://indieweb.org/">indieweb</a> compliant.</p>
<p>Last evening, <a href="https://atchuth.wordpress.com/">Atchuth</a> mentioned he&rsquo;s now using his RPi4 as a full fledged desktop machine. He&rsquo;s moved over from DietPi to the Raspbian OS. Makes sense given his current use-case. Sharath on the other hand is still using his RPi 4 predominantly as a Nextcloud server.</p>
<p>This week has been great in terms of re-connecting with some good old friends! We&rsquo;re planning a re-union sometime next year. 20 year since we finished school! Phew!</p>
<p>The Khat-pat makers group that I am part of is now getting more traction and it&rsquo;s awesome just hearing out the cool things that other folks are doing. This week&rsquo;s session was on building drones from scratch!</p>
<p>I also got around connecting with the kids I taught 10 years ago! They&rsquo;ve all moved on to college and are into various things now. One kid wanted to become a stellar teacher and this  is one of the best messages I&rsquo;ve received so far!</p>
<p>Last night we played a few good rounds of Pictionary/Dumb-charades with the kids. Shasta had a terrific time just watching the &lsquo;adults&rsquo; in their elements. You never get too old for this game!</p>
<p><strong>Interesting podcasts this week</strong></p>
<p>Picturing Data: Monocle</p>
<p><a href="https://monocle.com/extensions/monocle/bin/mp3">https://monocle.com/extensions/monocle/bin/mp3</a>_downloader.php?file=https://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/788260468/download/&amp;filename=monocle_on_design_442.mp3</p>
<p><strong>Interesting tools this week</strong></p>
<p>The <a href="https://termux.com/">Termux app</a> has been an amazing value-add to my phone for those quick server check-in&rsquo;s!</p>
<p><strong>Interesting reads this week</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://outline.com/agNcAx">‘We can’t go back to normal’: How will coronavirus change the world?</a>: 2020 will be etched in the memories of most people living today as one that drastically changed how we as humans functioned. As Covid19 spreads across various countries, it&rsquo;s influencing and compelling dire actions. What was considered to be impossible at various level, is now just a quick decision point - Financial stimulus, vaccine production, remote work and schooling to name a prominent few. As we build resistance to the virus as a society and consequently as the adrenaline that&rsquo;s currently rampant drains out, we&rsquo;re going to see the fallout&rsquo;s of our actions or several inaction&rsquo;s thereof. Assuming another event of this magnitude does not occur over the next decade, the world is going to need a major overhaul to recover from the pandemic.</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ea2f0cbab1fa1.31532716">Beginner&rsquo;s guide to PGP</a>: A simple and easy read on PGP with actionable guidance for non-tech folks out there. It&rsquo;s given that over the next few months most countries are going to erode into the privacy of its citizens. Policies that are brought into effect now for surveillance and tracing will overarchingly become the norm and will be almost impossible to retract. It&rsquo;s critical that we act now to safeguard what little privacy we can. It&rsquo;s never been about - &lsquo;There&rsquo;s nothing that I have to hide.&rsquo; Ignorance can and will heavily be mis-appropriated for someone else&rsquo;s benefit.</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5e9ecbae16ccb0.15652872">Why one Neuroscientist started blasting his core</a>: Neural pathways, stress control systems and of course the adrenal medula. Yet another fascinating read on how amazing the human body is!</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ea68cce89b171.88947262">How Saudi Arabia&rsquo;s religious project transformed Indonesia</a>: Religion, politics and power are so damned intertwined. If anything, its one of those defining necessities and vices of humanity.</p>
<p><a href="https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ea68e112d5251.85133599">It&rsquo;s time to build</a>: So beautifully phrased! It&rsquo;s high time we dusted those tarp sheets and get to build from ground-up. Over time we&rsquo;ve become complacent as a society and we need one strong re-boot!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
