<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jitsi-Electron-App on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/jitsi-electron-app/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jitsi-Electron-App on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/jitsi-electron-app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting Jitsi video conferencing</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/19/self-hosting-jitsi-video-conferencing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/19/self-hosting-jitsi-video-conferencing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jitsi.org/&#34;&gt;Jit.si&lt;/a&gt; is a terrific, secure video-conferencing #alternative to #Zoom and obviously comes with all the open-source awesomeness. Call clarity is amazing and with a room capacity of 100+ (and potentially much more, driven by network and server capabilities), it&amp;rsquo;s an absolute no-brainer to switch over. Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://meet.jit.si/&#34;&gt;Jitsi Meet&lt;/a&gt; on the desktop or use one of their slick android, F-droid or iPhone apps on hand-held devices to organise your video conferences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the recent push to video-conferencing most meetings, I decided to setup my own instance. This was way more straightforward than I thought! I am currenty running it as a docker container, fronted with #Traefik for encryption. Configuration and installation steps mentioned below assume you have access to a domain name and server with docker already installed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting up the server:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A records:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create a new A record with your hosting provider to point your subdomain to the IP address of your server&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSH into server and install&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It should cost you only about 5$ per month for a decent server configuration. I already had an account with Hetzner, so I deployed my instance there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SSH into your server: &lt;code&gt;sudo ssh user@xx.xx.xx.xx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Initialise a swarm: &lt;code&gt;sudo docker swarm init&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create the traefik network: &lt;code&gt;sudo docker network create --driver=overlay traefik-net&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create two new yml files - one for traefik-ssl and another for jitsi, copy over the contents from the respective files &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ethibox/stacks&#34;&gt;available here from ethibox&lt;/a&gt; and make edits as needed:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano traefik-ssl.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano jitsi.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deploy the Traefik stack: &lt;code&gt;sudo docker stack deploy -c traefik-ssl.yml traefik&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deploy the Jitsi stack: &lt;code&gt;DOMAIN=meet.srkn.org SCHEME=https docker stack deploy -c jitsi.yml jitsi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If all goes well, you should now have a Jitsi instance running on your server with routing and ssl taken care of by Traefik.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configuring Jitsi:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You now need to setup the admin account. Login to the Jitsi prosody container. (Update command to reflect your container name):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker exec -it jitsi_prosody_1.xxxxxx bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Set as many host credentials as you need:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;prosodyctl --config /config/prosody.cfg.lua register host meet.jitsi usejitsi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exit out of the console! You now have a fully functional self-hosted Video-conference running! Do note that the recording feature currently does not work outright. Will have to sort that out over the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desktop and Mobile clients:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I decided to go the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jitsi/jitsi-meet-electron/#jitsi-meet-electron&#34;&gt;electron route&lt;/a&gt; for the desktop client. Jitsi has apps for both android and iOS that work out of the box. Just make sure you set the domains to yours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
