<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2007-10-28 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2007-10-28-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2007-10-28 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2007-10-28-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Speed and Sleep...</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2007/10/28/speed-and-sleep.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2007/10/28/speed-and-sleep.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love travelling!Though, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t got much to do with my  tendency to fall asleep in moving vehicles , to a very large extent that&amp;rsquo;s been the prime factor!!They&amp;rsquo;ve been quite a few days when I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up a day ticket in Hyderabad, got into one of the city buses and dozed off to glory only to be woken up by the Conductor telling me it&amp;rsquo;s the last stop and I better get off the bus and find a richer place to sulk!! :-) Even on regular days, I&amp;rsquo;ve  overshot my destination stop quite a few times, thanks to my innate ability to achieve  sub conscious levels in a matter of minutes. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been around twenty years and I still don&amp;rsquo;t get the  Motion and Sleep relationship that&amp;rsquo;s evolved in my body. Fortunately my holy brain doesn&amp;rsquo;t activate the clause  when I&amp;rsquo;m at the wheel! I love Speed as much as I love Sleep in motion. It&amp;rsquo;s just the feeling of escalated sense of enormous brain activity that drives things in me. I remember ramming into a wall and falling into a small gutter, just a few days after learning to cycle. I was actually trying to match speeds with a guy on a moped who&amp;rsquo;d sneered at me. Being a pretty short tempered guy then, I had all the adrenalin pumped to sort things out . Lost my wits,  lost my senses and finally ended up losing my control. Dr. Hakunamatata once said &amp;lsquo;You never lose in life! Everyplace you lose, you gain something really worthwhile. It all depends on how you look at things.&amp;rsquo; Ah! and here I&amp;rsquo;ve gained bruises and blessings from my bro for having brought out the cycle without telling anyone at home  ! (By the way, Dr. Hakunamatata is a virtual Doctor who resides in me :-) )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few things that I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt to abide when the adrenalin rushes in my body-Firstly,There&amp;rsquo;s something that you&amp;rsquo;d want to doubly ensure when you&amp;rsquo;re speeding beyond norms-Stay IN control. Secondly,There&amp;rsquo;s someone present around you,who knows what&amp;rsquo;s what and the repercussions of every minor flaw that may occur .Thirdly-Follow your instincts (only after you follow the above two rules :-) )&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trekking and Adventure sports is what I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to be into , five years down the lane; Paragliding and Sailing to be preicse. But it&amp;rsquo;s all a function of money , time and more so the right training place. I&amp;rsquo;ve Cornered on a few people who&amp;rsquo;ve been in the field for long and are really experienced in their respective fields. Now it&amp;rsquo;s a function of Time and Money both of which I have no say on, given the bounds of life :-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
