<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Running on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/categories/running/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Running on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 21:54:52 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/categories/running/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Woken</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/09/28/woken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 21:54:52 -0600</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/09/28/woken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;BosqueDeChapultapec.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M taps me slightly and points to the window. I’d mentioned I would go for a run if it starts raining. I’d probably slept for about an hour? Not sure when I fell asleep. Must be the sugar high from the petta that M got from Vancouver. I quickly change and head outdoors. It’s pouring but not as much I’d like it to. Hopefully it’ll pick up soon. It’s real dark and cloudy. The GPS on the Forerunner 250 barely registers any signal. I walk fast and head further west on Polanco towards Ferro Carril via Homero. Reach the biking path by the rail line and bear left. It’s pouring. Decide to pick up some pace and essentially run up on all the foot bridges. There’s barely anybody else on the trail. This is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I cross Club Naval on the right I see a sign for scuba diving classes. We saw ZNMDB this afternoon and now this ad. Got to be a coincidence. Maybe I’ll swing in a few dives in Bacalar? I swap my ear buds out as &lt;em&gt;The Emptiness machine&lt;/em&gt; tapers down. That pitch! Reach a junction where I need to decide if I should head towards Santa Fe or head back home. Maybe I could make this an impromptu 15 miler? I’m about three miles in. Decide to bear left and head towards Campo Militar. There’s quite some crowd here. Looks like the Saturday market is bustling with activity. Oh that smell of firewood smoking some delicacies! I’m almost sold on stopping and getting a hot cup of coffee. I’m bone wet and good cup of coffee won’t hurt? Decide against it for whatever reason and head towards Chapultapec. Maybe I should turn left and head towards Paseo de Reforma? Nah, the park is literally empty and I could possibly get a few more miles in. I head towards the Castle and then the Independence monument. I should probably try and find that spot where those two super old hand carts are on the road. Maybe I might get a real good shot? I just can’t remember where I saw it the last time. Well…the rain’s flooded the roads and you can barely see anything. I run across the 200 or so meters of flooded road hoping not step in an open manhole. Can’t be that bad…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About four miles in. I cross the road and head towards the Museo de Antropologia. Tlaloc is definitely showering his blessings today! My legs feel good. They’ve always felt strong. But for that niggling knee pain. Maybe I should get it checked out? I should run more frequently. Maybe I won’t have this luxury in Yaounde. Why does it take so much effort to workout? Need to work on that tiny belly showing up…and maybe some upper body strength too? Get that climbing membership? I’ve got only five months left. And then all this work travel. Should probably just focus on Ashtanga. I think I’m – so close – to making that into a habit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oh this city reminds me so much of Pune. The monsoon, the lush green parks, the people, the smells…. I’m so glad Pune happened. Some real great memories were made there. I’m sure it’s not all the same now. Someday I should go back and reach out to all the people I led on the trails. Maybe they are still hiking somewhere? Would they even remember me? Or maybe I just shouldn’t and let the photos tell the tales. More thunder rumbles in. I’m about two miles away from home. S is probably up and my tummy is rumbling a bit too. Damn. I should have gotten that coffee and soaked in more of that burning wood&amp;hellip;Next time I guess. I cross the Miguel Hidalgo sign and finally head home clocking around seven miles. What a terrific evening. So glad M woke me up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020-08-03 00:00:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/08/03/oregon-ridge-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/08/03/oregon-ridge-park/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Run at the Oregon Ridge park. Not one single soul all through the 4 mile loop. Nasal only, all through the loop. Humid weather, nasal breathing and oh, those uphills&amp;hellip;one good tiring run!&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;image-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;ul class=&#34;photo-list &#34;&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;             &#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&#xA;                &lt;img src=&#34;./images/06.1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;06.1.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;             &#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&#xA;                &lt;img src=&#34;./images/06.2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;06.2.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;             &#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&#xA;                &lt;img src=&#34;./images/06.3.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;06.3.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;.photo-list {&#xA;    display: flex;  &#xA;    flex-wrap: wrap;  &#xA;    margin: -1px;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list &gt; li {&#xA;    height: 40vh;  &#xA;    flex-grow: 1;  &#xA;    list-style-type: none;  &#xA;    margin: 1px;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list li img {&#xA;    max-height: 100%;  &#xA;    min-width: 100%;  &#xA;    object-fit: cover;  &#xA;    vertical-align: bottom;  &#xA;    border: 2px solid gray;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list li:last-child {&#xA;    flex-grow: 10;  &#xA;    border: none;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA; &#xA;.photo-list.single-image &gt; li {&#xA;    height: auto;  &#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/08/03/oregon-ridge-park/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marina rain run</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/09/20/marina-rain-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2019/09/20/marina-rain-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A wonderful morning run on the Marina today. Barefoot as always!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With a &amp;lsquo;gloomy&amp;rsquo; weather and not many visitors this early morning, we had most of the beach all for ourselves! As S and I were just about turning around after reaching Ice House, the slight drizzle very soon turned into a full fledged rain. Pouring rain, early morning waves and an empty beach is something I could take in every single day! Shasta seemed to have a terrific time too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meena happened to click this picture of us running from the distance. So glad she got around capturing this moment!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TARC Camp 2017</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/06/12/tarc-camp-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/06/12/tarc-camp-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://trailanimals.com/&#34;&gt;TARC&lt;/a&gt; running camp all smitten with bug and mosquito bites. And it feels terrific! Logged a good sixteen odd miles back in the trails after a month’s rest and met a good bunch of folks. It’s always so inspiring to attend these TARC meets. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/srikanth_perinkulam/albums/72157669983500465&#34;&gt;Last year&lt;/a&gt; at the camp, it was my first ever deep exposure to TARC and I was blown away by the positivity, humbleness and expanse and depth of knowledge these (ultra)runners and other campers brought in. What really makes TARC outstanding is its inclusivity and support framework. They’re open to anybody who is remotely interested in the outdoors and just let the sheer culture of this community take over the reins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, that experience at camp last year deeply impacted my outlook towards running. From barely training for any of the half and full marathons and winging them for the most part, I diligently trained for a 50 miler early this year. The primary intention was to understand my body better and get into a better fitness regimen. Pretty ironic that I ended up spraining my ankle badly during the main event and had to drop out. A run for which I’d logged &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/category/channel/training/&#34;&gt;more than 300 miles&lt;/a&gt; in training! Endurance has always been my forte and however arduous it be, I have never ‘given-up’ during a run/hike over the last ten or so years that I’ve been exploring outdoors. As I was walking back to the car that day, I was in second thoughts if I should have pushed it and completed the run. Something that I didn’t have a definitive answer for then and neither do I have now. All I knew was that my morale did take a beating for sure. Wapack and Back remains an unfinished business and I will have to get back on those rolling peaks to make peace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The camp this weekend was a much needed fix. Just being there surrounded by folks who have DNF’d before consciously for practical reasons and physical limitations took some load off my shoulders. Overall I believe I also had good quality runs this weekend. I felt much stronger on the trails and my average pace definitely seems to have gone up. I can’t wait to get back to a good training regimen again. I definitely do want to make it to more of the weekly runs at the Fells and should also probably join the Blue Hills group whenever feasible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a more tangible target, I have my eyes on the StoneCat 50 miler this November. The India trip may be a mild deterrent but I think I should be able to find a way around that…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/cropped-cropped-SP01-550afdebv1_site_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com&#34;&gt;Srikanth Perinkulam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 to the 50</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/01/31/31-to-the-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/01/31/31-to-the-50/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good 31 miler weekend to close out the third training week. And with that I&amp;rsquo;ve met Miss Me&amp;rsquo;s mandated clause of sticking to the training plan at least till the end of January (I&amp;rsquo;ve never really trained for any of my long runs this far!)  and bought myself an entry to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wapacktrailrace.com/&#34;&gt;Wapack and Back&lt;/a&gt; 50 miler this May. Psyched!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[sgpx gpx=&amp;quot;/wp-content/uploads/gpx/01282017_033241.gpx&amp;quot;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With a family event planned for this weekend, I had to fit in my 20mile saturday run early in the day. Given my last weekends pace at Middlesex fells, I wanted to bucket at least 5 hours for the run. Got to bed at around 08:30pm on Friday night, was up by about 03:00am on Saturday and started the run by 03:30am. Mild showers and pretty comfortable temperatures (20-30F) had me going pretty good and I covered the first loop (8 miles) in about 01:40mins. Miss Me was already up and had an Orange shot (Orange juice with some chat masala!) and PBJs ready for me. A quick pit-stop at home and I head back towards Brookline to cover the rest of the miles. I knew the Brookline loop would give me an easy 10 miles, so decided to run further on to Fenway to get the extra 2 miles. Even before I knew, I was on my way back and was home by 07:30am. This was probably my fastest 20 miler so far. Also a great morale boost after my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/01/21/middlesex-17-miler/&#34;&gt;deplorable 17 miles&lt;/a&gt; last weekend.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Miss Me managed to go for a Yoga class while I was running and once she was back, we hit the road to Southborough and then towards NJ. 40mins into the drive, the left rear tire blew up and with that our plans to head to NJ went kaput. We eventually make our way back home by noon. A lazy rest of the day gives me enough rest for the 11 miler next day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/32577512896_568cce6320_o-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;All of us head to Callahan State park and as I rake in the miles, the rest of the folks head back home after an hour. I weave into trails I&amp;rsquo;ve been on before and spruce it up with sections that I&amp;rsquo;ve not explored so far. The sheer number of trails out here so close to the city limits blows my mind every single time I chance upon uncharted sections. As I&amp;rsquo;m just about to finish my run in about 2.5 hours, I have a scooping fall. A good one at that. Talk about being &amp;lsquo;down to earth&amp;rsquo;!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/32495311001_53021f54c0_o-e1486005361769-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today is a stark reminder that I&amp;rsquo;m much, much slower on the trails and should be using this pace as benchmark to push and improve. As I build my miles, hopefully the pace improves. My Garmin clocked 116 miles totally this month. 2017 is off to a phenomenal start!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Middlesex 17 miler</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/01/21/middlesex-17-miler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/01/21/middlesex-17-miler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good 5 hours out in the woods. Terribly underestimated the skyline trail. Quite a few foot slips and ankle twists made it more of a hike than a run. Also looks like my body is &amp;lsquo;reacting&amp;rsquo; to the weekday runs. Badly needed some tummilicious food at mile 13. Note to self for future runs!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally got around visiting the Wrights tower! Despite visiting the fells several times over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve never really &amp;lsquo;made it&amp;rsquo; to this section of the trail. The tower by itself is nothing impressive but it does have some interesting history. Ice from here was apparently &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2010/09/0913calcutta-ice-ship/&#34;&gt;exported to India&lt;/a&gt; way back in the 1800s when Middlesex fells was a commercial plot. The tower gets it&amp;rsquo;s name from Elizur Wright who was instrumental in converting the erstwhile commercial land to what is now called the Middlesex Fells reservation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/32446594185_9035470f13_o-e1485036258624-768x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An amazing view of the Boston Skyline from the tower.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/32068547940_93da01e93a_o-1024x768.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First long run for the season. Hey, also my first self supported half this year. With tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s 9 miler, I&amp;rsquo;ll be signing off with about 49 miles this week. Not a bad start! Miss Me&amp;rsquo;s post run stretches have been quite instrumental in my injury free runs and I can&amp;rsquo;t thank her enough to keep pushing me for those runs after a long day. Only hope she doesn&amp;rsquo;t take her coach&amp;rsquo;s responsibility too seriously and cuts me off the fries!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[sgpx gpx=&amp;quot;/wp-content/uploads/gpx/01212017_081012.gpx&amp;quot;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-negotiable milers</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/11/11/non-negotiable-milers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/11/11/non-negotiable-milers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several years back, While in Pune, I&amp;rsquo;d resolved to spend every weekend outdoors. The plan was to get out of home before the break of dawn, head out to one of the umpteen number of forts and villages on the outskirts of the city and spend the rest two days just being out there. The weekends were an interesting mix of some terrific hikes, long bike rides or just days of hopping on and off arbitrary buses with no specific destination. The goal was also to write about my experiences. Arguably, that turned out to be a good vicious circle. I&amp;rsquo;d travel to write and write to travel. Looking back those were some of my most memorable days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/file-1024x768.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Larz Anderson&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;Couple days back during a regular stroll at Larz Anderson, the crisp air really got me thinking. Over the last year - work, exams and several other things have taken up a lot of my mind-space and I realized, I badly needed something else to get me back on my toes. Something to look forward to everyday and to keep me going. This, coupled with my want to enter into a better running regimen got me to consciously commit to running every single day. To start with, the goal is to run at least a mile every day, irrespective of weather, health or anything else the mind tries to concoct and come up with. It&amp;rsquo;s been just a few days since I decided to do this and I already see how hugely rewarding those ten - fifteen minutes being out there in the dark is. In a few weeks, I do want to significantly build up the mileage and hopefully be in a better shape for the TARC DRB next year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I do want to blend in more non-negotiables (reading, chanting, writing and whatever I think I&amp;rsquo;d ideally like to do every single day). Let&amp;rsquo;s call it &amp;lsquo;Deepening the non-negotiables bucket&amp;rsquo;. For now, here&amp;rsquo;s to more miles, trails and everything else that&amp;rsquo;s in between!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ragnar - Reach the Beach</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/09/20/ragnar-reach-the-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/09/20/ragnar-reach-the-beach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some great routes all the way down from Bretton woods Ski area in New Hampshire to the Hampton beach. The home stretch was probably the best ragnar finish ever. Despite decent timing, I had a real bad time on my second leg. Not sure if I should attribute it to the training or just how i felt during the run. Probably just one of those &amp;lsquo;meh&amp;rsquo; runs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Highlight of this event was Sharath and Meena running their first ever Ragnar event. Terrific on the roads and inclines!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=&amp;lsquo;flickr&amp;rsquo; user_id=&amp;lsquo;35722694@N00&amp;rsquo; photoset_id=&amp;lsquo;72157670744118103&amp;rsquo;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ragnar - Washington DC</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2015/10/02/ragnar-washington-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2015/10/02/ragnar-washington-dc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of most exhilarating (and wet) runs so far. The night run with pitch dark trails and just Joaquin for company made this one unforgettable experience.  Reminded me of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/adventure-travel/katrabai-pass&#34;&gt;Katrabai Pass hike&lt;/a&gt; back in India.  The Ragnar Appalachians still remains unchecked!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/22014228892_3a4ee1b691_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2015 Ragnar&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bear Mountain Half</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2015/05/03/the-bear-mountain-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2015/05/03/the-bear-mountain-half/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ran the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thenorthface.com/get-outdoors/endurance-challenge/new-york.html&#34;&gt;#ECSNY Half&lt;/a&gt; at the Bear Mountain State park today! As the stats down under reveal - this was one divine killer run. One of the hardest long-runs I&amp;rsquo;ve run so far. My average timing on &amp;lsquo;flat-road&amp;rsquo; half-marathons has been 02:10.  Over the last few weeks as I mentally and physically prepared for this run I was estimating a sub 03:00 finish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/BMSP-NF.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/BMSP-NF.png&#34; alt=&#34;BMSP NF&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About six miles on the trail I targeted a sub 02:45 finish - But I guess I succumbed to the mountains and then the mind lost to the body in the last 3 or 4 miles. My initial strategy was to hike up the inclines and run down the slopes. Out there, running down the trails was absolutely inevitable and my glutes and calves reminded me of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/outdoors&#34;&gt;innumerable hikes&lt;/a&gt; done years back in India. A gracious fall by a culvert further slowed me down. I ended with a 03:27 finish. Though these run stats are deplorable even under average standards; I had a truly wonderful time on the trail there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I believe I need to strongly work on my lower back and do a lot more hill training. Also calls for a lot more hikes to work on the glutes and calves.  Now that the Bear mountain hike is off the list, eye&amp;rsquo;s on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://srtrunhike.com/&#34;&gt;SRT hike/run&lt;/a&gt; later this year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevation Profile:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/BMSP-Elevation-.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/BMSP-Elevation-.png&#34; alt=&#34;BMSP Elevation&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPX:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Note to self: Need to figure out why altitude isn&amp;rsquo;t showing up in the GPX]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[sgpx gpx=&amp;quot;/wp-content/uploads/gpx/activity_765121253.gpx&amp;quot;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Philadelphia Half</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2014/11/24/philadelphia-half/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2014/11/24/philadelphia-half/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great weather, strong finish and yet another run that convinced me running on city roads isn&amp;rsquo;t quite my thing. This most probably would be my last &amp;lsquo;scheduled&amp;rsquo; run for 2014 and couldn&amp;rsquo;t have asked for a finer closure of a crazy week. Another exciting family event adds further to this silver lining making this run even more memorable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mile 10 will be remembered and Philadelphia - we shall be back!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[sgpx gpx=&amp;quot;/wp-content/uploads/gpx/activity_638905039.gpx&amp;quot;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ragnar 2014 GPX Feeds</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2014/10/17/ragnar-2014-gpx-feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2014/10/17/ragnar-2014-gpx-feeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just found a nifty plugin that would map charts feeding off from gpx inputs. Here are the chart outputs from my recent Ragnar Run.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legs 01 - 06 [4.9 mi + 2.7mi + 8.9mi]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[sgpx gpx=&amp;quot;/wp-content/uploads/gpx/activity_602412715.gpx&amp;quot; ]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legs 13 - 18 [5.8mi]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[sgpx gpx=&amp;quot;/wp-content/uploads/gpx/activity_602412752.gpx&amp;quot; ]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legs 25 - 30 [3.4mi]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[sgpx gpx=&amp;quot;/wp-content/uploads/gpx/activity_602412773.gpx&amp;quot; ]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legs 31 - 36 [2.4mi]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was literally dead in this leg. Heat and uphills can be a deadly combination!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[sgpx gpx=&amp;quot;/wp-content/uploads/gpx/activity_602412785.gpx&amp;quot; ]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appalachians next!</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2014/10/08/appalachians-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2014/10/08/appalachians-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Ragnar.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Ragnar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ragnar&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t have ended September on a better note! Pounding the hilly terrain in the Adirondacks for 36 hrs, straight through the night with 9 other folks - This has been my best run so far. Though technically that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of time for 197 miles, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s the nuances of the event that really gives you the extra kick.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Running on those hills for miles at night with just absolute darkness for company, the sudden sprint from a water-station when you realized it was tactfully positioned right in front of a cemetery, the thrill of handing over the slap band to the next runner at the end of your run, the last one mile which never felt so close and that particular runner who always seems to cross you on every single uphill - few things that is quite uncommon in other running events. To top all of that, the camaraderie that emerges from participating in an event of such a scale just cannot be replicated in any other event.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looks like I&amp;rsquo;m more than &amp;lsquo;addicted&amp;rsquo; to these Ragnar events and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to start training for yet another run. My feet yearn for a good trail run and how wonderful it would be if I could blend that in with a Ragnar event. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ragnartrail.com/locations/appalachians-wv&#34;&gt;Appalachians next!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  Will probably fit in a couple of half&amp;rsquo;s in between just to keep the muscles working.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ragnar times</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2014/09/23/ragnar-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2014/09/23/ragnar-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Fort-lee.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Fort-lee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fort lee&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Friday, I&amp;rsquo;d be doing a 200 mile relay run at Adirondacks, NY with 9 other family friends .  This one is extra special for several reasons. Few months back, an ankle injury prevented me from running the Bear Mountain State Park Half Marathon - a run I was really looking forward to. That setback and the recovery from the injury further fueled my training for the Adirondacks Ragnar relay run. In the last two months,  I&amp;rsquo;ve explored more trails than I did all over the last year and a half. I&amp;rsquo;ve had stronger 8 mile and 10 mile finishes than ever before. More importantly, I&amp;rsquo;m truly enjoying running and the places it&amp;rsquo;s taking me to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This weekend would be a good gauge to set targets on an ultra run sometime soon. And I guess the &amp;lsquo;kick&amp;rsquo; is not in the distance but the distances it would take me to and the experiences that would come by. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to leave school tomorrow evening for the mega weekend. Ragnar - Here we come!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mumbai 2012 Full Marathon</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2012/01/20/mumbai-2012-full-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2012/01/20/mumbai-2012-full-marathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/Mumbai-2012.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Mumbai-2012-724x1024.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Mumbai 2012&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
