<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2020-05 on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/month/2020-05/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2020-05 on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/month/2020-05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buzzards Rock and Illchester tunnel hike - Patapasco</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/31/buzzards-rock-and-illchester-tunnel-hike-patapasco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/31/buzzards-rock-and-illchester-tunnel-hike-patapasco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of those trails with a splendid combination of river, streams, tunnels, rail-line, good elevation profile and lots of rocks! Kids absolutely loved it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery size=&amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;8368,8367,8366,8365,8364,8363,8362,8361,8360,8359,8356,8355,8354&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/5019175074&#34;&gt;Garmin Connect GPX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soapstone Trail - Patapsco</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/30/soapstone-trail-patapsco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/30/soapstone-trail-patapsco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The trail we actually planned for had no parking spots left. Chanced upon Soapstone as we were driving back. A good 5mile loop with a decent elevation profile.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery size=&amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo; columns=&amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;8351,8350,8349&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/5015288976&#34;&gt;Garmin connect GPX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Run Woods</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/27/red-run-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/27/red-run-woods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Took Appa out for a stroll. Shasta enjoyed a good bunch bobbling around the streams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery size=&amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;8344,8345,8346&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascade falls hike - Patapsco</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/23/cascade-falls-hike-patapsco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/23/cascade-falls-hike-patapsco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good 2.5 mile long drive within the Patapsco state park gets you to the start point of this trail. A small climb up the hills and amidst thick foliage winds over and gets you to Cascade falls. Great weather and wonderful streams!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery size=&amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;8331,8332,8333,8334,8335,8336,8337,8338,8339&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/4980057314&#34;&gt;Garmin Connect GPX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Number Nine Trolley Trail Hike</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/number-nine-trolley-trail-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/number-nine-trolley-trail-hike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This trail has been on my lists in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alltrails.com/&#34;&gt;AllTrails&lt;/a&gt; app and for whatever reason, we haven&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to explore it yet. Decided on a whim to head here this Sunday. By-far one of the best hikes in Baltimore!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery link=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo; size=&amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;8157,8148,8147,8149,8150,8155,8151,8152,8153,8154,8156,8158&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trail as such is a tarred path winding up Ellicot city with multiple streams on either side. We decided to veer off on one of the sub-trails (Red trail) for some quality time out in the woods. With a mild breeze and a looming cloud shower, Shasta slept through most of it. Definitely heading back here later with Appa!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GPX from &lt;a href=&#34;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/4948345583&#34;&gt;Garmin Connect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing images</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/optimizing-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/optimizing-images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Samsung phone by default generates pretty high resolution pictures. Even with the most basic setting, captured images turn out to be ~3MB! I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge photo buff and don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily need such high clarity pictures which consume a lot of space. I recently came across two amazing utilities that help optimize images in Linux: jpegoptim and optipng&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install them via terminal:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install jpegoptim&#xA;sudo apt-get install optipng &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And optimize away!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jpegoptim --size=1024k &amp;lt;file-name&amp;gt;.jpg&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be sure note to go minimalist ( ~ 125k - Like I did in a few of my recent posts), since that doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite do a lossless compression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The utility can also be used to bulk optimize images which can be super useful!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switched!</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/switched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/switched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far I had all the micro-servers in the home network connected either to a LAN port or to an Orbi Satellite. This week I implemented a simple 8 port un-managed TP-Link switch into my &amp;lsquo;homelab&amp;rsquo;. Costed just about 18 bucks with a price-match from amazon and it has tremendously improved upload/download speeds! Also it&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool to visually see that the RPi3B+ boards are being throttled at 10/100Mbps while the RPi4 is rummaging at 1000Mbps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While at it, I re-purposed a few card-board boxes and built a bare bones stack. Ain&amp;rsquo;t pretty does absolutely does the job!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20200517_030654-868x1200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 20 - Trails and Switches</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/weeknote-20-trails-and-switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/weeknote-20-trails-and-switches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few things that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the kids at home, weather mostly good and the lock-down lifted we did venture out a bit and got a lot of hikes in this week. We obviously had all masks on and avoided crowded spaces. Also had this sudden realization that most of the hikes I was doing over the past few years in Baltimore were on the banks of the Patapsco river. Would be wonderful to plan a good long 15-20 miler one of these days. Should be a good recce for the half-marathon that I said I would organize for Meena, Nancy and Sharath next month!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wonderful talk with Atchuth last night on servers and hosting content! On my end, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/switched/&#34;&gt;installed a small switch&lt;/a&gt; for my devices. Also ordered a 2TB external drive since the laptop that I backup my files on is slowly reaching full capacity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Took appa out for a drive yesterday. His first outing in over three months now. I think it&amp;rsquo;s reasonably safe for him to head outdoors now. I do really want to take him to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/number-nine-trolley-trail-hike/&#34;&gt;Number nine trolley hike&lt;/a&gt; we did today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely loving the share article feature on Wallabag (And also Selfoss). It helps me share articles with family and friends without the annoying ads while providing a link to the source. I totally understand that certain publishers need ads to produce quality journalism. What I am not comfortable with is, them using that to track me. In the links that I share below, most are linked to &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;my wallabag instance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s public share. If I refer to an individual&amp;rsquo;s blog post however, I&amp;rsquo;ll link directly to the source. The only downside to that is, people tend to move across CMS or blogging software and links get orphaned&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting tools this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://e.foundation/&#34;&gt;The /e/ Foundation&lt;/a&gt;: My next phone is most likely going to be running this OS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/optimizing-images/&#34;&gt;Jpegoptim&lt;/a&gt;: Linux tools to compress images on a whim&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting podcasts this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/radiolab/articles/octomom&#34;&gt;Octomom&lt;/a&gt;: The octopus species that broods its eggs for close to five years!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec1a002090d83.01810323&#34;&gt;What does your gaze reveal about you?&lt;/a&gt;: A ridiculous whole lot! Will have to get back to this later to explore more of the links. The amount of information that can be gleaned and analyzed is pretty intriguing. The age-old saying goes - &amp;lsquo;Eyes are the windows to a person&amp;rsquo;s soul&amp;rsquo;. Looks like we humans took a good note of that!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5e9ecf5523a767.92611391&#34;&gt;Go squat!&lt;/a&gt;: Something that&amp;rsquo;s so common-place in India (And several other countries)&amp;hellip;It&amp;rsquo;s like coming back a full circle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec06776757543.21835439&#34;&gt;Would you want your tax dollars to be invested in Public-Private partnerships?&lt;/a&gt;: When it comes to a choice between investing in humans and investing in technology, I&amp;rsquo;d rather invest in humans. I understand why it&amp;rsquo;s a hard sell though…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec1a3d17320a4.24739015&#34;&gt;Converting type A blood to type O&lt;/a&gt;: Applications for this are huge! Imagine not having to wait to find donors for a specific blood type.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ec0702437ae34.22105740&#34;&gt;Swiper, no swiping&lt;/a&gt;! Privacy.com relies on plaid, which was bought by Visa recently…The good old days of relying on cash ought to be back.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loch Raven Reservoir Hike</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/16/loch-raven-reservoir-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/16/loch-raven-reservoir-hike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, not quite! The main trail was closed out for repairs so we ended up exploring the woods around the reservoir. We haven&amp;rsquo;t explored this section much, so it was good coming back here after a long time. Lot&amp;rsquo;s of bush-whacking and getting lost, which was good! Weather was very accommodating.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery link=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo; size=&amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;8119,8120,8123,8124,8125&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alberta road - Thru trail Hike</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/15/alberta-road-thru-trail-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/15/alberta-road-thru-trail-hike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of our last week&amp;rsquo;s hike I sensed we were close to a small dam but we didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get to that point . Wanted to explore that section and also cover the Alberta road trail. Meena and I head out this afternoon with the kids. While the trail was beautiful and the kids did have a real good time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite feel great. With temps reaching 85+ and absolutely no breeze, I was so glad when we were done with the hike. Totally about 2.5 miles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery size=&amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo; link=&amp;ldquo;none&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;8111,8112,8113,8114,8115,8116&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section of the Thru trail also had quite a few options for kayaking and rock climbing. Will definitely get back here later to spend time near the water.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old Main line and Daniels&#39; loop hike</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/10/old-main-line-and-daniels-loop-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/10/old-main-line-and-daniels-loop-hike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Planned to hike the Alberta Road Thru trail but ended hiking the Old Main Line and Daniels&amp;rsquo; loop since that&amp;rsquo;s where we found parking! Thanks to the Lock-down lift-off, the weekend and a terrific weather.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery size=&amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo; link=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;8103,8104,8105,8106,8107&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This turned out to be one of those random trail finds which I&amp;rsquo;ll truly cherish. Beautiful trail views as you ascend onto old main line and drop back on the Daniels&amp;rsquo; section with the river on your left. Bright sunshine, gentle breeze and a good nippy climate absolutely made our day! Rounded out about 3 miles as we made our way back to the car.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 19 - feeds and sessions</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/10/weeknote-19-feeds-and-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/10/weeknote-19-feeds-and-sessions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few things that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weather&amp;rsquo;s been pretty erratic this week. We also had a mild dusting yesterday out of the blue! Might consider heading out for a hike later today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I nudged Meena to write more. We&amp;rsquo;ve had some interesting discussions on Yoga and other things over the past week and I do think she has a ton to share! She&amp;rsquo;s also planning to train for a 50miler which I am super excited about! Oh and beyond all that marketing ploy, Happy Mothers&amp;rsquo; day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shasta&amp;rsquo;s talking a lot more now. Pretty sure her verbal diarrhea is soon going to start soon too!  The other day, while sitting with Appa she said something to the effect of &amp;lsquo;i-pae&amp;rsquo; pointing to the ipad. Grandfather and daughter are totally connecting on these gadgets!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Git: I agree on many levels with &lt;a href=&#34;https://kevq.uk/confession-i-have-no-idea-how-to-use-git/&#34;&gt;what Kev posted recently&lt;/a&gt; about Github. I enjoy working on and deploying software tools. What I do not enjoy is the whole git pull, push, fork thing!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sessions: I am running a session later this week for the Khat-pat folks on self hosting. Planning to keep it mostly hands-on and crisp. The idea is to get them started on taking better control of their presence on the interwebs! I&amp;rsquo;d also love to join the Indieweb folks one of these days. They have &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.indieweb.org/2020/05/online-indieweb-meetup-nyc-vkY32vBfCTEJ&#34;&gt;one coming up on the 20th&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tools: Earlier this week, I came across e-mail cloaking services - &lt;a href=&#34;https://simplelogin.io/&#34;&gt;Simplelogin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://anonaddy.com/&#34;&gt;Anondaddy&lt;/a&gt;. Love the idea and I might give them a shot the next time I subscribe or sign-up for a service.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feed Readers: Over the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve used multiple feed readers - Netvibes, TheOldReader, FreshRSS and Fever. They were all good in specific aspects but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really find them to be that one tool which I could use to consume the inter-webs my way. Earlier this week I decided to self-host one and narrowed down to FreshRSS, miniflux and selfoss. After a few iterations of deploying and testing, I stuck with &lt;a href=&#34;https://selfoss.aditu.de/&#34;&gt;selfoss&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s super light-weight and has all the specific features I was looking for.  To deploy it on docker, I used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/28/deploying-known-on-a-docker-stack/&#34;&gt;boiler-plate template that I created earlier&lt;/a&gt; when setting up my &lt;a href=&#34;https://known.srkn.org&#34;&gt;known&lt;/a&gt; instance.  The gist file for the docker-compose is &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/bf31682e6d9805ac29d6e4ff02bacb28&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The install should take you at most 10 minutes assuming you have the base framework setup. What I do love about selfoss is the ability to push articles over to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;wallabag&lt;/a&gt; instance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trilium: I&amp;rsquo;ve moved most of my notes over to Trilium and I am absolutely loving it! While it&amp;rsquo;s hierarchical, it is also setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium/wiki/Patterns-of-personal-knowledge-base&#34;&gt;not to be one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb322c0461ff3.59682906&#34;&gt;Time-restricted eating&lt;/a&gt;: Philip &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philipbrewer.net/2020/05/03/experiments-with-time-restricted-eating/&#34;&gt;referenced this article recently&lt;/a&gt; and I think it&amp;rsquo;s brilliant! Also went ahead and signed up for Rhonda&amp;rsquo;s podcast.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb705c2235124.51234929&#34;&gt;Tracking using ultrasound frequencies&lt;/a&gt;: Whoa! This totally blew my mind! If google uses it to connect your devices with chrome cast, what&amp;rsquo;s really stopping them from using it to track what you are watching? And now how do you block that invasion?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb6f8cbd8a783.67620597&#34;&gt;Workplaces in the era&lt;/a&gt;: Firms will have additional pressure from (or will be incentivised by) their insurance companies to have monitoring in place. Over the span of few months, this will be the new normal. Looking back, haven&amp;rsquo;t we all got used to keying-in and out at our workplaces?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb700e76826f2.47966883&#34;&gt;We kill people based on metadata&lt;/a&gt;: Quite a lot is changed since 2014. What hasn&amp;rsquo;t though is how fragmented and withdrawn several government and private entities are even in times of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5eb7034fba3519.79379071&#34;&gt;The mystic veil of End-to-End encryption&lt;/a&gt;: Interesting read on the data sharing between these apps.  The other day I was wondering how &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bark.us/&#34;&gt;Bark&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s able to access messages from these apps. Likely they have something on these lines drifting underneath? While I love the concept of the app and the benefits it provides, I did cringe and walk away because I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how they&amp;rsquo;d be handling the data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating over to Trilium notes</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/07/migrating-over-to-trilium-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/07/migrating-over-to-trilium-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;PS: For step-by-step instructions read &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/04/06/installing-trilium-notes/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; post instead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had my eyes on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium&#34;&gt;Trilium notes&lt;/a&gt; since last year. Having setup a robust docker framework &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/24/weeknote-17-covid19-webmentions-and-migrations/&#34;&gt;earlier this year&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to test Trilium out. Gave it a test run this morning and am way impressed with its&amp;rsquo; functionalities! With docker, installation was super easy and I am strongly leaning towards using Trilium as my primary note application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The yml file to get this running on docker (swarm) is in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/60323d29922069887f627ccedc65bad3&#34;&gt;github gist&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;d obviously need to have docker installed, docker swarm running with the traefik container and the domain mapped as needed. My &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/04/19/self-hosting-jitsi-video-conferencing/&#34;&gt;Jitsi post&lt;/a&gt; has this outlined further.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I haven&amp;rsquo;t spent a fair amount of time diving deep into the setup, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick first impression:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beautiful interface that can be as sparse or as detailed as you&amp;rsquo;d like it to be&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Encrypted by default and further protected sessions for sensitive notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A note-info section that details attributes and link-maps&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notes can be &amp;lsquo;cloned&amp;rsquo; under multiple places in a tree&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Code scripting, tables, markdown, images, files - It&amp;rsquo;s got it all!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Web clipper for quick screen and context grabs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Export and Import functionalities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No mobile apps yet! However, it does have a mobile front-end which should be a good alternative&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No multi-user support yet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was exploring Joplin as an alternative initially but decided to stick with Trilium since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://joplinapp.org/&#34;&gt;Joplin app&lt;/a&gt; currently has limited functionality (Creating nested trees in the mobile app). Meena&amp;rsquo;s been looking at switching over from her current Evernote setup and I think this might be a terrific replacement for her. Was never really a fan of Evernote and that dislike strengthened further when I had to install the app either on a Mac or PC to export my content! I am so glad we have the strength of open-source to weigh against these silo&amp;rsquo;ist setups!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
