<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sotn on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/sotn/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sotn on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/sotn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks – Feb 2022</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/02/22/state-of-the-networks-feb-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/02/22/state-of-the-networks-feb-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A bi-yearly rundown on the state of the home-servers I run and applications I host on the cloud.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Published while listening to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://invidious.snopyta.org/watch?v=zkvNnRjIhPE&#34;&gt;Mist of Capricorn ( Manavyalakincharadate ) | Agam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/wireguard-2.drawio.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few major changes since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/09/07/state-of-the-networks-sep-2021/&#34;&gt;last September update&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;During the Jan trip, I moved the Odroid XU4 and NCP over to MD. Thanks to WireGuard, I can still access these remotely super seamlessly!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brought in the RPi4 NC to the same WireGuard network. Lesser maintenance!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not quite using the Navidrome and Calibre-web setup as much. Definitely nice to have though.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setup a couple &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/02/20/bridged/&#34;&gt;Matrix Bridges&lt;/a&gt;. Ansible is pretty awesome! Need to front the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/25/snikket/&#34;&gt;Snikket instance&lt;/a&gt; I setup in Jan when I have the mind-space.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m liking Caddy better than Traefik!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next few months, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably focus a bit more on SSH hardening, implement more robust Firewalls and automating the backups.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks – Sep 2021</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/09/07/state-of-the-networks-sep-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/09/07/state-of-the-networks-sep-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months, I was able to take some time to explore a few self-hostable options. I got to explore &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/07/28/caddy-through-the-tunnel/&#34;&gt;caddy&lt;/a&gt; (Which is terrific by the way!), setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/07/15/guacamole-clientless-remote-desktop-access/&#34;&gt;guacamole&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m also absolutely loving &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/07/28/july-27-2021-2105/&#34;&gt;Navidrome&lt;/a&gt;. I got rid of OSMC since we weren&amp;rsquo;t quite using it as much and setup pi-hole to block ads network wide. With these changes, I think I am able to put these devices to real good use. While at it, I also setup a WireGuard tunnel from a VPS to access my local devices securely outside my home network.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Screenshot-from-2021-09-07-13-25-42-600x296.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/02/05/state-of-the-networks-feb-2021/&#34;&gt;February update&lt;/a&gt;, I haven&amp;rsquo;t changed the services on the cloud much. I did get rid of Bookstack, Known and Signal-CLI since I wasn&amp;rsquo;t using them as much. I am however using &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/?s=trilium&#34;&gt;Trilium notes&lt;/a&gt; exhaustively as my go-to notes and knowledge-base application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks - Feb 2021</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/02/05/state-of-the-networks-feb-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/02/05/state-of-the-networks-feb-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A quick rundown on the state of the home-servers I run or applications I host on the cloud.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Published while listening to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://invidious.snopyta.org/watch?v=RlcY37n5j9M&#34;&gt;Malang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With our temporary relocation, I currently manage two &amp;lsquo;home-labs&amp;rsquo; - one which I remotely manage with a WireGuard tunnel and the other just a local-access only setup. The remote home-lab is essentially a Nextcloud server running on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dietpi.com/&#34;&gt;DietPi OS&lt;/a&gt; spun on an RPi4. I pulled down the HAProxy config on the fronting server since that was no longer required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Homelab-SoTN-Feb-2021-600x478.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The local home-lab currently encompasses four units:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ownyourbits.com/nextcloudpi/&#34;&gt;NextcloudPi&lt;/a&gt; running on an RPi3 and connected to a 1TB main drive: This has been our primary document and media backup servers silently chugging along for close to three years now!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osmc.tv/&#34;&gt;OSMC&lt;/a&gt; installed on another RPi3: With a 1TB media drive, Amazon video and Youtube addons this primarily serves as a secondary family Television. A bit on the sluggish end but does the job for now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DietPi running on an &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.odroid.com/odroid-xu4/odroid-xu4&#34;&gt;Odroid-XU4&lt;/a&gt;: Pi-Hole for Ad control and WireGuard to access the remote home-lab.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pop.system76.com/&#34;&gt;PoPOS&lt;/a&gt; running on an Intel NUC7: My primary workstation! An attached 1TB drive acts as the secondary backup for my NC setup and then I run sync jobs to a 256GB flash drive for a cold backup of the really important files.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then, on a remote VM I run a slew of services that handle most of my social and productivity tools. Fronted by Traefik and running in docker containers, the following services run on the 8GB server:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bookstackapp.com/&#34;&gt;Bookstack&lt;/a&gt; – Wiki software which I am currently using to help publish my dad’s second book&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://known.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;Known&lt;/a&gt; – I mostly use this as a quick bookmarking tool. I also post short updates or status notes here infrequently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wallabag.it/en&#34;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; – Read-later app&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/14/guyon-flats-and-tuffys-tavern-trail/&#34;&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt; – Way better than Instagram and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixel.srkn.org/sriperinkulam&#34;&gt;my go-to space&lt;/a&gt; to post individual images&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://selfoss.aditu.de/&#34;&gt;Minflux&lt;/a&gt; – The light-weight feed-reader that I pipe all my RSS subscriptions to&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium&#34;&gt;Trilium Notes&lt;/a&gt; – A terrific Evernote alternative with awesome Markdown support&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbernhard/signal-cli-rest-api&#34;&gt;Signal-CLI&lt;/a&gt; – I use this for server trigger notifications to be sent via SMS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://etherpad.org/&#34;&gt;Etherpad&lt;/a&gt; – Quick, collaborative notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptpad.fr/&#34;&gt;CryptPad&lt;/a&gt; - Collaboration suite for documents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Calibre - I use this to manage &lt;a href=&#34;https://lib.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;my digital books collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lychee - A nifty photo gallery where I currently save my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/08/26/stamp-collection-digitized/&#34;&gt;digital stamps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;WordPress – I run 4 instances of WordPress – Portals for folks in my family&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nextcloud – This one’s more to test the recent releases before I deploy them on my home-lab&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometime down the lane I would like to setup a &lt;a href=&#34;https://snikket.org/&#34;&gt;Snikket instance&lt;/a&gt; for family chats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks – Jun 2020</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/18/state-of-the-networks-jun-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/18/state-of-the-networks-jun-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A quick rundown on the state of the home-servers I run or applications I host on the cloud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My &amp;lsquo;Homelab&amp;rsquo; setup has not changed much since my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/02/04/state-of-the-networks-jan-2020/&#34;&gt;last update in January&lt;/a&gt;. I did add in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/switched/&#34;&gt;switch&lt;/a&gt; and installed a wireguard vpn on the RPI 3B+ that fronts as a reverse proxy for the Nextcloud media devices. I also got a Seagate 2TB drive and built two partitions into it. One acts as a backup for my Nextcloud files and the other is a &amp;lsquo;cold backup&amp;rsquo; of my Hetzner cloud instance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/State-of-the-Network-Jun-2020--1200x977.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For personal use, I maintain two remote cloud servers on Hetzner:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hetzner 01&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first server essentially handles most of my social and productivity tools. Fronted by Traefik and running in docker containers, the following services run on the 8GB server:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bookstackapp.com/&#34;&gt;Bookstack&lt;/a&gt; - Wiki software which I am currently using to help publish my dad&amp;rsquo;s second book&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://known.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;Known&lt;/a&gt; - FB alternative. I mostly use this as a quick bookmarking tool. I also post short updates or status notes here infrequently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wordpress  - I run 4 instances of Wordpress - Portals for folks in my family.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wallabag.it/en&#34;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; - Read-later app&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/14/guyon-flats-and-tuffys-tavern-trail/&#34;&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt; - My go-to space to post individual images.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://selfoss.aditu.de/&#34;&gt;Selfoss&lt;/a&gt; - The light-weight feed-reader that I pipe all my RSS subscriptions to.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nextcloud - This one&amp;rsquo;s more to test the recent releases before I deploy them on my homelab.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium&#34;&gt;Trilium Notes&lt;/a&gt; - My go-to place to save quick notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbernhard/signal-cli-rest-api&#34;&gt;Signal-CLI&lt;/a&gt; - I use this for server trigger notifications to be sent via SMS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mattermost - Slack alternative&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Etherpad - Quick, collaborative notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hetzner 02:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This server hosts my Matrix and Jitsi Conference applications. While at it, I also have a Riot instance running in parallel that fronts the Synapse install.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks - Jan 2020</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/02/04/state-of-the-networks-jan-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/02/04/state-of-the-networks-jan-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A quick rundown on the state of the home-servers I run or applications I host on the cloud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week I opened up my Nextcloud instance for external access. Now, since my brother&amp;rsquo;s RPi4 was already exposed on the same network, I had to setup a reverse proxy on another RPi3 to access both simultaneously behind the router. Here&amp;rsquo;s the current setup:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/State-of-the-Network-Jan-2020-.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proxy server:&lt;/strong&gt; An RPi3 running on Raspbian Buster Lite with HAProxy installed to handle the reverse proxy. Here&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/23fee95d454fe3a9ff18a0555734e3ab&#34;&gt;gist of the code&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s handling all the heavy lifting. Since SSL is handled by the other servers themselves, all I needed was a quick pass-through handshake from HAProxy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server 01:&lt;/strong&gt; An RPi3 running on NextcloudPi essentially serving Nextcloud for all my file needs. Data is simultaneously backed up on a couple machines within the network. Decided against a remote backup [S3/Backblaze] for now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server 02:&lt;/strong&gt; An RPi4 running on Diet-Pi and serving Pi-Hole and a Nextcloud instance. I&amp;rsquo;ve turned off DHCP on the Orbi router and delegated that to the Pi-Hole. Both the Pi-Hole and the router have static IPs assigned to the SBCs and my trusty Dell machine based on their MAC address. I&amp;rsquo;m debating if I should move the Pi-Hole over to the Proxy Server&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beyond the home-lab, I have a droplet with DigitalOcean serving this website and a few other portals I manage. ServerPilot runs in the background on that droplet taking care of all the critical needs. I do intend to shift this over to a home-lab once I get hold of my ODroid XU4 which is currently in the Uganda shipment several thousand miles away in Chennai!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early this year, I also procured a Hetzner cloud instance to test its stability and see if I could move over certain portals to it. Should say I&amp;rsquo;m pretty impressed! Running on Debian Stretch and powered by Yunohost, I installed &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixel.srkn.org/sriperinkulam&#34;&gt;PixelFed&lt;/a&gt; and Wallabag. Installation has never been any easier! One drawback for sure is that the code-base may be a bit lagged as it gets deployed on Yunohost. Nevertheless, it&amp;rsquo;s pure magic to see things getting installed with just a few clicks and not much back-end work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then, I manage a Moodle Bitnami instance running on an AWS instance. I intend to move it over to the Hetzner cloud over the next month or so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
