<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2025-01-31 21:30:00 -0500 -0500 on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2025-01-31-213000--0500--0500/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2025-01-31 21:30:00 -0500 -0500 on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2025-01-31-213000--0500--0500/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Matamoros</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/31/matamoros/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/31/matamoros/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Brownsville.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back from a seemingly long but super-productive trip to Matamoros/Brownsville. This would be my last TDY while here in Mexico City. We went in body-heavy and it did pay-off. A good bunch of cables were pulled and cameras fixed. The weather was impeccable. With gusty winds, super dark and bearing clouds and temperatures barely hitting the 50s - It was perfect outdoor work weather. More so high up on an extended ladder!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Got to meet the Candadai&amp;rsquo;s the day I landed. They own a property right by a beautiful irrigation canal and this place reminded me of the serene back-waters in Kerala. I totally see myself retiring in a place like this!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M&amp;rsquo;s offer got rescinded because of the hiring freeze. Super bummed but I guess the writing was on the wall. Well, at least there&amp;rsquo;s a bit more clarity now and we can plan our home leave together. The new administration is pushing quite a changes. I&amp;rsquo;m all for productivity and efficiency but I don&amp;rsquo;t quite think they really see or understand the scope of what they&amp;rsquo;re pushing out. With direct impacts, for now it&amp;rsquo;s a wait and act game!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the Matamoros TDY done, I can now shift gears at work and throttle up the check-out procedures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Someone added &lt;em&gt;Cliffs of Dover&lt;/em&gt; to the Barnyard Burger&amp;rsquo;s Jukebox. Been years that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard this song! &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/31/matamoros/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
