<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vivekananda-Memorial on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/vivekananda-memorial/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vivekananda-Memorial on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/vivekananda-memorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sunrise at the confluence</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/10/15/sunrise-at-the-confluence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/10/15/sunrise-at-the-confluence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;@ Kanyakumari, India&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A glimpse of sunrise at the tip of the Indian subcontinent, where the Arabian Sea and the Bay of Bengal meet the Indian Ocean. Tourists throng to this overlook, right behind the Bagvathi Amman temple at the break of dawn (and the onset of dusk).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vivekananda memorial continues to be one of those few locations to be maintained sparking clean. Nothing much seems to have changed since my last visit to this place seven years ago. The shrouded Thiruvalluvar statue that&amp;rsquo;s to the far right talks volumes of the current political situation in the state. The ferry no longer stops at the statue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Appa&amp;rsquo;s 81st birthday (official). He had that sparkle in his eye&amp;rsquo;s when he was looking up to the sun rise above the horizon. Despite this being such a rushed trip, I&amp;rsquo;m so glad we could get him here. Climbing up one of the stairs on the Vivekananda memorial he mentioned this would probably be his last visit. Was quite disturbing to see him struggle through something that&amp;rsquo;s always been second nature. With old age his mobility seems to be drastically reducing. Hope over the next few years, we&amp;rsquo;re able to find better means of taking him to more places outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/favorite?tweet_id=920796903759011841&#34;&gt;like&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?tweet_id=920796903759011841&#34;&gt;reply&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/retweet?tweet_id=920796903759011841&#34;&gt;repost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
