<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CDMX on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/cdmx/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in CDMX on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 15:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/cdmx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mari Gold</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/25/mari-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/25/mari-gold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NO &lt;a href=&#34;https://guide.michelin.com/us/en/ciudad-de-mexico/miguel-hidalgo_1999281/restaurant/mari-gold&#34;&gt;Mari Gold&lt;/a&gt; ! You don&amp;rsquo;t get to call - a wrap of leaf salad drizzled with vinagarette and some flavorless yam, doused in running egg yolk - a KATHI ROLL! Such a disgrace! Wasn&amp;rsquo;t too excited about going here initially and now I&amp;rsquo;m more than convinced not to look back once.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/25/mari-gold/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La Malinche hike</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/19/la-malinche-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/19/la-malinche-hike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I type this note, my right forefinger has a sensation I&amp;rsquo;ve never felt before. It&amp;rsquo;s mildly numb yet fully functional. M tells me later this evening maybe a nerve is probably still chilling in there. Maybe this is how frostbite feels?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earlier this morning Adam, Jacob and I head out from the cabin around 0150 towards the Malinche trailhead. M checked with some of the locals in town last evening and they mentioned most guided hikes start around 0200 to get to the peak in time for sunrise. We decided to go without a guide since the trail was straightforward and I was reasonably optimistic I could guide the group myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful 3/4 moon night and the moonlight is just sufficient to light most of our path. With temperature skirting just around freezing, Adam realizes he&amp;rsquo;s forgotten his second jacket. We head back to the cabin,grab it and get back to the trail. Around 20 minutes in, we lose the trail. Only later on our way back will we realise that this trail atleast initially switches in and out of the emergency paved route that winds up close to the summit. Thankfully we notice hikers headlamps flashing on the actual trail and bushwack our way to the correct path.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With my right knee in not a great condition, I&amp;rsquo;d warned the boys we&amp;rsquo;d be taking this one slow. The path is relentlessly demanding with a steady 30&amp;rsquo; gradient. We had to cover about 4500 ft. elevation gain in about 4 hrs if we wanted to catch sunrise at the summit. We take breaks as needed but keep a decent steady pace. About 1.5hrs in, Malinche reveals itself right in between the foliage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/MalincheFirstSight.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Malinche by the moonlight&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At about 0545, ~13862ft, it feels as if there&amp;rsquo;s a sudden cold front. We layer up as we get to the alpine zone. The scree is mostly frozen and there&amp;rsquo;s quite some ice patches on the path. Neither Adam nor Jacob had brought their gloves. I smack myself for not checking with them before we left the cabin. The three of us take turns sharing the single pair of gloves I had and truck along - one step in front of another. Slowly but surely the summit comes to our line of sight. There&amp;rsquo;re maybe about 70/80 people already trying to summit ahead of us - their headlamps glimmering in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Malinche0500.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Malinche summit about 500ft away&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At around 0600 and 14108ft, we hit a narrow bottleneck with a slick ice patch slowing people down. I&amp;rsquo;m beyond concerned none of them are wearing microspikes or crampons. Well, Adam and Jacob don&amp;rsquo;t have it too. Adam mentioned his shoe didn&amp;rsquo;t have much grip either! I hand him over my microspikes and we head a bit further up. At this point, I&amp;rsquo;m mentally prepared to turn around and flag this to both of them. My main concern was the cold and us not having the right gear to make our way back. With dawn kicking in, ice melt was imminent and there was no way we&amp;rsquo;d be able to safely get down. We decide to trot up a bit more and hit another bottleneck around the knife-edge that would give us direct view of the summit. About ~400 ft maybe and the summit was right there. On our turn, Adam and Jacob are able to barely make it up the pivot and I&amp;rsquo;m constantly slipping - with no microspikes. Decide to call it a day and turn around. The boys aren&amp;rsquo;t super happy with the decision but agree. On the way down we see a taste of what we&amp;rsquo;d have to endure had we continued on. But for a few minor slips we make it below the alpine range.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/MalicheProxySummit.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Maliche Proxy Summit&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, this weekend, Deepa was hiking Nevado De Toluca and Jordan was doing a multi summit hike to Izta and Pico de Orizaba. We&amp;rsquo;d hear later that they had conducive conditions and were able to summit the peaks just as planned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/MalinchePano.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Maliche Pano&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/OrizabaByDawn.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Orizaba by Dawn&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We make it back to the Malintzi Cabin around 0945. A quick breakfast and we make our way back to CDMX around 1400. The stay at the cabin was great and I&amp;rsquo;m so glad we decided to stay overnight here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Malinche off my list now, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty undecided on Orizaba. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably give it a bit more thought after the Matamoros trip.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/19/la-malinche-hike/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carlos&#39; wedding</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/29/carlos-wedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/29/carlos-wedding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided not to drive to GDL for Carlos&amp;rsquo; wedding. Just not comfortable driving the GV until we get it properly serviced. Thankfully, we got a flight last minute and we head straight to the GDL zoo after landing. S has been wanting to see the penguins there for quite sometime now and what better opportunity than this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The zoo was immaculately maintained! And with the Sky-cables and trains, this was such a great experience. We checked in at the AC hotel for some short down time and then head to an Arabic restaurant for some pretty delicious wraps because we were quite certain M wouldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything vegetarian at the wedding. The wedding per se was super intimate with about 30 guests. I am glad we were able to fit this in despite a pretty packed end of the year. We head back to the hotel around 1145 just about when S was nearing her &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m done&lt;/em&gt; limit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/carlos_gdl.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next morning, we head to the vegan restaurant that M had scouted for a quick breakfast and get to the GDL airport just in time for the flight back to CDMX.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/29/carlos-wedding/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Las Estacas</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/las-estacas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 23:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/las-estacas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;V+D were visiting us for a few days around Christmas this year. With the 24th declared a holiday, M suggested we go glamping in Estacas for a night. S loved the idea and we booked two tents for the five of us. Cost was super reasonable given it included breakfast and entry to the park.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/estacas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We only got to Estacas around 1400 on 24th evening thanks to the four hours we lost to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/&#34;&gt;brake fade on the Grand Vitara&lt;/a&gt;. After a quick check-in, we decide to rent a kayak and row down the stream. I hop off the kayak and swim upstream. S was bent on going to the kids pool alone and not getting into the spring. After about an hour, S &amp;amp; I head to the kids pool. She spends maybe 30 mins in there and calls it a day. Her only ask was that we have dinner by the spring, which we gladly agree to since that&amp;rsquo;s the only restaurant that was open. After dinner, S was sleepy but still super excited about spending the night in the tent. Happy kid, Happy camper! She sleeps through the night despite all the Christmas fireworks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/shas_estacas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We wake up to a super crisp and nippy 25th morning. V and I decide to snorkel/swim in the warm 23C spring water. We spot some sleeping turtles and a great many schools of fish feasting on their morning find. After a simple yet delicious breakfast we make our way back to CDMX. Probably one of our best stays in Estacas so far and I&amp;rsquo;m so glad we decided to glamp! Though S didn&amp;rsquo;t get into the spring, she absolutely enjoyed our trip. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/las-estacas/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merida</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/20/merida/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/20/merida/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back from a productive work trip in Merida. Overall, I think it went great. Most of the planning over the last few months paid off and but for a few minor issues, we were able top wrap up coring the NCC in about three days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also found a few fantastic food options through the week. For lunch we mostly had to do an Uber eats since there weren&amp;rsquo;t many options around the new consulate. &lt;a href=&#34;https://habaneros.com.mx/&#34;&gt;Habaneros&lt;/a&gt; was the find of the week though. Their &lt;em&gt;Pimitos&lt;/em&gt; was on point!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This would most likely be my last work-trip to Merida. Time for some transition planning to hand the baton over.&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/20/merida/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bacalar</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/18/bacalar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/18/bacalar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;BacalarLagoon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cenote Negro&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bacalar has been on our travel list for quite sometime now. Between work travel, syncing our individual schedules and just getting around to actually booking the trip; we finally get around visiting this beautiful place this weekend in November.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we get off the plane, we&amp;rsquo;re immediately hit by a waft of the Yucatán humidity, soon followed by thick droplets of rain. Strikes me just then that we&amp;rsquo;re also right in the midst of the hurricane season. A quick lookup on the weather forecast reveals Hurricane Sara would be swinging past us and into the Gulf of Mexico in a bit. I slap myself on my wrist for not doing any research beforehand but also shrug this &lt;em&gt;minor&lt;/em&gt; oversight very quickly. How bad could it actually be? Maybe some showers here and there? We walk outside the Chetumal airport for about 500m and take a taxi from the main road to Bacalar. Oscar offers to take us there for 550 pesos. This was about 50 pesos shy of the amount the tour planner had quoted. M immediately accepts and we&amp;rsquo;re on our way. First impressions of this place immediately remind me of Trivandrum - lush green vistas with coconut trees strewn all around, narrow roads and barely any traffic. There&amp;rsquo;s construction for Tren Maya happening along the route but it barely impacts our drive. In about 50 minutes we reach the hotel and check-in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S immediately comments on the smell of wood as we enter our room. She&amp;rsquo;s ambivalent of the smell but seems to love the room setup. She goes around exploring the windows and shower. Once we get settled in, we head out to explore the property a bit. Hotel Carolina looks good with the woodsy feel and being right on the lagoon - but it definitely feels more commercial than I had imagined it to be. Yet another slap on the wrist. Note to self not to go by just pictures next time around. Maybe this trip planner thing is not quite working for us? This is the first time in all these years we&amp;rsquo;re using one - An embassy colleague&amp;rsquo;s wife runs a dive business and plans trips for folks across central America. We thought we&amp;rsquo;d give her a shot for this trip. Anyways, the stomach rumbles and we head over to Mango y Chile - a quaint vegan restaurant right by &lt;em&gt;Fuerte de San Filipe&lt;/em&gt; about 30 minutes walk from the hotel. The burgers and smoothies here are super delicious and we finish it off with some paletas. M&amp;rsquo;s restaurant picks barely go wrong! Back to the room and we settle down for the night.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around 0730 we stir awake and quickly get ready for the day. Plan is to head over to the fort to meet out boat captain who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to take us for a two hour ride in the lagoon. M messages the tour operator to check if the plan is still on since it&amp;rsquo;s super gloomy and heavy outside. She confirms and we head over to the fort. Just as we get to the fort, the skies let loose and the Boat captain gives us news that the police have closed the port for the day. We&amp;rsquo;re obviously disappointed and decide to grab a quick bite closer to the hotel. I offer to carry S on my shoulders as we make our way back in the pouring rain. The roads are flooded and the rain isn&amp;rsquo;t showing any signs of letting go. Love this walk back and it&amp;rsquo;s been quite sometime that we&amp;rsquo;ve actually done this! Some good breakfast at Noru&amp;rsquo;s and we make our way back to the hotel. M suggests we should probably consider getting back to CDMX that afternoon. Unfortunately, there are no tickets available on the flight. With that decision made for us, we decide to head back out for lunch at &lt;em&gt;Enamora&lt;/em&gt;. Food here&amp;rsquo;s okay. As we make our way back to the hotel, the weather clears up a bit. S wanted to head to the kids pool and we nudge her to try out the swing in the water. &lt;em&gt;Sara&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; effect lingers and the water is super choppy. We try getting the kayak out for a bit but aren&amp;rsquo;t quite successful. Back to the room and we spend some good time in the portico by the hammock. After we&amp;rsquo;re back from dinner at &lt;em&gt;Noru&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt;, I nudge S to head back to the wooden pier by the lagoon. We spend some time here as the sun sets and S plays with the idea of getting the kayak out. She flips it over in an instant and wants me to get in the water instead. The water does seem way calmer and I hop in to explore the waters. This impromptu wade in was probably one of the highlight&amp;rsquo;s for the day. We head back to the room. S spends some more time on the hammock and quickly falls asleep. M and I tinker with the idea of taking the kayak out the next morning to explore the lagoon by ourselves. As I type this at 0326 on Monday, I&amp;rsquo;m actually super psyched about this plan. Hoping S is game doing this in a few hours!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;BacalarSwing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And she is! We quickly change over in the morning and take to the waters. The weather is just right - Dark clouds hanging above and rays of sunshine creeping down. The water is much calmer and we&amp;rsquo;re near Cenote Negro in no time. We wade in the waters for about an hour and steal a few more minutes by the swing. Around 1030 we finally checkout and head to the airport after a brief breakfast stop at &lt;em&gt;Ajal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While we didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get to explore the whole lagoon, I&amp;rsquo;m so glad we ended up staying for the extra day. Overall S thoroughly enjoyed the water and just lazing in the hammock. Lesson learnt though that we are best at planning our own trips and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to head to Baja California later this December!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sixth</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/11/sixth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/11/sixth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;Sixth.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S celebrated her 6th today.  Unicorn themed - of course - and had her first and probably last ever Piñata. But for a mega meltdown initially she did great all through the event.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, we signed up for a Diwali party organized by the Indian Association in Mexico. Primarily on a whim and maybe for the food? The event was last evening and boy, it was a terrible disappointment! It started late as expected. And obnoxiously loud for no reason. Not quite sure if it was the acoustics at the venue or just the MC shouting into the mic.  Maybe both? I love some good rock and metal. I love some good loud music. But I guess not all loud is the same. Also, this day and age, who even does a looping slideshow of pictures of people organizing the event? Dinner was supposed to be served by 1900. Servers said they had orders to serve only at 2030. Maybe the organizers wanted the food to be served only after the main event? When we rechecked at 2030, they said it was pushed to 2130. Had enough of it and walked out.  People were still on the dance floor and there was a good turn out. I guess this kinda boisterous social mayhem is just not my jam?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We head out to a Japanese (?) restaurant in Polanco since Nimi&amp;rsquo;s, Mei Mei and Manaw were all closed for service. Sushi was &lt;em&gt;meh&lt;/em&gt;. S did great all through the evening though despite the loud music and the crowd. That &amp;lsquo;Sticker by number&amp;rsquo; book that she received as a gift from Maddy kept her fully occupied!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Monday morning here and S is off for school. She was mildly upset that I get to stay at home while she needs to go to school. Fair world logic, I guess. We drop her and get to spend a couple hours together watching &lt;em&gt;Spenser Confidential&lt;/em&gt;. Enjoyed it all the more because we recognized quite a few locations where the movie was shot. M&amp;rsquo;s got some brunch out with the ladies in a bit and then a couple more hours before I need to pick up S. Maybe I should tweak that 3D printer?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basilica de Guadalupe</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/02/basilica-de-guadalupe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/02/basilica-de-guadalupe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;BasilicaDeGuadalupe.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spent most of this morning at the Basilica de Guadalupe. This photo does not do enough justice to how much this old church is actually falling apart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tula and Tepozotlan</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/28/tula-and-tepozotlan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/28/tula-and-tepozotlan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;tula-ruins.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Took a couple days off work for a short break. M flagged a quick trip to the Tula ruins. Just about a couple hours from the city, these ruins were a nice quick visit. There was barely anybody out here as opposed to the crowds at the Teotihuacán pyramids. On the way back we did a quick stop in Tepozotlan for brunch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once back in the city, S wanted to roller blade and we head to Parque Americana for some good wheel time. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad we got these rollers! I&amp;rsquo;m definitely getting better at it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dia de muertos ride</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/26/dia-de-muertos-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/26/dia-de-muertos-ride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;Diademuertosride.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Took the bike out for a spin right after the CLO trick or treat. Reforma and parts of Centro Historico were closed out for the monthly night ride and this one coincided with Dia de muertos. Quite a few people showed up and most of the route was a huge bicycle jam. Nevertheless some good time out on the roads in the nippy weather. Clocked around 11 miles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand Vitara</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/06/08/grand-vitara/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 19:32:32 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/06/08/grand-vitara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brought the Grand Vitara home today. We’d been on the lookout for a decent car ever since we knew about our next posting. We don’t need one here in CDMX but would definitely need one in Yaounde. All I wanted was a reliable bare minimum car with no gadgetry shabangs. Over the last few months folks on their PCS did post a few decent cars but these are barely in the market for a few hours. With this one though, the stars seemed to align all well one day and we were able to seal the deal in a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given the mileage, the GV might need some maintenance over the next few years. It rides like butter now though and reminds me of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://0.0.0.0:8123/2016/04/26/the-grand-cherokee/&#34;&gt;Grand Cherokee&lt;/a&gt; we had in NYC/BOS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BMG</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/06/03/bmg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 21:00:36 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/06/03/bmg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://0.0.0.0:8123/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/imagepipe_04348564902056275560.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Went to a Blue Man Group performance last Friday. Our first and most likely last. The drums were great but the theatrics left a lot to be desired. Also didn’t help that S was in one of her super emotional moods…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nevado de Toluca</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/23/nevado-de-toluca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/23/nevado-de-toluca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this, sick to the core at 0300, rallying between sweating out the sheets and freezing to the bones. It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough couple days. Oddly enough I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel one ounce of pain during the alpine hike I did on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240422_163850.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We summited Nevado de Toluca on Saturday and this would be one of my best hikes so far. Just two hours from Mexico city, this hike has something for everybody. First off, just getting to the alpine lakes from the base, which takes about 20 minutes, opens out the playground. One can literally see the whole terrain and trails that surround the pristine alpine lakes. We decide to head clockwise and summit Pico del Fraile (15388&amp;rsquo;). The climb up is reasonably straighforward and its mostly choosing your path to get to the peak.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240420_105952-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once at the peak, instead of scrambling downhill to the lakes, we decide to complete the loop and summit all the other peaks in that circuit. For the next 4 hours we&amp;rsquo;re trapezing the peaks, scrambling up and down paths of our choosing. It&amp;rsquo;s windy but not unreasonably cold. A thunderstorm looms further on one of the peaks and as we make plans to find cover under the rocks a mild hail storm hits us. Thankfully, our helmets protect us and we make decent progress towards the other peaks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240420_183656-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sound of conch shells and drums give us constant company - From high up here at 15000&amp;rsquo; we see a group of about 30 people performing some ritual near one of the alpine lakes. As we push for the final descent we somehow loose our trail. All we&amp;rsquo;re left with is super loose soil and huge stones at a 80° gradient. There&amp;rsquo;s barely any grip here and we&amp;rsquo;re at the mercy of luck as we make our way down. Finally at around 1500 we reach the base and wait for the transport truck to take us down to the actual base.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This hike was such a contrast to Izta. Izta felt like just a suffer fest with barely any rewards while Toluca offered some terrific views right from the start. I&amp;rsquo;d repeat this hike in a heartbeat!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024-04-20 07:39:31 - &lt;strong&gt;Nevado de Toluca&lt;/strong&gt; 🥾 Hiked 6.07 miles in 06:39:57 Pace : 65.89 min/mile. Elevation Gain : 2611 ft. Elevation Loss : 2613 ft. Calories : 1037 Location : Toluca 💓 : 90&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pico de Águila</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/14/pico-de-%C3%A1guila/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/14/pico-de-%C3%A1guila/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/signal-2024-04-14-17-12-24-029-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S was having a rough day on Saturday and was scrunched up against me all day. Around 1900 I checked my work phone and saw that Mo had texted earlier that morning asking if I would be interested in hiking Pico de Aguilar the next day. I wanted to confirm immediately but given S&amp;rsquo;s health I wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite sure. Decided to take a call the next morning and hit the bed. Thankfully, on Sunday morning, S seemed to have almost recovered and I decide to head out to meet Mo at his place. With some starting troubles (literally!) we finally leave for Ajusco around 0830.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The drive up is super straightforward and we park at the trailhead around 1000. We decide to take on the steeper parts of the climb first going clockwise. Around 1200 we reach Pico de Águila (12596&amp;rsquo;) and in another 30 minutes we summit Cerro La Cruz del Marquez (12871&amp;rsquo;). The way down from the Cerro was super steep at an 82° gradient. So glad we decided not to climb up from here and note to self to bring a knee brace for these downhills next time I hike here in CDMX. The loose volcanic soil and incessant pebbles make for dicey path downhill. We finish the hike at around 1400 and relish some hot cakes at one of the shacks at the base.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than anything, this hike was a major morale booster after last weeks Izta attempt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024-04-14 09:43:52 - &lt;strong&gt;Pico de Águila et Cerro La Cruz del Marquez&lt;/strong&gt; 🥾 Hiked 4.69 miles in 04:50:29 Pace : 61.94 min/mile. Elevation Gain : 2405 ft. Elevation Loss : 2384 ft. Calories : 1810 Location : La Magdalena Contreras 💓 : 152&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Globo aerostático</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/04/globo-aerost%C3%A1tico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/04/globo-aerost%C3%A1tico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some good time up in the air above the Teotihuacán pyramids. Flight was super smooth and with us landing right over a cactus field, the ending was even better!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/imagepipe_705734486179367623137.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  title=&#34;Teotihuacán hot air balloon&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
