<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2008-01-06 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/date/2008-01-06-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2008-01-06 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/date/2008-01-06-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Rainmaker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/01/06/the-rainmaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/01/06/the-rainmaker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some reason of late, I take quite some time to read novels. How gripping it is really doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I finish a chapter or two and set it aside. Probably it&amp;rsquo;s just about rekindling that thrill to get back to it later for the next read ;-) !&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I just finished reading a very old  novel of John Grisham - The Rainmaker. One of his best writings, I would say. It&amp;rsquo;s about a law student by name Rudy Baylor fighting against a big time Insurance Company for it&amp;rsquo;s insensitiveness to one of its well deserving insuree. Just having passed the bar, this is one of his first few cases. To make things worse, Great Benefit - the insurance firm deploys a reputed lawyer to fight for them. Things get murky as days pass, making him wonder if at all he did the right choice in running up with the case. Amidst all this, he happens to meet a female Kelly , who&amp;rsquo;s tortured by her husband, in a hospital where he&amp;rsquo;s scouting for more cases. This is where the rafu chakkar starts :-) ! After a long tedious trial, he finally manages to win the suit for his client in a flamboyant manner but the irony is that the parent company of Great Benefit manages to wash it&amp;rsquo;s hands off leading to Great Benefit&amp;rsquo;s bankruptcy. Neither Baylor nor his client get what they&amp;rsquo;re legally bound to. Vexed with how things turned out he leaves Memphis and Law for good with Kelly!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way Grisham brings about the story is just fabulous! The courtroom trials , the emotions that he evokes and for the most part of it  the determination of Baylor that he consistently loops in, is just great. Definitely a great read!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;His latest book - The Appeal seems to be as much promising. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if i can lay my hands on it sometime this week.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
