<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021-07-15 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2021-07-15-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021-07-15 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2021-07-15-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guacamole - Clientless Remote Desktop access</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/07/15/guacamole-clientless-remote-desktop-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/07/15/guacamole-clientless-remote-desktop-access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://anydesk.com/en&#34;&gt;Anydesk&lt;/a&gt; for a while now to remote into my NUC workstation. It works great but for one big downside - It needs you to install the tool on both machines.  While looking for alternatives, I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://guacamole.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Guacamole&lt;/a&gt; which is a clientless remote desktop gateway. Set it up on the server and you can access your desktops now from any browser! So technically, If needed I could access my workstation even from a hand held device. All I need is a browser that supports HTML5!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It literally took me five minutes to set this up. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick run-through:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/compose/install/&#34;&gt;Docker-compose&lt;/a&gt; if you don&amp;rsquo;t have that setup already&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If the server is a linux machine and you need remote desktop access, now might be a good time to check and install xrdp: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install xrdp -y&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fetch the docker-compose file &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/reisbel/guacamole-docker-compose&#34;&gt;from here&lt;/a&gt; and follow instructions in the readme. You&amp;rsquo;re essentially setting up the postgres database and then spinning up the guac and guacd containers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the containers are up and running, your Guacamole server should be available at &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:8080/guacamole/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a functional server, lets tweak the settings to make this a bit client-ready:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change the default login/password - duh!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Navigate to Settings &amp;gt; Connections and add a new connection.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Under Edit Connection, add in a name and select &lt;strong&gt;RDP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scroll down to Parameters and fill in details for your network and authentication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/image-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scroll all the way down and save. That&amp;rsquo;s it! As you&amp;rsquo;d see there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://guacamole.apache.org/doc/gug/configuring-guacamole.html#rdp&#34;&gt;quite a few parameters&lt;/a&gt; that you can define for each connection. The above should however be sufficient to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that you have the server setup and the connections defined, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to connect to the machines directly from any browser within the same network. Navigate to http://&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;:8080/guacamole, login and based on your configuration you will be either connected to the server directly or provided the option to choose from the connections available. To access the machine from a different network, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to tunnel through which I&amp;rsquo;ll probably cover in a follow-up post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
