<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2017-06-19 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2017-06-19-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2017-06-19 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2017-06-19-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning to breathe</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/06/19/learning-to-breathe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/06/19/learning-to-breathe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First ashtanga class at Down Under Yoga and it felt SO FREAKING GOOD! Started off with a short chant and dived straight into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jasonyoga.com/wp-content/uploads/sun_salutes_A_breaths.jpg&#34;&gt;Sun Salutations A&lt;/a&gt;. The first few rounds felt pretty straight forward. But then pretty quickly I found it really hard to keep track of my breathing and the sequence. I was asked to watch as Meena and another fogi (fellow yogi) moved over to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jasonyoga.com/wp-content/uploads/Suns_B_minimal_names_510.jpg&#34;&gt;Sun Salutations B&lt;/a&gt;. After they practiced that for a bit, We moved over to the lotus position. Some good shoulder stretch and body holds (names of which I don&amp;rsquo;t quite remember now!) and we closed out the session with a long &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shavasana&#34;&gt;Shavasana&lt;/a&gt;. The heat in the room and the consistent nasal breathing had me sweating loads by the end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m consciously working on improving my breathing and working on my core and with this brief exposure to Ashtanga, I&amp;rsquo;m psyched about its tremendous benefits. With mandated early AM classes at least thrice a week, It&amp;rsquo;s going to be a huge time commitment. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be an interesting few weeks initially as we try and work out our new schedule. Truly excited to see this through!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/cropped-cropped-SP01-550afdebv1_site_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com&#34;&gt;Srikanth Perinkulam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
