<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/teaching/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>El Campeonato | March 17th 0800hrs | Mystic land of Epiphany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/03/12/el-campeonato-march-17th-0800hrs-mystic-land-of-epiphany/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/03/12/el-campeonato-march-17th-0800hrs-mystic-land-of-epiphany/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some things are just worth fighting for. Some are just worth dying for. More so when legends need to be told and champions honed. This championship is what we believe is the beginning of the end of a school of thought.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE CHAMPIONSHIP:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A day long intra-class athletic championship. Just sports. No books. No gyan - Just before the examinations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHO&amp;rsquo;S INVOLVED:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Pegasus, the Dragons and the Unicorns from the mysterious land of the epiphany dynasty-each with 15 members chosen to handle their intra-team dynamics while fighting it out on the ground for their team&amp;rsquo;s honour.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-at-stake&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT&amp;rsquo;S AT STAKE?:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Gladiators shield of honor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be awarded to the team that shows outstanding team work and fights it out on the ground meeting all objectives and abiding by all the rules of the championship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Outstanding Champions Trophy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be awarded to the champion who plays to the tune of his/her heart and abides by the rules of the championship while not sacrificing his/her duty to the team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;El Campeonato nomination for the Annual Scholarship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An athletic nomination entry awarded to the champion who embodies the true spirit of sportsmanship. This nomination would enable the champion to compete in the final rung for a scholarship that would partially waive his/her next years academic fees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participation and Performance certificates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENTS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Drills&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Speed Workouts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kabaddi&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Amoeba race&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Relay race&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Obstacle crossing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rationale behind El Campeonato:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;March is generally a testing time for teachers and students. With end of year examinations round the corner and in an academic setup during times such as this,  it would be surprising to find the staff room void of any discussions around the projected &amp;lsquo;pass rate&amp;rsquo; of the students. Besides, with the direct and indirect interactions with a networked group of teachers that we have here, most of the discussions are about the end of year examinations.That is where Kavitha and I found the disconnect. We just couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why the last few weeks before the examination had to be so stressful on the kids and their parents. Revision in the last moment just before the examinations and the data emanating from this process system wouldn&amp;rsquo;t really give a gauge of the students academic capabilities. More so the data from these examinations  just remain figures in paper or data projections that grossly are invalid given the scope of these so called examinations. We for one didn&amp;rsquo;t want the kids to pass through a cycle of unnecessary strain period - something that we were compelled to go through during our &amp;rsquo;education&amp;rsquo; phase.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this theory that is highly talked about in the circles here that academic achievement is what motivates kids to excel in other learning streams - yet another school of thought that we couldn&amp;rsquo;t digest. Through the second year, we focused our instructions more towards constructive learning than just based on formative or summative data analysis.  Eventually the time that the kids spent outdoors became almost equal to the time they spent indoors. Probably that is what led us to formulating this championship - El Campeonato. This by no means is the &amp;lsquo;mandated&amp;rsquo; showcase. It&amp;rsquo;s just a platform for us as teachers to explore what holistic learning could mean, a platform for the kids to participate in the essence of team work and patience; not to compete just to win but to also learn by losing. As the baton passes, only time would tell what will last&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event details:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Be there at our school premises at 0800hrs sharp on the 17th of March to see our dragons, unicorns and the Pegasus compete to win the Gladiators trophy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bring your own drinks and snacks to beat the march sun, for its going to be one long exciting day with lots of fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ammi-Abba race</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/02/16/the-ammi-abba-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/02/16/the-ammi-abba-race/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of this term, we&amp;rsquo;ve been making a conscious effort to get the kids down to the playground and smell some dust. Early this month as we were trying to infuse the elements of team work in them, we decided to get them to do the &amp;lsquo;Amoeba race&amp;rsquo;. After a brief description of &amp;lsquo;Amoeba&amp;rsquo; we got the kids down to the ground and flagged the race.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[vimeo &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/36854058&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/36854058&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Later the next day, when asked to recollect the name- One kid pops up and innocently transliterates it as Ammi Abba!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery link=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo; columns=&amp;ldquo;8&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emotions and Equations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/12/16/emotions-and-equations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/12/16/emotions-and-equations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was it the impeccable sound system? Was it the unwavering emotions in the song? Was it the crowd or was it the realization of the importance of the whole event. Some days are just worth living. Today is one of those.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kids had their annual day showcase today and as I walked out after their performance, the immense gratification of being a teacher of 45 little brats peaked to the top. If anything could come anywhere close to the feeling of jumping off a flight and free falling It had to be this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The theme of the Annual day this year was Love, Peace and Harmony.  We decided to do more of a musical than just a dance perfomance. The choreography, practice and rehearsals all in all took up over 15days - At times eating into class instructional time and at times post school hours. But I guess It was all truly worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watch the below videos as they ponder, enact, hope and bring to life the myriad emotions of being a part of the vicious circle of an army mans life. -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[vimeo &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/33801439&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/33801439&lt;/a&gt;] [vimeo &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/33801706&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/33801706&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what the kids have taken away from the whole experience and even if they truly understand what message the skit is conveying. I see no business in jutting my head in and getting them to reflect on it. All I see personally is that this WILL change the dynamics in the classroom right from Monday and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see that happen. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to head back to school to show them their performance and celebrate their hard work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Time to raise a toast. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m one proud teacher.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Midway to the Supreme Showcase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/01/midway-to-the-supreme-showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/01/midway-to-the-supreme-showcase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is it. We now have the data. We now have the proof. Two more units and we should be all set to perform in front of an audience 15000 strong. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://theepiphanydynasty.wordpress.com/projects/unit-wise-projects/unit-iii-projects/&#34; title=&#34;Unit 3 Projects&#34;&gt;THIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is the tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Three doctrines of Transitional Leadership</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/27/the-three-doctrines-of-transitional-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/27/the-three-doctrines-of-transitional-leadership/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[Pun intended]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Event management team in the Epiphany Dynasty decided to raise funds for their third unit projects. Besides organizing a movie showcase they also ran a sale of important commodities. Through these activities - under the hood- they formulated and exhibited the three doctrines of Transitional Leadership. Readers are advised to read through the doctrines first and then watch the videos for a comprehensive understanding.These are extremely profound and intellectual thoughts and are being shared by the rulers with nothing but a humble gesture to levitate humanity to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first doctrine of Transitional Leadership:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Event management team executing the first doctrine of Transitional leadership [Market for all its worth!] during a dry run in the classroom. To be a transitional leader in just two minutes watch as these rockstar leaders execute what they&amp;rsquo;ve learnt. If you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed something funny/something off the norms of regular business, You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to join the exclusive discussion forum in our classroom - We&amp;rsquo;re working on refining the doctrines.Who knows you could be the next guru in Transitional Leadership!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[vimeo &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vimeo.com/31186794&#34;&gt;http://www.vimeo.com/31186794&lt;/a&gt; w=398&amp;amp;h=299]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second doctrine of Transitional Leadership:&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rulers of the Epiphany dynasty figured that once you market your product you need to be up to speed in selling it. Time and timing is excruciatingly important and you need to be on your heels and watch out for competition. Integrity is vital and discipline makes or breaks your business. This short video encapsulates this doctrine in action. Of course this is a debatable topic and you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to thrash it out with the rulers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[vimeo &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vimeo.com/31187120&#34;&gt;http://www.vimeo.com/31187120&lt;/a&gt; w=398&amp;amp;h=299]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third doctrine of Transitional Leadership:&lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are always just three rules that govern everything in this world. So it is with Transitional Leadership. Performance under pressure is something that&amp;rsquo;s really important and you need to be on the top of things despite the constraints and limitations. The rulers figured out that deadlines are always round the corner and when you&amp;rsquo;re a top performer pressure is inevitable. Watch as the ruler of the Cholas empire leads by example in conveying this point. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[youtube &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b&lt;/a&gt;_vXIuG1EY8]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following the newly formulated rule book, the rulers made a whooping &lt;strong&gt;negative&lt;/strong&gt; profit of 498.00 INR.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is something that they&amp;rsquo;ve never done before and the hardwork and the lessons they&amp;rsquo;ve learned would immensely help them in formulating a new &amp;lsquo;biziness&amp;rsquo; theory. Well, isn&amp;rsquo;t that how you become a stalwart bania?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gearing up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/02/gearing-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/02/gearing-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow as the dawn cracks in, we&amp;rsquo;d be introducing our kids to their new projects for this unit. We plan to make this units showcase much better organised than the &lt;a href=&#34;http://theepiphanydynasty.wordpress.com/projects/unit-wise-projects/unit-2-projects/&#34;&gt;last one&lt;/a&gt; and give them a better support structure. We consciously decided to make do with their extra classes and just give them time to work with their teams on their projects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we had a roundup with the Kings and Queens and formulated an Event Management committee. The President and Secretary were elected, Various committees [ Logistics, Finance, Invite and Advt. and Marketing] were formed and tasks delegated. The kids are overwhelmed but I guess that&amp;rsquo;s where we really want to push them to. Project execution would begin from Tuesday onwards and they have just about 12 days to comprehend, execute, document and showcase their work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery columns=&amp;ldquo;8&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike the last unit, we decided to have just six project ideas -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Build a working model of a Reservoir and dam.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Build a prototype of a Hovercraft.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Build a candle propelled &amp;lsquo;Tuk-Tuk&amp;rsquo; boat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Build a fort.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paint the Library Trunks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diver in a bottle.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea is to have two kingdoms choose the same project and push them to compete against each other.Consistent self documentation would help them keep track of their progress and compare it with the other team. We&amp;rsquo;ve also given responsibility to the Event management team to raise funds to bear 50pc of the total expenses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just cant wait to voice this out to the whole class tomorrow. The showcase on 20th of October will spell out whats feasible and whats not but till then I guess all that&amp;rsquo;s going to help is impromptu revisions to the plans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of the playground…</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/10/dynamics-of-the-playground/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/10/dynamics-of-the-playground/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Couple of  hours back I opened my student tracker,  just sat back and started mulling over how each of my kids have changed over the past few months. As I went through the list reading each of the kids names, images of the kid kept flashing in and out of my mind and most of them, so turned out to be of those moments when they were being ecstatic or really happy. This made me wonder how we as humans tend to capture/remember only the positives or the cheerful part in our relationships. But as a teacher, am I not failing my kids in not noticing their negative behaviour and working to get them back to their normal self? Am I doing justice to them by not stopping what I’m doing and not taking that extra time to pay attention to that minuscule behavioral change? How many times have I swept a behavioral change under the blanket and continued with my class/session? How many times have I ‘neglected’ a kid in the rush to finish off a topic/objective?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sadly in retrospect I seem to recollect more than one occasions where I’ve failed noticing/paying heed to the change. This could probably be one of those reasons why a particular kid did not perform well in a particular objective; a reason why a particular kid did not receive me with the same enthusiasm as he otherwise would have and this is something I’m really beginning to appreciate in this role as a teacher. Every moment in the classroom you end up dealing with the emotions of 46 kids out there. Human to human interaction is the utmost priority. When I go back to my classroom in twenty days for the second term, this is one thing that I have to keep in mind always.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Talking by numbers, my kids have progressed from a class average of 25% to 56% in Math, from 17% to 59% in Grammar and from 28%[-0.1 Grade] to 85%[1.5 Grade] in RC. Thats some significant progress that the class has made. But again, the class average does not necessarily represent the overall growth of the classroom. There still are kids like – Sarfaraz, Nabil, Aditya More, Meghana and Yash Pawar who need to make tremendous progress if they have to be on par with the other kids. I guess that is where the main challenge lies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, I visualize my classroom as a circular board resting on a pivot. I being the pivot and the circular board,  a playground where my 46 little ones decide the dynamics of the classroom from inside. My responsibility is to  maintain the equilibrium and I need to be extremely flexible so as to adjust and re-position to the external stimuli and the dynamics created by my kids so that the whole system remains in equilibrium &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt;. The next fortnight I guess is all about figuring out how to maintain that equilibrium, about how I push myself to my limits of being flexible and making that transformation something sustainable…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections by the roadside…</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/10/reflections-by-the-roadside/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/10/reflections-by-the-roadside/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I take one last gulp of hot tea from a roadside stall, Ronnie wickedly smiles and brings his hand forward with a congratulatory gesture. He just says – ‘One month’ and grins wildly! I wink back, pay for the tea and walk back towards the school gate. As we quickly make our way through the puddles and pits in the slight Pune drizzle, my mind wanders out in search of those small moments that I could call ‘achievements’ of the month thats been from my one month of teachers life. Sadly I get to recollect just a couple of them. And then it looms on me again how important it is to appreciate minuscule milestones in this journey – Something which I’ve been working hard on ever since the summer school.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today for some reason, I’m not really as happy as I should have been. Administered a diagnostic test today and a perfunctory look at the sheets sunk me deeper in the gravel. These kids are just not able to answer even bare simple questions. I’ve spent about 23 whole days with these 46 kids and things do not really seem to be on the green side. Classroom and Behavior management still seems to be an issue and objectives wise I haven’t progressed much. They seem to understand Math concepts but for some reason that is just not translating onto the answer sheets. Collectively they seem to know how to reach to the solution but when asked individually they just put up a poker face. English for them seems to be a magnanimous monster lurching right round the corner. I’m yet to figure out where that small invisible spark exists so that I can magically tap it on and fire them up to speed. A couple of strategies to be implemented and a lot more are to be learnt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow marks a new beginning of looking back and taking the best of what worked; of paying attention and appreciating the minute ‘eureka’ moments in the classroom and not to forget – of understanding how close I could get to build the bridge between possibility, predictability and uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The battle so far</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/10/the-battle-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/10/the-battle-so-far/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just about a month that the second academic year has started. The past four weeks have been really hectic juggling the plethora of tasks left on the table. The kids have slowly started getting back to the regular schedules and attendance is almost touching 100 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The much needed break that I took hiking up the Himalayas and the internship at the TFI Summer institute gave a fresh perspective to the second academic year that I would be spending with the kids. Back in the holidays I was both optimistic and jittery about the maturity factor that I was expecting to see in the kids. Compared to last year they now seem to be much more on their toes and have got quite restless.It takes much more patience and effort to get their attention and even more a challenge to retain it. Wondering why, I could corner upon a couple of reasons - They&amp;rsquo;ve just not yet got out of their holiday mood, the afternoon summer camp is taxing them out or the more worrying concern - something is just not working in the classroom properly. The second year, at least the first quarter seems to be much more demanding in terms of investment and classroom management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On another front, this year we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to push them in both academics and extra curricular as far as possible. We&amp;rsquo;re rolling out &lt;a href=&#34;http://theepiphanydynasty.wordpress.com/projects/&#34; title=&#34;Projects&#34;&gt;several projects&lt;/a&gt; for them and holding them accountable to three supreme goals that we&amp;rsquo;ve set. Exposing them to various opportunities available and training them to be self dependent is something that&amp;rsquo;s bang up on the list.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Funnily, the year has just started.but every time I walk into the classroom reality looms in as to how little time [Just about 8 months!] we&amp;rsquo;re left with to accomplish all that we&amp;rsquo;ve planned out for them. As time progresses, hopefully things would get a bit more concrete.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When a Dynasty is born...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/10/when-a-dynasty-is-born.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/10/when-a-dynasty-is-born.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yet another day was coming to an end and the people of the land were tending their chores. It was all one peaceful ambiance with just minor disruptions here and there.  To help manage the affairs, the architect of the land decided to pull up a few responsible men and women and give them the authority to administer sections of the land..Well, ‘Decentralization of power’ as they call it. And then, things changed. With just one word, rose eleven kingdoms all powerful and energetic. And within minutes, the Kings and Queens swore at the altar to uprise their just formed kingdoms. Ministers, Treasurers and Soldiers were deputed and responsibilities bestowed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since then, things have drastically improved. The men and women now have something really concrete to look forward to – a structure, a pattern and above all rejoice in the powers that they otherwise would not have. There’s now an aura of peace in the empire and the subjects seem to be showing quite some interest in strengthening their kingdoms.  As days progress, the architect is still working out the finer details as to how the empires could be allowed to rule in mutual peace and still compete with each other for mutual benefit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Class of IIA at Epiphany- Where we play the Age of Empires with real Kings, Queens and Ministers!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking back, it’s kind of funny how just a random idea seems to be making so much of an impact on the kids. Ever since we divided the classroom into groups and gave them this theme to build upon, things have quite changed. Behavior management in the classroom has tremendously improved and almost every objective that is taught, once related to the theme even in some abstract form is investing the kids so much. It has also given scope to introduce an awesome value system in the class, which I’ve been trying in vain for the past 8 months to integrate in my regular classes. This coming friday, if things work well, I hopefully would be able to introduce them to the barter system and eventually trade and commerce. The options seem endless…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While biking back home today, I wonder why this idea didn’t strike me when I was scouting for a proper theme for my class late June, last year. There’s just about 25 instructional days left for this academic year to come to an end and I probably could have invested them a bit more had things ‘clicked’ before. But well, I guess thats just the feeling of not doing enough, that every teacher experiences every single day in his/her life. Really hoping this new system evolves into a robust framework and also if nothing works, I still can now be proud of founding eleven dynasties, not just in my dreams but in reality!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brain Gate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/09/brain-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/09/brain-gate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Asked the kids to form a song/poem for their kingdom. This is what one of the teams came up with in fifteen minutes!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read: Our team love me so much. I also love them. Thank you. Math Oh Math you are so great. I know this addition so how much I eating I can tell the time so I dont get late. Math I love so much it has open my brain gate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home visit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/09/home-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/09/home-visit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yukta and her sister Pooja[From another section in the same school] have been asking us to visit their home for quite sometime now. And now they&amp;rsquo;re threatening to give us letters every single day till we turn up there!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tell me why...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/09/tell-me-why.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/09/tell-me-why.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was stumped by this innocent letter from a kid in my class. Yukta - One of the smartest kids, questions me[ In RED and gives place for me to answer!] on how I came across the idea of playing the Age of Empires game!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this game that we play in the class, she happens to be the &amp;lsquo;Queen&amp;rsquo; with the most notorious &amp;lsquo;subjects&amp;rsquo;. Guess she just wanted to vent all her frustration[?] through this letter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zebra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/09/zebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/09/zebra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d asked the kids to find out why a zebra is black and white in colour. Ali - A kid who was in a marathi medium school until last year, comes up with this paper the next day. &amp;lsquo;Zebra mothe is black and waite. The zebra is black and wate. Jab upar wale ne usko aise kar diya, vo kya karega&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhaiya, Faasht coming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/03/24/bhaiya-faasht-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/03/24/bhaiya-faasht-coming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, you&amp;rsquo;re one of the first few lucky visitors to lay eyes on this freshly baked portal created to share our classroom experience.Feel free to skim through the portal and give in your suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
