<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/politics/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stimulus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/03/11/stimulus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/03/11/stimulus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting point on M1 and M2 [Measures of money]. With the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.allsides.com/story/biden-signs-19-trillion-covid-19-relief-bill-law&#34;&gt;signing of the 1.9T$ bill today&lt;/a&gt; in the US, we&amp;rsquo;ve essentially created 6T$ over the last 10 months. Just like that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Covid19 has brought  unprecedented suffering to many. Deaths, Unemployment, Medical complications, lifestyle changes, Social unrest and several other ramifications which we are yet to experience. If anything, it has taught us highlighted how abysmally poor we are in collectively addressing pressing issues. It has also shown us that when disaster strikes, we only take care of our own and we are selectively biased even at that. Nature gave us yet another opportunity to show how we could better ourselves and elevate us to the next stage of evolution and we miserably failed. With our myopic non-collaborative actions, pushing politics and power over general good, we&amp;rsquo;ve defined a new low. Mileage on isolated or individual efforts unfortunately does not carry the ripple effect that can scale. Nothing surprising there - Humans are selfish creatures. We of course needed something to balance all the &lt;em&gt;intelligence&lt;/em&gt; and cognitive advances we supposedly have over other living things. Humanity rests is constant chaos and Covid19 was continues to fuel that chaos.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quite a digression, eh?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Telangana issue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/03/23/the-telangana-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/03/23/the-telangana-issue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A 34 minute video presentation made by the Telangana Development Forum on the issue of a separate state for Telangana. The first twenty minutes doles on the history of the state and the remaining part more or less is a publicity or so called awareness campaign by the TRS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But how murky is the land on the other side?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R.I.P while we U.I.M!!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2007/12/29/r.i.p-while-we-u.i.m/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2007/12/29/r.i.p-while-we-u.i.m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hate blogging about &amp;lsquo;people&amp;rsquo;s demise&amp;rsquo; on my blog! Just couldn&amp;rsquo;t help this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Veteran Congress leader and Khairtabad MLA, Mr P. Janardhan Reddy, died of a massive cardiac arrest here on Friday. He was 59 and leaves behind his wife, Sulochana, four daughters and a son. The funeral will be conducted with State honours at Amberpet on Saturday. A mass leader, Janardhan Reddy held sway over city politics for nearly three decades. His sudden death was a shock to the people of the city.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The news of his sudden death was relayed to the GHCC meeting by Congress MP, V. Hanumantha Rao. The meeting was then stopped. His family members including son, Vishnuvardhan Reddy, rushed to the hospital and cried inconsolably. The popular leader’s supporters too broke down and beat their chests raising the slogan,”PJR Amar Hai. ”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;source: Andhracafe.com and mynews.in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May his soul R.I.P!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interesting part is that we have a quasi strike here on the roads of Hyderabad! Most of the shops , even petty footpath ones have been compelled to bring down shutters. Banks, Medical shops et al! How silly can people get?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agreed his supporters are deeply mourned by his death. I would be too, HAD i known about him and his services. But what is the point in bringing down day to day activities in the city just because their leader has expired. This guy popped because of a natural cause. No one shot him , It wasn&amp;rsquo;t an attempted murder, It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a suicide. The docs have verified it to be due to cardiac arrest and still, we have this wonderful , sincere, coveted, devoted, true Hyderabadi followers display their misery by rampaging on the streets. True CITIZENS that they are. Huh! Ah! Did I tell you that my Aunt actually found a couple of Ayyappa devotees arguing with a Bank Manager to close the bank for the day?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting for tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s News paper headlines. The congress is gonna blame BJP for not arranging proper facilities , not giving him due respect.. blah blah blah.The BJP is gonna refute the statements. His son is gonna join the fray. Contest for the next elections, Get sympathy votes. Wins it , becomes the people&amp;rsquo;s man and we know what follows !&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wonder what would be the state of affairs had he been assasinated!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
