<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Women-Shopping on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/women-shopping/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Women-Shopping on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/women-shopping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Kids teach!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2008/03/13/what-kids-teach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2008/03/13/what-kids-teach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, way back home from office, I got down at Narayanguda. I had to buy a couple of DVDs and a few books for my nephew &amp;rsquo;s and nieces. I got into Big Bazaar and walked directly to the Kids section. Took me some time to find the place where they stocked these stuffs . I initially thought this would just be  a pick and run shopping, but it turned out to be a total turn plate! :-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I flipped through a few CD&amp;rsquo;s and DVDs, found only a few interesting and put them aside. A few minutes later, I picked a couple of night time story books and thought I&amp;rsquo;m all done. The queue was quite big at the billing counter and I was the last person standing there.  Just around this moment, an old lady and her grand daughter walked in to the store and started sifting through the collection. The Lady picked up a couple of DVDs and asked the kid if she liked the selection. You&amp;rsquo;ve got to be there to see the response the kid gave :-)  ! She was like - I &amp;rsquo;ve gone through this shit several times, get me something new :-) ! That made me have a re-look on my selection and that is when I realised what dumb collection I had selected  :-) ! A bit more backtracking made me realise I had already bought similar stuff last year!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next moment I fell out of the queue and started sifting through the collection again.Still, I was no where close to getting a decent collection for the kids. Before I finally gave up I thought the best thing to do would be to talk to my sis and SIL to know exactly what they were looking for.Placed a brief call to both of them and got inputs from them. Then on, the selection was a mere cakewalk. Fortunately when I was done there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anyone standing in the queue. Walked over to him before I could change my mind, paid him the amount and walked out. By sheer instinct I look at the time in my watch. It was 8:30!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d spent a solid one hour shopping for DVDs and books for kids :-) ! I bet I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have spent even a quarter of this when selecting a pair of clothes for myself!  Probably this is one of the reasons why women shop that long! :-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
