<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tarc on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/tarc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tarc on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/tarc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Run for Colin</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/06/13/run-for-colin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/06/13/run-for-colin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Met Joe McConaughy over the weekend at the TARC camp. Three years ago he beat the record for a supported through hike/run of the PCT at 53 days and 6 hours. 2660 miles&amp;hellip;Such an inspiration!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MoaMlE3WDTs&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MoaMlE3WDTs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TARC Camp 2017</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/06/12/tarc-camp-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/06/12/tarc-camp-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/35273505625_29eed23d58_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;Back from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://trailanimals.com/&#34;&gt;TARC&lt;/a&gt; running camp all smitten with bug and mosquito bites. And it feels terrific! Logged a good sixteen odd miles back in the trails after a month’s rest and met a good bunch of folks. It’s always so inspiring to attend these TARC meets. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/srikanth_perinkulam/albums/72157669983500465&#34;&gt;Last year&lt;/a&gt; at the camp, it was my first ever deep exposure to TARC and I was blown away by the positivity, humbleness and expanse and depth of knowledge these (ultra)runners and other campers brought in. What really makes TARC outstanding is its inclusivity and support framework. They’re open to anybody who is remotely interested in the outdoors and just let the sheer culture of this community take over the reins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, that experience at camp last year deeply impacted my outlook towards running. From barely training for any of the half and full marathons and winging them for the most part, I diligently trained for a 50 miler early this year. The primary intention was to understand my body better and get into a better fitness regimen. Pretty ironic that I ended up spraining my ankle badly during the main event and had to drop out. A run for which I’d logged &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/category/channel/training/&#34;&gt;more than 300 miles&lt;/a&gt; in training! Endurance has always been my forte and however arduous it be, I have never ‘given-up’ during a run/hike over the last ten or so years that I’ve been exploring outdoors. As I was walking back to the car that day, I was in second thoughts if I should have pushed it and completed the run. Something that I didn’t have a definitive answer for then and neither do I have now. All I knew was that my morale did take a beating for sure. Wapack and Back remains an unfinished business and I will have to get back on those rolling peaks to make peace.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The camp this weekend was a much needed fix. Just being there surrounded by folks who have DNF’d before consciously for practical reasons and physical limitations took some load off my shoulders. Overall I believe I also had good quality runs this weekend. I felt much stronger on the trails and my average pace definitely seems to have gone up. I can’t wait to get back to a good training regimen again. I definitely do want to make it to more of the weekly runs at the Fells and should also probably join the Blue Hills group whenever feasible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a more tangible target, I have my eyes on the StoneCat 50 miler this November. The India trip may be a mild deterrent but I think I should be able to find a way around that…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/cropped-cropped-SP01-550afdebv1_site_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com&#34;&gt;Srikanth Perinkulam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The Trails Are Free’ Brings TARC, Ultrarunning Culture to the Big Screen</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/02/25/the-trails-are-free-brings-tarc-ultrarunning-culture-to-the-big-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/02/25/the-trails-are-free-brings-tarc-ultrarunning-culture-to-the-big-screen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Likes: &lt;a href=&#34;https://massultra.com/2017/02/23/the-trails-are-free-brings-tarc-ultrarunning-culture-to-the-big-screen/&#34;&gt;‘The Trails Are Free’ Brings TARC, Ultrarunning Culture to the Big Screen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://massultra.com/2017/02/23/the-trails-are-free-brings-tarc-ultrarunning-culture-to-the-big-screen/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekender - 04/02</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/04/03/weekender-04/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/04/03/weekender-04/02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got back to reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/33600.Shantaram&#34;&gt;Shantaram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25066990-living-with-a-seal&#34;&gt;Living with a Seal&lt;/a&gt; this weekend. Shantaram was Meena&amp;rsquo;s pick (gift for Christmas) and Living with a seal was &lt;a href=&#34;http://journeys-explored.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Ankur&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; recommendation (nudge to get back to fitness!). Of late reading has taken a back stage. Current target is to read these two books for the month.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Late last week chanced upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://trailanimals.com/&#34;&gt;TARC&lt;/a&gt; - a trail runner&amp;rsquo;s group in Boston! Joined them for 6 miler on Saturday morning. Oh, how humbling! Need to get my act together and train better for my runs. Middlesex fells looks to be a great training ground. Great reservoirs and longish trails. Wanted to do another long run today. But you know&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heard about &lt;a href=&#34;https://sandstorm.io/&#34;&gt;Sandstorm&lt;/a&gt; earlier this week and have been wanting to set up a personal server for a while now. Spent some time on Saturday reading up on the Ubuntu server and dabbled with Sandstorm online. Will potentially set this up over the next week or two. Also figured out a few minor issues with regards to e-mail access on Outlook for a few portals I manage. Explored some SQL and excel feeds for something at work. On another note, tweaked some settings to make this site a bit faster. Potentially exploring  moving out of pingbacks and into &lt;a href=&#34;https://indiewebcamp.com/Webmention&#34;&gt;Webmentions&lt;/a&gt;. Well, this is a test post to see if that&amp;rsquo;s working!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watched an impromptu Malayalam movie - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zbqfe_dm6sw&#34;&gt;Anarkali&lt;/a&gt;.  A good watch. An interesting take on life in Lakshwadeep and a tad bit on diving and free-diving. I take that as another &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/rambles/deepwaters&#34;&gt;hint&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Setting up the Norbo and fixing a book shelf are two things still pending. Soon, very soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to write more frequently. Several years back, writing got me to using my weekends more productively. I&amp;rsquo;d want to hike because I wanted to write and vice-versa. That &amp;lsquo;cycle&amp;rsquo; eventually got me to &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/outdoors&#34;&gt;explore the outdoors&lt;/a&gt; even more. Well I think it&amp;rsquo;s time I re-invent that wheel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
