<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2007-12-29 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2007-12-29-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2007-12-29 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2007-12-29-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AdVentura - Bangalore</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2007/12/29/adventura-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2007/12/29/adventura-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this wonderful group called Adventura for adventure freaks that operates from Bangalore. So if you are into trekking and stuff and stay somewhere near bangalore it&amp;rsquo;s high time you enroll yourself in this group. They arrange treks in and around Bangalore almost every weekend. Even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t really been on a trek and are pretty much a novice, you can still enroll yourself. Each trek outing is classified as Beginners, Intermediate and the like and I believe they&amp;rsquo;ve got gears for beginners too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Join the following group to enroll yourself: adventura@googlegroups&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;com&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t really been there out with them as I&amp;rsquo;d been in Bangalore only for a brief span of three months and odd. I wonder why we don&amp;rsquo;t have any such active group here in Hyderabad. Or do we?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple of my friends and I plan to start one. Nothing has materialized though. Shall let you know in case anything props up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R.I.P while we U.I.M!!</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2007/12/29/r.i.p-while-we-u.i.m/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2007/12/29/r.i.p-while-we-u.i.m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hate blogging about &amp;lsquo;people&amp;rsquo;s demise&amp;rsquo; on my blog! Just couldn&amp;rsquo;t help this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Veteran Congress leader and Khairtabad MLA, Mr P. Janardhan Reddy, died of a massive cardiac arrest here on Friday. He was 59 and leaves behind his wife, Sulochana, four daughters and a son. The funeral will be conducted with State honours at Amberpet on Saturday. A mass leader, Janardhan Reddy held sway over city politics for nearly three decades. His sudden death was a shock to the people of the city.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The news of his sudden death was relayed to the GHCC meeting by Congress MP, V. Hanumantha Rao. The meeting was then stopped. His family members including son, Vishnuvardhan Reddy, rushed to the hospital and cried inconsolably. The popular leader’s supporters too broke down and beat their chests raising the slogan,”PJR Amar Hai. ”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;source: Andhracafe.com and mynews.in&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;May his soul R.I.P!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interesting part is that we have a quasi strike here on the roads of Hyderabad! Most of the shops , even petty footpath ones have been compelled to bring down shutters. Banks, Medical shops et al! How silly can people get?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agreed his supporters are deeply mourned by his death. I would be too, HAD i known about him and his services. But what is the point in bringing down day to day activities in the city just because their leader has expired. This guy popped because of a natural cause. No one shot him , It wasn&amp;rsquo;t an attempted murder, It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a suicide. The docs have verified it to be due to cardiac arrest and still, we have this wonderful , sincere, coveted, devoted, true Hyderabadi followers display their misery by rampaging on the streets. True CITIZENS that they are. Huh! Ah! Did I tell you that my Aunt actually found a couple of Ayyappa devotees arguing with a Bank Manager to close the bank for the day?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting for tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s News paper headlines. The congress is gonna blame BJP for not arranging proper facilities , not giving him due respect.. blah blah blah.The BJP is gonna refute the statements. His son is gonna join the fray. Contest for the next elections, Get sympathy votes. Wins it , becomes the people&amp;rsquo;s man and we know what follows !&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wonder what would be the state of affairs had he been assasinated!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
