<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hiking on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/hiking/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hiking on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 21:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/hiking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arista de Humboldt</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/24/arista-de-humboldt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/24/arista-de-humboldt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I sent out a poll to the ESC group to gauge interest in a group hike at Nevado de Toluca. There was reasonable interest and we slotted this to be a family hike on the 24th. The Padilla&amp;rsquo;s and Johnston&amp;rsquo;s had to drop off last minute. It was just going to be Hadley and the Arturo&amp;rsquo;s now with the three of us. We reached the Shuttle point around 1015, hopped in a shuttle and got to the trail-head around 1100. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to hop off the shuttle - the gasoline stench coupled with the super dusty windy roads was more than churning my tummy. S did terrific with no complaints!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This time around we had to pay 65 pesos/person to enter the park. Very nominal and I guess it might be to control the crowd. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen Nevado de Toluca this busy! We trot up from the campamento towards Arista de Humboldt. I compromise with S before-hand that I&amp;rsquo;d carry her on sections when I can. Boy, she is getting heavy - &lt;em&gt;big and strong&lt;/em&gt; as M would like me to phrase it. We reach the viewpoint in no time.  This place is so freaking beautiful. Even with the almost ten fold crowd than usual.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;AristaDeHumboldt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Houss is definitely feeling the altitude ~14,060 ft. M is slowly warming up and S wants to head back to the trailhead. We decide to split the group here. The girls head over to scale one of the shorter hills on the right while the three of us head up the steepish peak on the left. In about twenty five minutes we reach to the top of this knoll and decide to turn around. At about 14,550 ft. oddly, it was way warmer than the lower elevations. A quick trot down to the rim and we decide to head back to the trail-head. The shuttle back from the trail-head is in a beaten Chevy pickup truck. We&amp;rsquo;re smothered with loads of fine dust as it zooms down the hill. S takes a mini-nap and wakes up just as we reach the car parking spot. A quick hour and a half and we&amp;rsquo;re home for a slow Sunday catch-up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cascada de la burbuja</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/17/cascada-de-la-burbuja/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/17/cascada-de-la-burbuja/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;Burbuja.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spent a good few hours out in the woods along with the girl scouts. M is not a leader this year so we took a step back and had a great time just enjoying the outdoors. S had a slow start and was heavily resisting for the first hour or so. She suddenly flipped once we reached the mid point and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to stop! She clocked around 5.2 miles in 3 hours and this would be one of her longest hikes in quite some time now! Super proud and she did earn her ramen!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The waterfall and the trail per se were beautiful with quite a few switchbacks on the stream fed by melt water from the Iztaccihuatl volcano. The approach road to the trail-head was quite beaten and the Vitara handled it real well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nevado de Toluca</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/23/nevado-de-toluca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/23/nevado-de-toluca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this, sick to the core at 0300, rallying between sweating out the sheets and freezing to the bones. It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough couple days. Oddly enough I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel one ounce of pain during the alpine hike I did on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240422_163850.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We summited Nevado de Toluca on Saturday and this would be one of my best hikes so far. Just two hours from Mexico city, this hike has something for everybody. First off, just getting to the alpine lakes from the base, which takes about 20 minutes, opens out the playground. One can literally see the whole terrain and trails that surround the pristine alpine lakes. We decide to head clockwise and summit Pico del Fraile (15388&amp;rsquo;). The climb up is reasonably straighforward and its mostly choosing your path to get to the peak.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240420_105952-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once at the peak, instead of scrambling downhill to the lakes, we decide to complete the loop and summit all the other peaks in that circuit. For the next 4 hours we&amp;rsquo;re trapezing the peaks, scrambling up and down paths of our choosing. It&amp;rsquo;s windy but not unreasonably cold. A thunderstorm looms further on one of the peaks and as we make plans to find cover under the rocks a mild hail storm hits us. Thankfully, our helmets protect us and we make decent progress towards the other peaks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240420_183656-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sound of conch shells and drums give us constant company - From high up here at 15000&amp;rsquo; we see a group of about 30 people performing some ritual near one of the alpine lakes. As we push for the final descent we somehow loose our trail. All we&amp;rsquo;re left with is super loose soil and huge stones at a 80° gradient. There&amp;rsquo;s barely any grip here and we&amp;rsquo;re at the mercy of luck as we make our way down. Finally at around 1500 we reach the base and wait for the transport truck to take us down to the actual base.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This hike was such a contrast to Izta. Izta felt like just a suffer fest with barely any rewards while Toluca offered some terrific views right from the start. I&amp;rsquo;d repeat this hike in a heartbeat!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024-04-20 07:39:31 - &lt;strong&gt;Nevado de Toluca&lt;/strong&gt; 🥾 Hiked 6.07 miles in 06:39:57 Pace : 65.89 min/mile. Elevation Gain : 2611 ft. Elevation Loss : 2613 ft. Calories : 1037 Location : Toluca 💓 : 90&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pico de Águila</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/14/pico-de-%C3%A1guila/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/14/pico-de-%C3%A1guila/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/signal-2024-04-14-17-12-24-029-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S was having a rough day on Saturday and was scrunched up against me all day. Around 1900 I checked my work phone and saw that Mo had texted earlier that morning asking if I would be interested in hiking Pico de Aguilar the next day. I wanted to confirm immediately but given S&amp;rsquo;s health I wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite sure. Decided to take a call the next morning and hit the bed. Thankfully, on Sunday morning, S seemed to have almost recovered and I decide to head out to meet Mo at his place. With some starting troubles (literally!) we finally leave for Ajusco around 0830.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The drive up is super straightforward and we park at the trailhead around 1000. We decide to take on the steeper parts of the climb first going clockwise. Around 1200 we reach Pico de Águila (12596&amp;rsquo;) and in another 30 minutes we summit Cerro La Cruz del Marquez (12871&amp;rsquo;). The way down from the Cerro was super steep at an 82° gradient. So glad we decided not to climb up from here and note to self to bring a knee brace for these downhills next time I hike here in CDMX. The loose volcanic soil and incessant pebbles make for dicey path downhill. We finish the hike at around 1400 and relish some hot cakes at one of the shacks at the base.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than anything, this hike was a major morale booster after last weeks Izta attempt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024-04-14 09:43:52 - &lt;strong&gt;Pico de Águila et Cerro La Cruz del Marquez&lt;/strong&gt; 🥾 Hiked 4.69 miles in 04:50:29 Pace : 61.94 min/mile. Elevation Gain : 2405 ft. Elevation Loss : 2384 ft. Calories : 1810 Location : La Magdalena Contreras 💓 : 152&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Izta Attempt</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/12/izta-attempt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/12/izta-attempt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got my ass royally whooped last weekend on Izta. The plan was to camp at La Joya until 0000 on Sunday and push for the summit by 0800. With around 4500&amp;rsquo; to climb, I knew this would be challenging. What I was not ready for, was the elevation sickness that hit me at about 14000&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240412_0649293003591195629761476.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  title=&#34;Izta from La Joya&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;La Joya is at around 13000&amp;rsquo;. We got here around 1200 on Saturday, setup camp and did a short 1.5 hours acclimatization hike to Portillo 1 and got back to La Joya for dinner and rest around 1600. I&amp;rsquo;m usually able to sleep well despite the surroundings. Today however, I sense a mild headache and am not quite able get much sleep for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We break camp around 0000 on Sunday and start the climb. As we reach Portillo 1 in about an hour I do notice I&amp;rsquo;m hurting a bit. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t this difficult last evening. A short break here and we head up to Portillo 2. Marco our guide checks on how we&amp;rsquo;re doing and I tell him - Today&amp;rsquo;s not my day. The headache from last night lingers and I feel a bit queasy. First sign of altitude sickness hitting me. I ask if we can slow down the pace and keep moving. At Portillo 3, I&amp;rsquo;m laboring and for a moment I think I saw M climbing down. That can&amp;rsquo;t quite be true because she never did come on this hike. I eat a couple nutri bars and suggest I stick right behind Marco as we climb the loose soil gradient towards Portillo 4. Around 15000&amp;rsquo; I start feeling a bit dizzy and take a call to turn around. The group agrees and I stay real close to Marco just focussing on his feet movements. It&amp;rsquo;s still pitch dark. On the way down, a group of hikers attempting the summit wish us a good hike and trudge along in the opposite direction. As the last person in the group crosses me, one look at her and I realise its M and I turn around and follow her. Only issue being - it&amp;rsquo;s not her. She never came on this hike. I snap back into reality when Adam checks in on me questioning why I&amp;rsquo;d turned around. And this is when I realise my altitude sickness is getting worse - quicker. I take a couple minutes to gather myself and we attempt to scale down the peak as quickly and safely as we can.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Portillo 1, we get some well needed rest. The sky is free of any pollution and all we see is beautiful stars strewn all over the pitch black sky. Shooting stars and satellites galore! I wish I had a good camera to capture this all. But then that would still do no justice to the magnificent show the universe was putting up this morning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240412_0759053559839938595451752.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Though we didn&amp;rsquo;t quite summit and Izta is yet to checked off the list, It&amp;rsquo;s been quite an eventful night. With sufficient rest at Portillo 1, I feel much better and literally run down the last section of this trail. We reach La Joya by dawn break and make our way back to CDMX.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leleiwi overlook trail</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/03/leleiwi-overlook-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/04/03/leleiwi-overlook-trail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Super short hike up to the overlook. Absolutely mesmerized to see the Tradewinds holding down the sea of clouds!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/imagepipe_694997230811934222143.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La Joya Izta Volcan hike</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/01/28/la-joya-izta-volcan-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/01/28/la-joya-izta-volcan-hike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to scout out the Izta-Popo national park ever since I got a sneak peek at the volcanoes while in Ikea a few months ago. Several blogs pointed at exploring this region by doing the La Joya traverse which essentially gets one to the base of the Iztaccihuatl volcano. I head out this morning to &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amecameca&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - a small quaint town to the east of Mexico City. The bus that left TAPO [Terminal de Autobuses de Pasajeros de Oriente] around 0700 only got to Amecameca by 0900. Should have left earlier! From there at the Centro, I was able to hop into a cab that got me to &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paso de Cortes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; around 0930.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;image-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;ul class=&#34;photo-list &#34;&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;             &#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&#xA;                &lt;img src=&#34;./images/Imagepipe_59.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Imagepipe_59.jpg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;             &#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&#xA;                &lt;img src=&#34;./images/Imagepipe_60.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Imagepipe_60.jpg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;             &#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&#xA;                &lt;img src=&#34;./images/Imagepipe_61.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Imagepipe_61.jpg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;.photo-list {&#xA;    display: flex;  &#xA;    flex-wrap: wrap;  &#xA;    margin: -1px;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list &gt; li {&#xA;    height: 40vh;  &#xA;    flex-grow: 1;  &#xA;    list-style-type: none;  &#xA;    margin: 1px;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list li img {&#xA;    max-height: 100%;  &#xA;    min-width: 100%;  &#xA;    object-fit: cover;  &#xA;    vertical-align: bottom;  &#xA;    border: 2px solid gray;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list li:last-child {&#xA;    flex-grow: 10;  &#xA;    border: none;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA; &#xA;.photo-list.single-image &gt; li {&#xA;    height: auto;  &#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hit the trail without wasting any time. Izta looks pretty unassuming from here. About 30 minutes into the hike, Popocatepetl reveals its massive self, smoking out pretty tamely. As I tread my way up to La Joya, just as I pass the radio tower around 1045, I notice a small rattle snake slither across the path. I looked up iNaturalist a few days ago and knew this park did have a good bunch of snakes. Needles to say, seeing one slithering around did give me a good reality check. The last couple miles, I&amp;rsquo;m stuck behind a big group making their way up to La Joya. I initially planned to climb Izta upto Portillo 2. Getting to La Joya and seeing the crowd there, I decide to head back. Also, the scenery wasn&amp;rsquo;t changing much and I didn&amp;rsquo;t see great benefit in climbing the last half mile of the planned hike.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next time I come here, I&amp;rsquo;d probably make this a multi-day trip and camp at La Joya. Great hike overall but for the heat and crowd.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cerro San Miguel Hike</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2023/12/10/cerro-san-miguel-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2023/12/10/cerro-san-miguel-hike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At 12,220 ft and after a 3-hour climb, it felt like home and more importantly I felt real strong. This was my first decent hike in quite some time now and I was pleasantly surprised my body wasn&amp;rsquo;t really complaining.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Imagepipe_58.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early this month, M and I spoke about getting back into the hiking circuit. It&amp;rsquo;s been about 9 months that we&amp;rsquo;ve moved to CDMX and we&amp;rsquo;ve covered a decent bunch of the touristy stuff. CDMX has so many good hikes to offer and quite a few are reasonably accessible from the city limits. With work-travel, visitors and other schedule conflicts; we felt it was reasonable for us to fit in one camping trip and one exploratory hike very month.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I chanced on Di&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://slightnorth.com/desierto-de-los-leones-cerro-san-miguel/&#34;&gt;post on hiking Cerro San Miguel&lt;/a&gt; from Ex Convento. She had some great pointers on the trail and coupled with the AllTrails app, this was a super easy trail to navigate. We did summit Cerro El Caballete on the way to Cerro San Miguel. Weather was just right and we barely ran into three or four other people on the way up. Was a treat to see MTB bikers literally flying downhill on those steep gradients. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t think twice to come back here!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sugarloaf Mountain</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/11/07/sugarloaf-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/11/07/sugarloaf-mountain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Took A out for a short hike up Sugarloaf Mountain. More of a hill than a mountain! This one&amp;rsquo;s a quick 25min hike up to the summit and has some real nice views on the top. The trail generally gets super crowded but looks like the cold weather did keep the majority indoors. A got some tough love but he did enjoy the hike thoroughly!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Franconia, yet again.</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/09/24/franconia-yet-again./</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/09/24/franconia-yet-again./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The initial plan was to hike up to Greenleaf hut by the Old bridle trail and summit Mt. Lafayette at the crack of dawn. Sunrise on the ridge would have been terrific and the switchbacks on the way down would have been just perfect! However, Mountain weather forecast on Thursday indicated a cold front approaching on Friday night - temps dropping down to 3 F! We decided to shift this to a day hike instead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Screenshot_20220922-062727_Firefox-270x600.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA; Sharath and I flew into Logan around 2130 hrs on Friday night. A few hours of good rest at K&amp;rsquo;s place and we hopped back in the car at 0330hrs on Saturday morning to head to the trailhead parking. Getting to the trailhead early around 0530hrs, got us a couple serene hours of hiking up in the darkness - near freezing cold winds swishing by trees on the mountains, dim headlamps guiding us in the darkness, silence of the wilderness and just each other for company.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the way up, folks making the traverse in the CCW direction warned of the white-out conditions they&amp;rsquo;d faced on the ridge. The very reason why we set out on this hike was to get S and J to experience a ridge hike, so I really hoped we could get to the ridge. Realistically though, it just didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like we would be able to. Once at the hut, we decide to push for Mt Lafayette&amp;rsquo;s summit and turn around. About 500ft in, conditions worsened super quickly and black ice on the stones made it super unsafe to head further. We turn around, make another quick stop at the hut and descend down the same trail to reach the Lafayette parking ground by 1245hrs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery link=&amp;ldquo;none&amp;rdquo; columns=&amp;ldquo;4&amp;rdquo; size=&amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;51617,51618,51619,51620&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All in all, despite the weather and not being able to summit and hike the ridge, this was a terrific hike. Franconia never disappoints!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visapur-Lohagad hike</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/04/03/visapur-lohagad-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/04/03/visapur-lohagad-hike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/image-1200x900.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;L made me promise on Saturday night that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t cancel the hike next morning. She had every reason to be doubtful since we&amp;rsquo;d cancelled the Rajgad hike earlier today. After our &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/04/05/k2s-5/&#34;&gt;K2S hike last night&lt;/a&gt; neither Ankur nor I were in a mood to venture out in the heat.  What we didn&amp;rsquo;t know however was that she traded a sleepover with her friend for the Saturday morning hike to Rajgad. With us on the hills all last night and bad network reception things fell between the cracks. Amends were made and we chalked out a plan to head to Lohagad/Visapur on Sunday first thing in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20220406_190022-900x1200.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been here once during monsoon. With cascades in all directions, this is one terrific monsoon hike. Turns out, the Visapur stretch is a great summer hike too. The rocky path all the way up to the fort makes it quite interesting and challenging. S had a terrific time sitting in the carrier and commanding me to  climb faster! We made it to the top of the fort just before the heat started kicking in. Spent quite sometime exploring the vast fort contours and now arid interiors. Devoured several glasses of lemon juice and &lt;em&gt;Thak&lt;/em&gt; before making our way back to the car. My calves were screaming of their presence on every step downhill. Such bliss and yet another reminder to continue scouting for such opportunities to explore the outdoors even more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Katraj to Sinhagad - Take 5</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/04/02/katraj-to-sinhagad-take-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/04/02/katraj-to-sinhagad-take-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_37938&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;1200&amp;rdquo;]&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/DSC02891-1200x900.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA; Sinhagad at a distance. This picture is from on of my previous hikes.[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sharp at 0600 as we finally reach the road that winds up to Sinhagad, Ankur and I take a moment to savor the twilight chill. The last 7.5 hours has been nothing short of mesmerizing and rewarding. Just as it was twelve years ago when I did this hike with a much larger group.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Part of me wanted to just camp right on the first hill. To think of it, this has been something I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do for a while. Next time around, I should probably start a bit early and set camp on the hill just before Sinhagad so I can catch sunrise there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, something which had been up in the air for more than a year and half, finally fell in place. So this hike is also a celebration of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oregon Ridge Park</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/06/oregon-ridge-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/06/oregon-ridge-park/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Took Appa and S out to the Oregon Ridge Park while M helped getting things ready for Amma&amp;rsquo;s Shraadam. While at it I also got to test the new action camera that we bought last month.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20000810_055033-1200x675.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quite a chilly and windy day. That didn&amp;rsquo;t deter S from having a blast at the playground. The &amp;lsquo;hike&amp;rsquo; quickly turned into a playground outing. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t complain. Amazed at how well she handled the low temps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patapsco thru trail loop</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/05/patapsco-thru-trail-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/05/patapsco-thru-trail-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of the morning today was spent wasted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/05/january-6-2022-0633/&#34;&gt;getting the RT-PCR&lt;/a&gt; for the upcoming travel. M suggested we hit the trails with N &amp;amp; A as they had a snow day - after-effects of the winter storm earlier this week. We decided to head to the Patapsco thru trail since we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much daylight hours left. The snow showers earlier this week and dusk setting in made this place look terrific!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20220105_022008-900x1200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intent was to hike down to the Patapsco river, follow the trail along the banks and loop back within a mile or so. We&amp;rsquo;ve been here before so I kinda knew the loop - or so I thought. We took the wrong fork a mile or so in and even before sunset made our way back to the car. S had a terrific time spotting Santa and the reindeer&amp;rsquo;s amidst the tree and she had her 101 on trail markers. Dainty queen that she is, she chose to sit in the carrier and  avoid all the snow on her snow shoes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today was just so beautiful!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trolley trail</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/01/trolley-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/01/trolley-trail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This first, we wanted to take Miss S out for some good time outdoors. With various factors at play, we haven&amp;rsquo;t had that mental space to prioritize this over the last few months and this is something we definitely wanted to change this year. The Trolley trail was an easy pick since we&amp;rsquo;d already been there a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/05/17/number-nine-trolley-trail-hike/&#34;&gt;few&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/14/reflections-by-the-rail-line/&#34;&gt;times&lt;/a&gt; in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[gallery link=&amp;ldquo;none&amp;rdquo; size=&amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;31845,31847,31844,31848,31846&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We directly went to this &amp;lsquo;secret&amp;rsquo; spot that&amp;rsquo;s hidden right at the beginning of the trail. The fog and the weather made this space look even more mystical! Miss S had a terrific time hopping around and throwing pebbles stones across the stream. Later on during the drive back she went on to claim all the fog on the road was because she threw those pebbles in the water. Today was magical!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
