<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022-01-05 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/date/2022-01-05-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022-01-05 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/date/2022-01-05-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>January 6, 2022 06:09</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/05/january-6-2022-0609/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/05/january-6-2022-0609/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Built this robust scooter for little S last evening. Absolutely love how intricate these infento kits can get. Kept both of us engaged for more than four hours. The scooter should keep her occupied for a few days&amp;hellip;or not&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>January 6, 2022 06:33</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/05/january-6-2022-0633/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/05/january-6-2022-0633/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most repulsive moment of the day yesterday was to pay 40x for an RT-PCR test - as compared to the test I&amp;rsquo;d taken just a few days ago. So repulsive that I fumingly shred the papers in tiny bits and walked out of the queue just looking at that number and knowing fairly well I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite have any other options&amp;hellip;only to rejoin the queue half an hour later since guess what? - I&amp;rsquo;d absolutely no other options. Sucked big-time and now I&amp;rsquo;d also wasted a few more hours of precious time with family. Pandemic travel tales, I guess. The looming snow storms better not mess this up further!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patapsco thru trail loop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/05/patapsco-thru-trail-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/01/05/patapsco-thru-trail-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of the morning today was spent wasted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/05/january-6-2022-0633/&#34;&gt;getting the RT-PCR&lt;/a&gt; for the upcoming travel. M suggested we hit the trails with N &amp;amp; A as they had a snow day - after-effects of the winter storm earlier this week. We decided to head to the Patapsco thru trail since we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much daylight hours left. The snow showers earlier this week and dusk setting in made this place look terrific!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20220105_022008-900x1200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intent was to hike down to the Patapsco river, follow the trail along the banks and loop back within a mile or so. We&amp;rsquo;ve been here before so I kinda knew the loop - or so I thought. We took the wrong fork a mile or so in and even before sunset made our way back to the car. S had a terrific time spotting Santa and the reindeer&amp;rsquo;s amidst the tree and she had her 101 on trail markers. Dainty queen that she is, she chose to sit in the carrier and  avoid all the snow on her snow shoes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today was just so beautiful!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
