<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2009-11-24 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2009-11-24-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2009-11-24 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2009-11-24-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic First-aid Primer</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2009/11/24/basic-first-aid-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2009/11/24/basic-first-aid-primer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Couple of weeks back when I received an e-mail from Vibha from the GHAC group regarding a basic first aid certification course, I immediately RSVP&amp;rsquo;d as YES. This was not something I would miss at any cost. Having miraculously walked out unscathed through two major accidents, it was a lesson learnt the hard way to be equipped with at least minimal knowledge of first-aid. My futile attempts to try out CPR on a badly injured neighbour whom I was pillion riding with 9 years back and the Oil tanker incident four years back where I was equally helpless flashed out of memory as the detailed practical session commenced.Though I could not attend the whole two day program due to personal commitments, it was indeed one of the most fruitful programs / meets I&amp;rsquo;ve attended of late.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, here in India, most of us take things only on the frontal perspective. You do not learn or do something unless it is mandated and the pivotal source of information is available only to those who choose to delve in. Its an irony that even preliminary information is not dissipated to the masses and even if it is, it is done in the most rudimentary form that effectively does not make sense. Basic first aid sessions is something I guess every individual should be introduced to, irrespective of age. To be able to sustain a weaning life and if required, be responsible to keep the flame burning is a chance that we always hope does not cross our paths. But given todays&amp;rsquo; fast paced life and highly inorganic growth in the cities, chances are pretty remote that you would see a day pass by without hearing an Ambulance hooting out there on the roads.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m much more active outdoors than indoors [I sometimes wonder how I even ended being a Software Engineer!],  I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to update this post as and when I come across relevant information catering to first aid. That said, there&amp;rsquo;s absolutely no substitute to practical demonstration. So do attend a certification course whenever possible!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In case of any eventuality perform &lt;strong&gt;DR. ABC&lt;/strong&gt; - Look out for &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;anger, Check for &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;esponse, Check for &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;irway clearance, Check for &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;reathing, Check for &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;irculation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Look out for &lt;strong&gt;Danger&lt;/strong&gt; - [Electrical live wires, Wild animals etc.  - Keep yourself safe and then only attempt rescue]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check for &lt;strong&gt;Response&lt;/strong&gt; - Do NOT tap on the cheeks. Do NOT shake the body vigorously. Try vocal stimuli [call the patients name] and speak into his/her ears if required, shake the shoulders gently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check for ****A&lt;strong&gt;irway&lt;/strong&gt; clearance - In most of the cases, airway could be blocked by the tongue. Gently shift the face to either left or right and maintain in that position for about 15seconds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check for &lt;strong&gt;Breathing&lt;/strong&gt; - Raise the chin gently and sense if the person is breathing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check for &lt;strong&gt;Circulation&lt;/strong&gt; - With the first two fingers check for the Carotid pulse. [ Check adjacent to the adams apple].&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pictographic representation of CPR [Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://southjerseycpr.com/&#34;&gt;http://southjerseycpr.com/&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While shifting the patient to the hospital in case of non-availability of ambulance, make it a point to keep the persons head tilted to the left or right.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If patient shows signs of life and you&amp;rsquo;re waiting for an ambulance, get the patient to posture 6.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Related links :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mayoclinic.com/health/FirstAidIndex/FirstAidIndex&#34;&gt;Mayo Clinic-First Aid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribd.com/doc/299034/FM-2176-US-Army-Survival-Manual&#34;&gt;U.S Army Survival Manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check for &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;irway clearance&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
