<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2024 on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/year/2024/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2024 on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 22:26:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/year/2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>All hugo&#39;d out</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/01/all-hugod-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 22:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/01/all-hugod-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got some decent progress on tweaking this portal. All hugo&amp;rsquo;d out for now though and a short break is overdue. Super slow weekend otherwise. Watched Moana 2. Meh. Not much story but decent visuals. Tragedy of sequels, maybe?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 12 01 003000</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/01/2024-12-01-003000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/01/2024-12-01-003000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moved over the syndication links in my posts to post-meta. The syndication icon only shows up if a valid link is present in the FrontMatter of a post. Once micro.blog picks up the feed, it&amp;rsquo;s currently set to auto publish to the fediverse on my GoToSocial (GTS) instance.  On the backend, a GO script fetches the RSS feed from my GTS instance and saves the RSS feed item link and the corresponding link to my post in a JSON file. Another script quickly looks up which post&amp;rsquo;s FrontMatter needs to be updated for the syndication links in each post and updates the files as needed. A bit windy but seems to do the job for now. I might end up consolidating these into just one script later and/or directly use the masto API to publish to the fediverse and grab the syndication link from there. For now, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty psyched this is all working.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-11-29</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/29/2024-11-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/29/2024-11-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just struck me that most of my disk drives are quite old. Almost all of them were salvaged from old laptops. Age does not necessarily equate to performance and I do have decent backups, but only a question of time before I see them going kaput. Living vicariously on the edge when it comes to self-hosting!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arista de Humboldt</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/24/arista-de-humboldt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/24/arista-de-humboldt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I sent out a poll to the ESC group to gauge interest in a group hike at Nevado de Toluca. There was reasonable interest and we slotted this to be a family hike on the 24th. The Padilla&amp;rsquo;s and Johnston&amp;rsquo;s had to drop off last minute. It was just going to be Hadley and the Arturo&amp;rsquo;s now with the three of us. We reached the Shuttle point around 1015, hopped in a shuttle and got to the trail-head around 1100. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to hop off the shuttle - the gasoline stench coupled with the super dusty windy roads was more than churning my tummy. S did terrific with no complaints!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This time around we had to pay 65 pesos/person to enter the park. Very nominal and I guess it might be to control the crowd. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen Nevado de Toluca this busy! We trot up from the campamento towards Arista de Humboldt. I compromise with S before-hand that I&amp;rsquo;d carry her on sections when I can. Boy, she is getting heavy - &lt;em&gt;big and strong&lt;/em&gt; as M would like me to phrase it. We reach the viewpoint in no time.  This place is so freaking beautiful. Even with the almost ten fold crowd than usual.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;AristaDeHumboldt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Houss is definitely feeling the altitude ~14,060 ft. M is slowly warming up and S wants to head back to the trailhead. We decide to split the group here. The girls head over to scale one of the shorter hills on the right while the three of us head up the steepish peak on the left. In about twenty five minutes we reach to the top of this knoll and decide to turn around. At about 14,550 ft. oddly, it was way warmer than the lower elevations. A quick trot down to the rim and we decide to head back to the trail-head. The shuttle back from the trail-head is in a beaten Chevy pickup truck. We&amp;rsquo;re smothered with loads of fine dust as it zooms down the hill. S takes a mini-nap and wakes up just as we reach the car parking spot. A quick hour and a half and we&amp;rsquo;re home for a slow Sunday catch-up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garmin Ported</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/22/garmin-ported/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/22/garmin-ported/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spent a good few hours yesterday and ported my garmin data over to this site &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/garmin/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s turned out better than my wordpress plugin and is way simpler to manage. I&amp;rsquo;ve still got quite a few tweaks to do but I&amp;rsquo;m super happy with how this has turned out!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bacalar</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/18/bacalar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/18/bacalar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;BacalarLagoon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cenote Negro&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bacalar has been on our travel list for quite sometime now. Between work travel, syncing our individual schedules and just getting around to actually booking the trip; we finally get around visiting this beautiful place this weekend in November.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we get off the plane, we&amp;rsquo;re immediately hit by a waft of the Yucatán humidity, soon followed by thick droplets of rain. Strikes me just then that we&amp;rsquo;re also right in the midst of the hurricane season. A quick lookup on the weather forecast reveals Hurricane Sara would be swinging past us and into the Gulf of Mexico in a bit. I slap myself on my wrist for not doing any research beforehand but also shrug this &lt;em&gt;minor&lt;/em&gt; oversight very quickly. How bad could it actually be? Maybe some showers here and there? We walk outside the Chetumal airport for about 500m and take a taxi from the main road to Bacalar. Oscar offers to take us there for 550 pesos. This was about 50 pesos shy of the amount the tour planner had quoted. M immediately accepts and we&amp;rsquo;re on our way. First impressions of this place immediately remind me of Trivandrum - lush green vistas with coconut trees strewn all around, narrow roads and barely any traffic. There&amp;rsquo;s construction for Tren Maya happening along the route but it barely impacts our drive. In about 50 minutes we reach the hotel and check-in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S immediately comments on the smell of wood as we enter our room. She&amp;rsquo;s ambivalent of the smell but seems to love the room setup. She goes around exploring the windows and shower. Once we get settled in, we head out to explore the property a bit. Hotel Carolina looks good with the woodsy feel and being right on the lagoon - but it definitely feels more commercial than I had imagined it to be. Yet another slap on the wrist. Note to self not to go by just pictures next time around. Maybe this trip planner thing is not quite working for us? This is the first time in all these years we&amp;rsquo;re using one - An embassy colleague&amp;rsquo;s wife runs a dive business and plans trips for folks across central America. We thought we&amp;rsquo;d give her a shot for this trip. Anyways, the stomach rumbles and we head over to Mango y Chile - a quaint vegan restaurant right by &lt;em&gt;Fuerte de San Filipe&lt;/em&gt; about 30 minutes walk from the hotel. The burgers and smoothies here are super delicious and we finish it off with some paletas. M&amp;rsquo;s restaurant picks barely go wrong! Back to the room and we settle down for the night.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around 0730 we stir awake and quickly get ready for the day. Plan is to head over to the fort to meet out boat captain who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to take us for a two hour ride in the lagoon. M messages the tour operator to check if the plan is still on since it&amp;rsquo;s super gloomy and heavy outside. She confirms and we head over to the fort. Just as we get to the fort, the skies let loose and the Boat captain gives us news that the police have closed the port for the day. We&amp;rsquo;re obviously disappointed and decide to grab a quick bite closer to the hotel. I offer to carry S on my shoulders as we make our way back in the pouring rain. The roads are flooded and the rain isn&amp;rsquo;t showing any signs of letting go. Love this walk back and it&amp;rsquo;s been quite sometime that we&amp;rsquo;ve actually done this! Some good breakfast at Noru&amp;rsquo;s and we make our way back to the hotel. M suggests we should probably consider getting back to CDMX that afternoon. Unfortunately, there are no tickets available on the flight. With that decision made for us, we decide to head back out for lunch at &lt;em&gt;Enamora&lt;/em&gt;. Food here&amp;rsquo;s okay. As we make our way back to the hotel, the weather clears up a bit. S wanted to head to the kids pool and we nudge her to try out the swing in the water. &lt;em&gt;Sara&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; effect lingers and the water is super choppy. We try getting the kayak out for a bit but aren&amp;rsquo;t quite successful. Back to the room and we spend some good time in the portico by the hammock. After we&amp;rsquo;re back from dinner at &lt;em&gt;Noru&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt;, I nudge S to head back to the wooden pier by the lagoon. We spend some time here as the sun sets and S plays with the idea of getting the kayak out. She flips it over in an instant and wants me to get in the water instead. The water does seem way calmer and I hop in to explore the waters. This impromptu wade in was probably one of the highlight&amp;rsquo;s for the day. We head back to the room. S spends some more time on the hammock and quickly falls asleep. M and I tinker with the idea of taking the kayak out the next morning to explore the lagoon by ourselves. As I type this at 0326 on Monday, I&amp;rsquo;m actually super psyched about this plan. Hoping S is game doing this in a few hours!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;BacalarSwing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And she is! We quickly change over in the morning and take to the waters. The weather is just right - Dark clouds hanging above and rays of sunshine creeping down. The water is much calmer and we&amp;rsquo;re near Cenote Negro in no time. We wade in the waters for about an hour and steal a few more minutes by the swing. Around 1030 we finally checkout and head to the airport after a brief breakfast stop at &lt;em&gt;Ajal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While we didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get to explore the whole lagoon, I&amp;rsquo;m so glad we ended up staying for the extra day. Overall S thoroughly enjoyed the water and just lazing in the hammock. Lesson learnt though that we are best at planning our own trips and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to head to Baja California later this December!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spanglish</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/16/spanglish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/16/spanglish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;Spanglish.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back to the Yucatan for a work trip. Too many variables to factor in and ultimately I decided to head here for just a couple days. Short but super productive. Nothing to beat some good facetime.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new building here is at a much better state than Hermosillo and we should be quite ready for the move next year. Spent about a day at the NCC and head back to the COB to close out a few things there. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite hungry but decided to walk over to a quaint place closeby. Barely anybody at this Puerto-Rican restaurant - Spanglish, but boy am I not glad I walked in? One of the best meals I&amp;rsquo;ve had here in Merida in a while. Salsa with some piping hot white rice served with some steaming hot platanos glazed with baked beans paste. Simple yet -potent- with flavors and spice. Surprised we did not quite visit this place over the last year. Coming back here for sure! Missed going to the Korean place this time around for the ice-cream. Spanglish more than made up for that though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As timing would have it, we&amp;rsquo;ll be back to the Yucatan this weekend for the Bacalar trip. This one&amp;rsquo;s been on our list for a while now and we are super looking forward to it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Momboard</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/14/momboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 22:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/14/momboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is such a neat idea. Love a good purposeful e-ink display! Adding his &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/WebOrigami/japan-hike-ebook&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; to my read-list.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sixth</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/11/sixth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/11/sixth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;Sixth.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S celebrated her 6th today.  Unicorn themed - of course - and had her first and probably last ever Piñata. But for a mega meltdown initially she did great all through the event.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, we signed up for a Diwali party organized by the Indian Association in Mexico. Primarily on a whim and maybe for the food? The event was last evening and boy, it was a terrible disappointment! It started late as expected. And obnoxiously loud for no reason. Not quite sure if it was the acoustics at the venue or just the MC shouting into the mic.  Maybe both? I love some good rock and metal. I love some good loud music. But I guess not all loud is the same. Also, this day and age, who even does a looping slideshow of pictures of people organizing the event? Dinner was supposed to be served by 1900. Servers said they had orders to serve only at 2030. Maybe the organizers wanted the food to be served only after the main event? When we rechecked at 2030, they said it was pushed to 2130. Had enough of it and walked out.  People were still on the dance floor and there was a good turn out. I guess this kinda boisterous social mayhem is just not my jam?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We head out to a Japanese (?) restaurant in Polanco since Nimi&amp;rsquo;s, Mei Mei and Manaw were all closed for service. Sushi was &lt;em&gt;meh&lt;/em&gt;. S did great all through the evening though despite the loud music and the crowd. That &amp;lsquo;Sticker by number&amp;rsquo; book that she received as a gift from Maddy kept her fully occupied!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Monday morning here and S is off for school. She was mildly upset that I get to stay at home while she needs to go to school. Fair world logic, I guess. We drop her and get to spend a couple hours together watching &lt;em&gt;Spenser Confidential&lt;/em&gt;. Enjoyed it all the more because we recognized quite a few locations where the movie was shot. M&amp;rsquo;s got some brunch out with the ladies in a bit and then a couple more hours before I need to pick up S. Maybe I should tweak that 3D printer?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebuilding the photo gallery</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/09/rebuilding-the-photo-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/09/rebuilding-the-photo-gallery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://billglover.me/2023/11/07/creating-a-photography-gallery-with-hugo/&#34;&gt;Bill Glover&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to rebuild my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/photos/&#34;&gt;photo gallery&lt;/a&gt;. Similar to how I built this earlier in wordpress, all I&amp;rsquo;m doing is mimicking an archive page but with just the images. Took me a bit to figure out that the &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; function breaks the context and I had to dynamically reassign the permalink. With that sorted, this page should auto-update whenever I publish posts. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basilica de Guadalupe</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/02/basilica-de-guadalupe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/02/basilica-de-guadalupe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;BasilicaDeGuadalupe.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spent most of this morning at the Basilica de Guadalupe. This photo does not do enough justice to how much this old church is actually falling apart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/02/migrating-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/02/migrating-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open notes with a running list of things I&amp;rsquo;m working on for this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dec-2024&#34;&gt;DEC 2024&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Build roadmap for Garmin posts migration&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Fetch activity summaries over as an archive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Build a yearly summary per activity&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Add webmentions to the site. Thanks, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hugo.md/post/add-webmentions-to-hugo-from-micro-blog/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;!&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tweak CSS to display webmentions properly. Maybe explore &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PlaidWeb/webmention.js&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maybe explore setting up an interactions content type &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jayeless.net/2021/02/integrating-webmentions-into-hugo.html&#34;&gt;like Jessica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Fix syndication issues&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Limit RSS Feed fetch to just 5 recent posts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make FrontMatter updates Camelcase proof&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consolidate into just one GO script&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Figure out how to fetch synd links for micro posts without embed links&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Consolidate categories&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Convert old tweets to a summary page on this portal&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Merge old instagram posts to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/photos&#34;&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt; page&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Maybe add some pagination to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/micro&#34;&gt;micro&lt;/a&gt; page&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Migrate old PixelFed photos over.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Add a proper comment form for posts&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Setup a script to autopost to GoToSocial.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;nov-2024&#34;&gt;NOV 2024&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Used lonekorean&amp;rsquo;s fantastic &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lonekorean/wordpress-export-to-markdown&#34;&gt;wordpress-export-to-markdown&lt;/a&gt; tool to convert WP xml to markdown&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; learned that the &lt;em&gt;hugo server&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;hugo build&lt;/em&gt; serve different purposes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Setup aliases on NUC and Thinkpond to quickly build and publish. Moved the actual publishing workflow to the Thinkpond and retained the main static site on the NUC.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Fixed permalinks to prevent link rot, almost?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Fixed RSS feed issues&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; For posts tagged as &lt;em&gt;micro&lt;/em&gt; set the title to just date+time so that micro.blog picks it up as a note and not display the title.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Migrate older posts as deemed fit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Build a proper archive page. Made some decent progress, thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://darcynorman.net/archives/&#34;&gt;D&amp;rsquo;Arcy Norman&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;, pointers &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io/t/listing-all-posts/30575/4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Build a proper photo gallery&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Decided to add a permalink to each post at the end. A shortcode automatically fetches the permalink and adds it to the end of each post.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wrote a quick GO script to consolidate these&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moved the photos over. Decided to leave the photo notes behind.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/09/last-mile-closures/&#34;&gt;Decided to use ISSO&lt;/a&gt; over Remark42&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running on Hugo</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/01/running-on-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/11/01/running-on-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/posts/2024/10/crisp-new-start/&#34;&gt;That&lt;/a&gt;  didn&amp;rsquo;t last long. Moved over to Hugo from WriteFreely for a bit more flexibility. This site is going through some major overhaul. Slowly and recklessly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diwali</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/31/diwali/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/31/diwali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;Diwali2024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being overseas and not having access to firecrackers, this festival is just not what it used to be. I wish I could go back to those days when we would try and wake up before Kitta mama would burst his 1000 wala before the break of dawn. Days when you yearn to wear those new set of clothes - The only time of the year when you get new clothes and not hand-me-downs. Days when you make a TON of sweets and savories to share with family and friends. Days when you would hop into people&amp;rsquo;s houses uninvited to see what special delicacy they&amp;rsquo;ve made. Days when every single house is lit up and the smoke of firecrackers permeate everything. Such good memories&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diwali this year was super low key. We did light up some &lt;em&gt;Diyas&lt;/em&gt; and M had ordered some savory snacks from one of her local contacts. A few calls to family and I think we called it a day. Times when you miss being amongst family and friends. Happy Halloween and Diwali - I guess?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crisp new start</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/29/crisp-new-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 21:54:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/10/29/crisp-new-start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2007, WordPress has been home to most of my digital presence. Sometime last week one of the plugins – Wordfence, I think – took a major dump and nuked my site down. Didn&amp;rsquo;t quite see that coming but I take that as a sign for me to change things up a bit. I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to test out WriteFreely for a while now and this might be just about the right opportunity. I&amp;rsquo;m not quite suew how I want to handle the migration. For now though, it&amp;rsquo;s a brand new shiny slate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
