<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rock-Climbing on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/rock-climbing/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rock-Climbing on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/rock-climbing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>32 and onwards!</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/12/12/32-and-onwards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/12/12/32-and-onwards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/1513812908.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;Miss Me gifted me a months rock climbing pass for my birthday. Been at it for a few weeks now and we&amp;rsquo;re thoroughly loving it! Something that we&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to do for a while now and I&amp;rsquo;m psyched we got to start it on my birthday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We try and make it to the gym almost every day. After a long day at work it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how just entering that space helps clear your mind altogether! An hour in and though you&amp;rsquo;re physically tired, you walk out with so much more energy. Goes without saying, it also aligns  with one of my resolutions this year to work on my upper body strength.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last birthday, we went for an &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/12/12/flying-31-with-the-reindeer/&#34;&gt;indoor diving class&lt;/a&gt;, six months later we &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/06/12/ashtanga/&#34;&gt;started ashtanga&lt;/a&gt; and now this! Loving the trend!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where are my feet?</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2008/03/14/where-are-my-feet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2008/03/14/where-are-my-feet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m off to B&amp;rsquo;lore this weekend on a fast paced adventure trip :D . This is going to be HydVentura&amp;rsquo;s second outing, majorly organised by AdVentura folks in collab. with a few other professional groups in Bang. So it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be mighty interesting :-)!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Twenty one of us from the Hyd DC would be reaching Bangalore tomorrow morning, where we&amp;rsquo;d meet up with ppl from Mysore and Bangalore and move to Hoskote for a Parasailing stint. Once that&amp;rsquo;s done, we&amp;rsquo;d drive down to Anthargange for cave exploration, Rock climbing , Rappelling and brief treks en-route. In the evening we&amp;rsquo;d move over to Kalvarhallibetta base for a night camp :-) ! Sunday morning - 1:00am to 4:00am we&amp;rsquo;d trek up the hill to catch a glimpse of Sunrise at the and then we&amp;rsquo;d get back to the base and move to Nandi Hills as the final destination before we board the train back to Hyd from Yeshwanthpur. All of this in just two days :-)!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the first time, Hydventura folks would be meeting Adventura folks ( The Bang. adventure club) officially before we merge with other similar groups in India ( Pune, Chennai, Mysore, Jaipur, Chandigarh et al) to form one single entity - AdVenturaIndia :-)!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just hoping, I don&amp;rsquo;t get that expected mail from the HR asking me to report to Pune on Monday ! And, there&amp;rsquo;s also loads of work to get done before EOD :-( .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wishing for the best! :-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
