<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021-02-05 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/date/2021-02-05-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021-02-05 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/date/2021-02-05-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks - Feb 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/05/state-of-the-networks-feb-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/05/state-of-the-networks-feb-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A quick rundown on the state of the home-servers I run or applications I host on the cloud.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Published while listening to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://invidious.snopyta.org/watch?v=RlcY37n5j9M&#34;&gt;Malang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With our temporary relocation, I currently manage two &amp;lsquo;home-labs&amp;rsquo; - one which I remotely manage with a WireGuard tunnel and the other just a local-access only setup. The remote home-lab is essentially a Nextcloud server running on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dietpi.com/&#34;&gt;DietPi OS&lt;/a&gt; spun on an RPi4. I pulled down the HAProxy config on the fronting server since that was no longer required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Homelab-SoTN-Feb-2021-600x478.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The local home-lab currently encompasses four units:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ownyourbits.com/nextcloudpi/&#34;&gt;NextcloudPi&lt;/a&gt; running on an RPi3 and connected to a 1TB main drive: This has been our primary document and media backup servers silently chugging along for close to three years now!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osmc.tv/&#34;&gt;OSMC&lt;/a&gt; installed on another RPi3: With a 1TB media drive, Amazon video and Youtube addons this primarily serves as a secondary family Television. A bit on the sluggish end but does the job for now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DietPi running on an &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.odroid.com/odroid-xu4/odroid-xu4&#34;&gt;Odroid-XU4&lt;/a&gt;: Pi-Hole for Ad control and WireGuard to access the remote home-lab.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pop.system76.com/&#34;&gt;PoPOS&lt;/a&gt; running on an Intel NUC7: My primary workstation! An attached 1TB drive acts as the secondary backup for my NC setup and then I run sync jobs to a 256GB flash drive for a cold backup of the really important files.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then, on a remote VM I run a slew of services that handle most of my social and productivity tools. Fronted by Traefik and running in docker containers, the following services run on the 8GB server:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bookstackapp.com/&#34;&gt;Bookstack&lt;/a&gt; – Wiki software which I am currently using to help publish my dad’s second book&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://known.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;Known&lt;/a&gt; – I mostly use this as a quick bookmarking tool. I also post short updates or status notes here infrequently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wallabag.it/en&#34;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; – Read-later app&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/14/guyon-flats-and-tuffys-tavern-trail/&#34;&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt; – Way better than Instagram and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixel.srkn.org/sriperinkulam&#34;&gt;my go-to space&lt;/a&gt; to post individual images&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://selfoss.aditu.de/&#34;&gt;Minflux&lt;/a&gt; – The light-weight feed-reader that I pipe all my RSS subscriptions to&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium&#34;&gt;Trilium Notes&lt;/a&gt; – A terrific Evernote alternative with awesome Markdown support&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbernhard/signal-cli-rest-api&#34;&gt;Signal-CLI&lt;/a&gt; – I use this for server trigger notifications to be sent via SMS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://etherpad.org/&#34;&gt;Etherpad&lt;/a&gt; – Quick, collaborative notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptpad.fr/&#34;&gt;CryptPad&lt;/a&gt; - Collaboration suite for documents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Calibre - I use this to manage &lt;a href=&#34;https://lib.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;my digital books collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lychee - A nifty photo gallery where I currently save my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/08/26/stamp-collection-digitized/&#34;&gt;digital stamps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;WordPress – I run 4 instances of WordPress – Portals for folks in my family&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nextcloud – This one’s more to test the recent releases before I deploy them on my home-lab&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometime down the lane I would like to setup a &lt;a href=&#34;https://snikket.org/&#34;&gt;Snikket instance&lt;/a&gt; for family chats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
