<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Micro on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/micro/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Micro on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/micro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>QOL Upgrades</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/23/qol-upgrades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/23/qol-upgrades/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tweaked my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/lifemap&#34;&gt;Lifemap&lt;/a&gt; page a bit more and added a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/daynote&#34;&gt;Daily Note&lt;/a&gt; page for friction-less notes. Love how this is all coming together. Also in anticipation of the upcoming move, switched comment notifications to the public URL. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/23/qol-upgrades/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upset</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/22/upset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/22/upset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/upset.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not quite sure, what triggered it but S was super upset this morning. She walked over to the &amp;lsquo;sun&amp;rsquo; room and stood there for a good twenty minutes. And just like that she totally forgot about it all&amp;hellip;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/22/upset/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-Feb-23</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/daynote/2025-feb-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/daynote/2025-feb-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trying to implement something similar to DayOne. Essentially a place where I can dive in and jot quick notes for that day - not having to worry about frontmatter, templates etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I might have to do some minor tweaks on how images are displayed here similar to the photos page&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M went over to the Jewish neighborhood in Centro Historico for the Post Language Program trip. S &amp;amp; I stayed back. Got some paperwork done for our visas. Walked over to El Jardín Escénico on Reforma and from there head over to Ehden Restaurant to meet the PLP group there. Some decent Lebanese food, a delicious date cake and a TERRIFIC arabic coffee!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-Feb-22</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/daynote/2025-feb-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/daynote/2025-feb-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tinkered a bit with my Matrix installation. Upgrade went smooth but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to backfill my messages in &lt;em&gt;Element&lt;/em&gt;. Looks like the rooms get added back in only when some new message comes in. No biggie&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ESC Gifts</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/19/esc-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/19/esc-gifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/ESCGifts.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My colleague gifted me a walking pole engraved with everybody&amp;rsquo;s names as a going away gift. Loved it! The OBO RSTs got me some mezcal. Just in time before the packout tomorrow. Still got a week left here but boy, I am going to miss this bunch!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/19/esc-gifts/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025-Feb-20</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/daynote/2025-feb-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/daynote/2025-feb-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The packers came in today and boxed up most of our belongings. We&amp;rsquo;d already sorted stuff pretty decently, so they barely needed our intervention. Another team should come in tomorrow to load these out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last reforma ride!</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/16/last-reforma-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/16/last-reforma-ride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/victoryride.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since we got her training wheels off, S has been nervous riding down the small hill near the Chapultapec zoo for some reason. M convinced S to ride on Reforma one last time today. She nailed it! Rode all the way to the Angel statue and back without any fuss. With the movers packing all our things this thursday, this would probably be our last ride on Reforma! &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/16/last-reforma-ride/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/12/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/12/time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve got barely two weeks left here in CDMX! As with any move, we&amp;rsquo;ve been trimming our holdings down. Still amazed that I can fit almost all of my vital belongings into two 50 lbs suitcases. As a family our holdings weighed about 3000 lbs in total when we moved to Mexico city. Pretty sure we should be in that ball-park for this move too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Made the tough call NOT to hike Orizaba the coming weekend. I think I just didn&amp;rsquo;t have the mind space to plan it all out.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Decided to let go of the 3D Printer I bought from a colleague last year. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much time to tinker with it and it just sank in, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have a tough time getting the supplies shipped over to Yaounde. Some indulgences - invested or not - are probably just worth letting go!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tweaked my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/05/implementing-static-comments/&#34;&gt;comments code&lt;/a&gt; to send notifications to my NTFY channel when this site receives spam - just for kicks. And boy, it does seem to work. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/12/time/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing static comments</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/05/implementing-static-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/05/implementing-static-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/comments.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bit the bullet and setup a rudimentary comment system for this site. For the last few months, I relied on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/isso-comments/isso/&#34;&gt;ISSO&lt;/a&gt;, but it kinda felt a bit too heavy. Finally scratched the itch and switched over to a basic form and some javascript to push comments over to my self-hosted ntfy server. For now, I&amp;rsquo;ve left the moderation to manual mode - I have to copy over the comments manually from NTFY to a comments.json file. A GO script that usually publishes this site also builds the comments for each of the posts as needed  based on the posts&amp;rsquo; permalink. Pretty friction-less and nifty! &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/05/implementing-static-comments/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boba Stickers</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/01/boba-stickers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/01/boba-stickers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/BobaStickers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Santa is so magical. Coz he knows kids would like it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exploring her boba stickers which she received for Christmas last year.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/01/boba-stickers/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mari Gold</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/25/mari-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/25/mari-gold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NO &lt;a href=&#34;https://guide.michelin.com/us/en/ciudad-de-mexico/miguel-hidalgo_1999281/restaurant/mari-gold&#34;&gt;Mari Gold&lt;/a&gt; ! You don&amp;rsquo;t get to call - a wrap of leaf salad drizzled with vinagarette and some flavorless yam, doused in running egg yolk - a KATHI ROLL! Such a disgrace! Wasn&amp;rsquo;t too excited about going here initially and now I&amp;rsquo;m more than convinced not to look back once.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/25/mari-gold/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping GPX</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/24/mapping-gpx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/24/mapping-gpx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/GPXmapping.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Took me a bit but I finally got a decent handle on displaying the gpx summary on the gpx map. Still a bunch of tweaks to make this look better but super happy with how this is shaping. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/24/mapping-gpx/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Dell alert</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/13/blue-dell-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/13/blue-dell-alert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around 0300 today, I was woken up rudely to a blaring sound. For a moment I assumed it was from the Seismic City alert system that CDMX has. Turned out, it was from the old blue dell laptop that I currently use to run NextcloudPi. For some reason, looks like it rebooted and went into a huge panic mode because it lost time sync. Yanked all the cables and shut it down. Something to figure out over the next few days when I have time. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/13/blue-dell-alert/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>clara</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/10/clara/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/10/clara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;/s This turned out to be simpler than I thought. All I had to do was add all the libraries to the overdriive account on the desktop. And then login to that overdrive account on the Kobo. By design, only one card shows on the Kobo. To borrow books from a library not shown on the Kobo, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to fetch that on a separate device. So simple!  &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/10/clara/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Houston calling</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/05/houston-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/05/houston-calling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We wanted to make it to Houston during S&amp;rsquo; Christmas break, because we very well knew we might not come here during our home leave. Oh boy, what a trip this has been in terms of travel snafus! On our way there we got routed to San Antonio and got grounded for a couple hours because of inclement weather en-route.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/houston.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the way back, we thought we missed our connection in Dallas because of a delayed departure from Houston, and re-booked for a later flight from Dallas. However, our connecting flight was delayed too and when I checked at the counter in Dallas if we could get switched back to our previous booking, the attendant said that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible. M however was adamant and worked her magic. Looks like they had a &amp;lsquo;weight restriction&amp;rsquo; on the flight and M was able to convince them to flip back our reservations since we didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything to check-in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trip otherwise was pretty uneventful. Some good time with family, speckled with delicious home cooked food and some oh-so-okay outside food. Also note-to-self to make these trips shorter to just about two nights instead of week-long.&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/05/houston-calling/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
