<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Micro on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/micro/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Micro on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/micro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementing static comments</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/05/implementing-static-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/05/implementing-static-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/comments.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bit the bullet and setup a rudimentary comment system for this site. For the last few months, I relied on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/isso-comments/isso/&#34;&gt;ISSO&lt;/a&gt;, but it kinda felt a bit too heavy. Finally scratched the itch and switched over to a basic form and some javascript to push comments over to my self-hosted ntfy server. For now, I&amp;rsquo;ve left the moderation to manual mode - I have to copy over the comments manually from NTFY to a comments.json file. A GO script that usually publishes this site also builds the comments for each of the posts as needed  based on the posts&amp;rsquo; permalink. Pretty friction-less and nifty! &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/05/implementing-static-comments/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boba Stickers</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/01/boba-stickers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/01/boba-stickers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/BobaStickers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Santa is so magical. Coz he knows kids would like it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exploring her boba stickers which she received for Christmas last year.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/02/01/boba-stickers/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mari Gold</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/25/mari-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/25/mari-gold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NO &lt;a href=&#34;https://guide.michelin.com/us/en/ciudad-de-mexico/miguel-hidalgo_1999281/restaurant/mari-gold&#34;&gt;Mari Gold&lt;/a&gt; ! You don&amp;rsquo;t get to call - a wrap of leaf salad drizzled with vinagarette and some flavorless yam, doused in running egg yolk - a KATHI ROLL! Such a disgrace! Wasn&amp;rsquo;t too excited about going here initially and now I&amp;rsquo;m more than convinced not to look back once.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/25/mari-gold/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping GPX</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/24/mapping-gpx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/24/mapping-gpx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/GPXmapping.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Took me a bit but I finally got a decent handle on displaying the gpx summary on the gpx map. Still a bunch of tweaks to make this look better but super happy with how this is shaping. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/24/mapping-gpx/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Dell alert</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/13/blue-dell-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 06:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/13/blue-dell-alert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around 0300 today, I was woken up rudely to a blaring sound. For a moment I assumed it was from the Seismic City alert system that CDMX has. Turned out, it was from the old blue dell laptop that I currently use to run NextcloudPi. For some reason, looks like it rebooted and went into a huge panic mode because it lost time sync. Yanked all the cables and shut it down. Something to figure out over the next few days when I have time. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/13/blue-dell-alert/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>clara</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/10/clara/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/10/clara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;/s This turned out to be simpler than I thought. All I had to do was add all the libraries to the overdriive account on the desktop. And then login to that overdrive account on the Kobo. By design, only one card shows on the Kobo. To borrow books from a library not shown on the Kobo, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to fetch that on a separate device. So simple!  &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/10/clara/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Houston calling</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/05/houston-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/05/houston-calling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We wanted to make it to Houston during S&amp;rsquo; Christmas break, because we very well knew we might not come here during our home leave. Oh boy, what a trip this has been in terms of travel snafus! On our way there we got routed to San Antonio and got grounded for a couple hours because of inclement weather en-route.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/houston.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the way back, we thought we missed our connection in Dallas because of a delayed departure from Houston, and re-booked for a later flight from Dallas. However, our connecting flight was delayed too and when I checked at the counter in Dallas if we could get switched back to our previous booking, the attendant said that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be possible. M however was adamant and worked her magic. Looks like they had a &amp;lsquo;weight restriction&amp;rsquo; on the flight and M was able to convince them to flip back our reservations since we didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything to check-in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trip otherwise was pretty uneventful. Some good time with family, speckled with delicious home cooked food and some oh-so-okay outside food. Also note-to-self to make these trips shorter to just about two nights instead of week-long.&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/05/houston-calling/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carlos&#39; wedding</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/29/carlos-wedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/29/carlos-wedding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided not to drive to GDL for Carlos&amp;rsquo; wedding. Just not comfortable driving the GV until we get it properly serviced. Thankfully, we got a flight last minute and we head straight to the GDL zoo after landing. S has been wanting to see the penguins there for quite sometime now and what better opportunity than this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The zoo was immaculately maintained! And with the Sky-cables and trains, this was such a great experience. We checked in at the AC hotel for some short down time and then head to an Arabic restaurant for some pretty delicious wraps because we were quite certain M wouldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything vegetarian at the wedding. The wedding per se was super intimate with about 30 guests. I am glad we were able to fit this in despite a pretty packed end of the year. We head back to the hotel around 1145 just about when S was nearing her &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m done&lt;/em&gt; limit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/carlos_gdl.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next morning, we head to the vegan restaurant that M had scouted for a quick breakfast and get to the GDL airport just in time for the flight back to CDMX.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/29/carlos-wedding/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manaw</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/25/manaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 21:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/25/manaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/manaw.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;Never fails to impress &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/25/manaw/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Las Estacas</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/las-estacas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 23:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/las-estacas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;V+D were visiting us for a few days around Christmas this year. With the 24th declared a holiday, M suggested we go glamping in Estacas for a night. S loved the idea and we booked two tents for the five of us. Cost was super reasonable given it included breakfast and entry to the park.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/estacas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We only got to Estacas around 1400 on 24th evening thanks to the four hours we lost to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/&#34;&gt;brake fade on the Grand Vitara&lt;/a&gt;. After a quick check-in, we decide to rent a kayak and row down the stream. I hop off the kayak and swim upstream. S was bent on going to the kids pool alone and not getting into the spring. After about an hour, S &amp;amp; I head to the kids pool. She spends maybe 30 mins in there and calls it a day. Her only ask was that we have dinner by the spring, which we gladly agree to since that&amp;rsquo;s the only restaurant that was open. After dinner, S was sleepy but still super excited about spending the night in the tent. Happy kid, Happy camper! She sleeps through the night despite all the Christmas fireworks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/shas_estacas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We wake up to a super crisp and nippy 25th morning. V and I decide to snorkel/swim in the warm 23C spring water. We spot some sleeping turtles and a great many schools of fish feasting on their morning find. After a simple yet delicious breakfast we make our way back to CDMX. Probably one of our best stays in Estacas so far and I&amp;rsquo;m so glad we decided to glamp! Though S didn&amp;rsquo;t get into the spring, she absolutely enjoyed our trip. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/las-estacas/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kobo Clara</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/kobo-clara/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 21:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/kobo-clara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordered a Kobo Clara BW for M on a whim. Been a while that I&amp;rsquo;ve surprised her! Twelve years ago when I gifted her the Kindle she was initially super upset - we barely had any money then. This time around when she opened it, her reaction was neutral at best.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Setting it up wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite intuitive. Took me 20 minutes to figure out that the software wasn&amp;rsquo;t showing the option for overdrive sync because it sensed our location to be outside US/Canada. An easy fix until we hit the next issue - M only has a Libby account and that does not map 1:1 to an Overdrive account. Looks like I&amp;rsquo;ll have to setup an overdrive account now, add all her library cards and then sync that account in the Kobo. Reasonable ask I guess. But doesn&amp;rsquo;t really help my case of getting her to try off mainstream devices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brake fade</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/GrandVitaraCuernavaca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downhill and no brakes, what fun! Definitely not at that moment though. Somewhere near Cuernavaca, The Grand Vitara had a brake fade &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; this morning on our way to Las Estacas. The brakes would just not work and it felt like I had to pump it to get even a bit of traction.  Got  super close to hitting the car in front of us but thankfully, I found a small lane (ditch?) to veer off from the traffic and engine braked it to a stop. Super lucky none of us were hurt and we were able to veer away from traffic just in time. Also lucky that this happened just about 100m from a mechanic shop! What are the odds? Took them about three hours to do a &lt;del&gt;thorough&lt;/del&gt; check on all four wheels and fix the oil reservoir tray - which they broke while jacking the car up. Oh boy, what a start to this years&amp;rsquo; Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Immediately after we were able to get the vehicle to a stop, M asked if it was the floor mat that was the culprit. Nope - I&amp;rsquo;d removed them a few days after we bought this car. All thanks to another &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/04/26/the-grand-cherokee/&#34;&gt;dreadful experience&lt;/a&gt; several years ago in the Grand Cherokee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ignorance and oversight only make sense in hindsight.  About fifteen minutes before this incident,  I did notice the brakes feeling soft and remember thinking - that&amp;rsquo;s odd the brakes worked just fine so far. Also maybe I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice the smoke from the tires because we were driving through quasi dirt roads? All signs of the brakes giving in - had I known about brake fade then. Wee bit wiser now I guess? &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apparently that is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brake_fade&#34;&gt;technical term&lt;/a&gt; for a failed brake.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merida</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/20/merida/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/20/merida/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back from a productive work trip in Merida. Overall, I think it went great. Most of the planning over the last few months paid off and but for a few minor issues, we were able top wrap up coring the NCC in about three days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also found a few fantastic food options through the week. For lunch we mostly had to do an Uber eats since there weren&amp;rsquo;t many options around the new consulate. &lt;a href=&#34;https://habaneros.com.mx/&#34;&gt;Habaneros&lt;/a&gt; was the find of the week though. Their &lt;em&gt;Pimitos&lt;/em&gt; was on point!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This would most likely be my last work-trip to Merida. Time for some transition planning to hand the baton over.&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/20/merida/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Memory Palace</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/16/the-memory-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/16/the-memory-palace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/603-the-memory-palace-book/&#34;&gt;podcast from 99% invisible&lt;/a&gt; nudged me to get Nate DiMeo&amp;rsquo;s book - &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookshop.org/p/books/the-memory-palace-true-short-stories-of-the-past-nate-dimeo/21177599?ean=9780593446157&#34;&gt;The Memory Palace&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved the Memory Palace podcast. Super intrigued to see how Nate carries over the suspense in written form. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/16/the-memory-palace/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Piping hot</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/15/piping-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/15/piping-hot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing to beat sunning on a calm and quite weekend morning with some steaming hot coffee.&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;image-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;ul class=&#34;photo-list single-image&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;             &#xA;             &#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&#xA;                &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/15/piping-hot/images/20241215_082140.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./images/20241215_082140.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20241215_082140.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;a&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;.photo-list {&#xA;    display: flex;  &#xA;    flex-wrap: wrap;  &#xA;    margin: -1px;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list &gt; li {&#xA;    height: 40vh;  &#xA;    flex-grow: 1;  &#xA;    list-style-type: none;  &#xA;    margin: 1px;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list li img {&#xA;    max-height: 100%;  &#xA;    min-width: 100%;  &#xA;    object-fit: cover;  &#xA;    vertical-align: bottom;  &#xA;    border: 2px solid gray;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list li:last-child {&#xA;    flex-grow: 10;  &#xA;    border: none;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA; &#xA;.photo-list.single-image &gt; li {&#xA;    height: auto;  &#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/15/piping-hot/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
