<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adirondacks on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/adirondacks/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adirondacks on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/adirondacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Appalachians next!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/10/08/appalachians-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/10/08/appalachians-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Ragnar.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Ragnar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ragnar&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t have ended September on a better note! Pounding the hilly terrain in the Adirondacks for 36 hrs, straight through the night with 9 other folks - This has been my best run so far. Though technically that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of time for 197 miles, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s the nuances of the event that really gives you the extra kick.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Running on those hills for miles at night with just absolute darkness for company, the sudden sprint from a water-station when you realized it was tactfully positioned right in front of a cemetery, the thrill of handing over the slap band to the next runner at the end of your run, the last one mile which never felt so close and that particular runner who always seems to cross you on every single uphill - few things that is quite uncommon in other running events. To top all of that, the camaraderie that emerges from participating in an event of such a scale just cannot be replicated in any other event.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looks like I&amp;rsquo;m more than &amp;lsquo;addicted&amp;rsquo; to these Ragnar events and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to start training for yet another run. My feet yearn for a good trail run and how wonderful it would be if I could blend that in with a Ragnar event. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ragnartrail.com/locations/appalachians-wv&#34;&gt;Appalachians next!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  Will probably fit in a couple of half&amp;rsquo;s in between just to keep the muscles working.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ragnar times</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/09/23/ragnar-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/09/23/ragnar-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Fort-lee.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Fort-lee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fort lee&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Friday, I&amp;rsquo;d be doing a 200 mile relay run at Adirondacks, NY with 9 other family friends .  This one is extra special for several reasons. Few months back, an ankle injury prevented me from running the Bear Mountain State Park Half Marathon - a run I was really looking forward to. That setback and the recovery from the injury further fueled my training for the Adirondacks Ragnar relay run. In the last two months,  I&amp;rsquo;ve explored more trails than I did all over the last year and a half. I&amp;rsquo;ve had stronger 8 mile and 10 mile finishes than ever before. More importantly, I&amp;rsquo;m truly enjoying running and the places it&amp;rsquo;s taking me to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This weekend would be a good gauge to set targets on an ultra run sometime soon. And I guess the &amp;lsquo;kick&amp;rsquo; is not in the distance but the distances it would take me to and the experiences that would come by. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to leave school tomorrow evening for the mega weekend. Ragnar - Here we come!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
