<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/coding/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coding on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Owning my Garmin data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/29/owning-my-garmin-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/29/owning-my-garmin-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last month, I took some time to build a tiny WordPress plugin that fetches data from my Garmin Connect platform and displays it on my website. Currently the workflow only pulls activity data from the platform - which was my focus for this month. With modifications to the python script, I think this can be extended further to fetch any type of data from the platform. Here&amp;rsquo;s a rundown of the publishing workflow so far:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bluetooth Sync data from the watch to the Garmin connect portal. This is manual since I see no point in having Bluetooth turned on 24/7&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Edit the activity in the Garmin connect app for say activity title, activity type or just add some more context to the workout&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A cron job runs on my website twice every week to trigger &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/johannesh83/garmin-connect-export&#34;&gt;this python script&lt;/a&gt; in my WordPress plugin. I made slight modifications to the script so as to tie-in with my workflow.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The python script connects to my Garmin connect account, pulls the latest three activities and saves them as JSON files on my server.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/garmin-stats/&#34;&gt;garmin-stats page&lt;/a&gt; when requested by a client, parses the JSON file for each activity and displays the content in a predefined format. There&amp;rsquo;s also a provision to publish a specific activity as an individual post. If I&amp;rsquo;m logged in WordPress, a &amp;lsquo;Publish this&amp;rsquo; button is displayed for activities that have not been posted yet.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Currently I am assigning all of these posts to the &amp;lsquo;workout&amp;rsquo; category and I&amp;rsquo;ve disabled these from showing up on my main RSS feed. These posts however do show up on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/micro/&#34;&gt;micro-posts&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To-do&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The script currently triggers a &amp;lsquo;Garmin login alert&amp;rsquo; email for my account. Most likely because of locale settings. Would be good to mute these.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The plugin code currently dynamically generates the summary page on 200+ JSON files. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably limit this to just 20 or so.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fetch non activity data too.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maps, charts, visualizations!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always scope for cosmetic tweaks!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Micro updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/05/08/may-7-2021-1431/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 7, 2021 14:31&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/05/12/garmin-plugin/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 11, 2021 19:19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving files from all subdirectories without the tree structure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2020/04/19/moving-files-from-all-subdirectories-without-the-tree-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2020/04/19/moving-files-from-all-subdirectories-without-the-tree-structure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Appa, who&amp;rsquo;s very active on Facebook, recently wanted an easy way to sift through his old videos and photos that were up on his account. I decided to take a dump of his data from the network using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/dyi/&#34;&gt;download your information&lt;/a&gt; section. I initiated the process with just a few clicks and after a few days, I was able to download the zipped files of all the content he had posted on FB. including the likes, messages, shares etc. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, I would strongly recommend you get a copy of your data. I rarely interact on Facebook these days so it was even more interesting to see all the information they collect on you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, once I had the zipped files, I wanted to sift through the folder structure and copy over all the media from it to a specific location. Using a combination of the tree and find commands this was pretty straightforward. Logging them here for later reference:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;List files with tree hierarchy:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;tree&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find all files within the current directory and nested sub-directories and move them to specific folder:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;find . -print -name &amp;quot;*_.*_&amp;quot; -type f -exec mv -n {} /path/to/destination/directory/ \;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once I had the files [Totally about 25Gb], I realised I had to move them over to my dad&amp;rsquo;s machine. Good old &lt;a href=&#34;https://syncthing.net/&#34;&gt;Syncthing&lt;/a&gt; came to use here to send over the files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network auto-latch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/10/25/network-auto-latch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019/10/25/network-auto-latch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I realised the raspberry pi that hosts my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/?s=nextcloud&#34;&gt;nextcloud setup&lt;/a&gt; wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite latching back on to the network if the router was turned off or if the internet was sketchy. Was a pain to hard boot the device manually to reset it. Decided to write a short script to reset the network connection when it noticed something was off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#xA;ping -c4 192.168.0.1 &amp;gt; /dev/null&#xA;if [ $? != 0 ] &#xA;then&#xA;  echo &amp;#34;SOS..Restarting eth0 for network latch&amp;#34;&#xA;  /sbin/ifdown &amp;#39;eth0&amp;#39;&#xA;  sleep 5&#xA;  /sbin/ifup --force &amp;#39;eth0&amp;#39;&#xA;fi&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;A chron job runs every 10 minutes to take pulse of the network, runs the above code and picks up connectivity without manual intervention!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Independence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/06/02/independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/06/02/independence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As planned a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2017/05/26/tweaks-and-squeaks/&#34;&gt;few days&lt;/a&gt; back, I rewrote some back-end code to minimize the dependency on the workflow app and better integrate with direct desktop publishing. But for a  few isolated kinks, this should be set. This should now give me more flexibility to post from indie publishing platforms and set the stage for other enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
