<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homelab on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/homelab/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homelab on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks - Jan 2020</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/02/04/state-of-the-networks-jan-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/02/04/state-of-the-networks-jan-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A quick rundown on the state of the home-servers I run or applications I host on the cloud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week I opened up my Nextcloud instance for external access. Now, since my brother&amp;rsquo;s RPi4 was already exposed on the same network, I had to setup a reverse proxy on another RPi3 to access both simultaneously behind the router. Here&amp;rsquo;s the current setup:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/State-of-the-Network-Jan-2020-.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proxy server:&lt;/strong&gt; An RPi3 running on Raspbian Buster Lite with HAProxy installed to handle the reverse proxy. Here&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/23fee95d454fe3a9ff18a0555734e3ab&#34;&gt;gist of the code&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;rsquo;s handling all the heavy lifting. Since SSL is handled by the other servers themselves, all I needed was a quick pass-through handshake from HAProxy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server 01:&lt;/strong&gt; An RPi3 running on NextcloudPi essentially serving Nextcloud for all my file needs. Data is simultaneously backed up on a couple machines within the network. Decided against a remote backup [S3/Backblaze] for now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server 02:&lt;/strong&gt; An RPi4 running on Diet-Pi and serving Pi-Hole and a Nextcloud instance. I&amp;rsquo;ve turned off DHCP on the Orbi router and delegated that to the Pi-Hole. Both the Pi-Hole and the router have static IPs assigned to the SBCs and my trusty Dell machine based on their MAC address. I&amp;rsquo;m debating if I should move the Pi-Hole over to the Proxy Server&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beyond the home-lab, I have a droplet with DigitalOcean serving this website and a few other portals I manage. ServerPilot runs in the background on that droplet taking care of all the critical needs. I do intend to shift this over to a home-lab once I get hold of my ODroid XU4 which is currently in the Uganda shipment several thousand miles away in Chennai!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early this year, I also procured a Hetzner cloud instance to test its stability and see if I could move over certain portals to it. Should say I&amp;rsquo;m pretty impressed! Running on Debian Stretch and powered by Yunohost, I installed &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixel.srkn.org/sriperinkulam&#34;&gt;PixelFed&lt;/a&gt; and Wallabag. Installation has never been any easier! One drawback for sure is that the code-base may be a bit lagged as it gets deployed on Yunohost. Nevertheless, it&amp;rsquo;s pure magic to see things getting installed with just a few clicks and not much back-end work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then, I manage a Moodle Bitnami instance running on an AWS instance. I intend to move it over to the Hetzner cloud over the next month or so.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
