<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2009-08-13 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2009-08-13-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2009-08-13 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/date/2009-08-13-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber slices on the plate...</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2009/08/13/cucumber-slices-on-the-plate.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2009/08/13/cucumber-slices-on-the-plate.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last one month has been real crazy with a sudden upsurge in activity. Every other day a fresh thought pops up to do things in a different manner. The list of To-Do just gets bigger and bigger. Just thought I&amp;rsquo;d document them on a regular basis to keep the pulse on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/themorondiaries&#34;&gt;The Book&lt;/a&gt; - Been working on compiling a book of my treks/travels. This is turning out to be one mega affair. Quite complicated and time consuming. Seriously getting a book out is NO joke!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AUPS - Been regularly visiting the Arundati Upper Primary school every Saturday to take English classes for grade 6 kids.  Man, these kids really need mighty help. Their standards are so damn low! Makes me wonder at times how effective these two hours a week is really going to be. But it has to go on!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HydVentura - But for a couple of us there aren&amp;rsquo;t many interested in taking up the reins. People just want to have everything organised for them! Of late, the club has become quite popular. In fact I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting calls from quite a few folks requesting outings to be arranged for their groups. Somehow need to find means to make the club less dependent on just a couple of people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Site maintenance - Currently administering three portals - The HydVentura site, &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com&#34;&gt;My own site&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://perinkulams.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Dad&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;. At times it becomes a real pain to keep a tab on them. So far so good though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GMAT - One of the few important decisions taken. This seems to be one major thing that&amp;rsquo;s tightening the ropes. Morning rides during weekends are sacrificed for the classes and The Official guide has now replaced the novels / books which I otherwise used to read during the 1hr commute to work during weekdays.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Work - Things seem to have caught up pretty fast. Right from a rise in the number of requests to client calls received at home. Last months been one hectic patch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Riding - This had taken a backseat thanks to the Chestburn. Back to form now though. The next big ride is chalked out this weekend - The 62km Freedom ride. About 175  riders in the city would be riding togetherfor a cause. Eagerly looking forward to it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reading - Completed Into thin Air and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Himalaya_%28book%29&#34;&gt;Himalaya&lt;/a&gt; . Two must read books for any travel enthusiast! Currently reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2005/feb/06/scienceandnature.society&#34;&gt;Blink: The Power of Thinking Without Thinking.&lt;/a&gt; Plan to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three_Men_in_a_Boat&#34;&gt;Three men in a Boat&lt;/a&gt; next!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
