<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/posts/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2025-01-10 21:30:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/10/clara/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/10/clara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;/s This turned out to be simpler than I thought. All I had to do was add all the libraries to the overdriive account on the desktop. And then login to that overdrive account on the Kobo. By design, only one card shows on the Kobo. To borrow books from a library not shown on the Kobo, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to fetch that on a separate device. So simple!  &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2025/01/10/clara/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-25 21:21:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/25/manaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 21:21:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/25/manaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/manaw.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;Never fails to impress &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/25/manaw/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-24 23:30:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/las-estacas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 23:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/las-estacas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;V+D were visiting us for a few days around Christmas this year. With the 24th declared a holiday, M suggested we go glamping in Estacas for a night. S loved the idea and we booked two tents for the five of us. Cost was super reasonable given it included breakfast and entry to the park.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/estacas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We only got to Estacas around 1400 on 24th evening thanks to the four hours we lost to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/&#34;&gt;brake fade on the Grand Vitara&lt;/a&gt;. After a quick check-in, we decide to rent a kayak and row down the stream. I hop off the kayak and swim upstream. S was bent on going to the kids pool alone and not getting into the spring. After about an hour, S &amp;amp; I head to the kids pool. She spends maybe 30 mins in there and calls it a day. Her only ask was that we have dinner by the spring, which we gladly agree to since that&amp;rsquo;s the only restaurant that was open. After dinner, S was sleepy but still super excited about spending the night in the tent. Happy kid, Happy camper! She sleeps through the night despite all the Christmas fireworks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/shas_estacas.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We wake up to a super crisp and nippy 25th morning. V and I decide to snorkel/swim in the warm 23C spring water. We spot some sleeping turtles and a great many schools of fish feasting on their morning find. After a simple yet delicious breakfast we make our way back to CDMX. Probably one of our best stays in Estacas so far and I&amp;rsquo;m so glad we decided to glamp! Though S didn&amp;rsquo;t get into the spring, she absolutely enjoyed our trip. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/las-estacas/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-24 21:31:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/kobo-clara/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 21:31:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/kobo-clara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordered a Kobo Clara BW for M on a whim. Been a while that I&amp;rsquo;ve surprised her! Twelve years ago when I gifted her the Kindle she was initially super upset - we barely had any money then. This time around when she opened it, her reaction was neutral at best.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Setting it up wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite intuitive. Took me 20 minutes to figure out that the software wasn&amp;rsquo;t showing the option for overdrive sync because it sensed our location to be outside US/Canada. An easy fix until we hit the next issue - M only has a Libby account and that does not map 1:1 to an Overdrive account. Looks like I&amp;rsquo;ll have to setup an overdrive account now, add all her library cards and then sync that account in the Kobo. Reasonable ask I guess. But doesn&amp;rsquo;t really help my case of getting her to try off mainstream devices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-24 21:30:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/GrandVitaraCuernavaca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downhill and no brakes, what fun! Definitely not at that moment though. Somewhere near Cuernavaca, The Grand Vitara had a brake fade &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; this morning on our way to Las Estacas. The brakes would just not work and it felt like I had to pump it to get even a bit of traction.  Got  super close to hitting the car in front of us but thankfully, I found a small lane (ditch?) to veer off from the traffic and engine braked it to a stop. Super lucky none of us were hurt and we were able to veer away from traffic just in time. Also lucky that this happened just about 100m from a mechanic shop! What are the odds? Took them about three hours to do a &lt;del&gt;thorough&lt;/del&gt; check on all four wheels and fix the oil reservoir tray - which they broke while jacking the car up. Oh boy, what a start to this years&amp;rsquo; Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Immediately after we were able to get the vehicle to a stop, M asked if it was the floor mat that was the culprit. Nope - I&amp;rsquo;d removed them a few days after we bought this car. All thanks to another &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2016/04/26/the-grand-cherokee/&#34;&gt;dreadful experience&lt;/a&gt; several years ago in the Grand Cherokee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ignorance and oversight only make sense in hindsight.  About fifteen minutes before this incident,  I did notice the brakes feeling soft and remember thinking - that&amp;rsquo;s odd the brakes worked just fine so far. Also maybe I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice the smoke from the tires because we were driving through quasi dirt roads? All signs of the brakes giving in - had I known about brake fade then. Wee bit wiser now I guess? &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/24/brake-fade/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apparently that is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brake_fade&#34;&gt;technical term&lt;/a&gt; for a failed brake.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-20 21:30:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/20/merida/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/20/merida/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back from a productive work trip in Merida. Overall, I think it went great. Most of the planning over the last few months paid off and but for a few minor issues, we were able top wrap up coring the NCC in about three days.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also found a few fantastic food options through the week. For lunch we mostly had to do an Uber eats since there weren&amp;rsquo;t many options around the new consulate. &lt;a href=&#34;https://habaneros.com.mx/&#34;&gt;Habaneros&lt;/a&gt; was the find of the week though. Their &lt;em&gt;Pimitos&lt;/em&gt; was on point!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This would most likely be my last work-trip to Merida. Time for some transition planning to hand the baton over.&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/20/merida/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-16 21:30:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/16/the-memory-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 21:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/16/the-memory-palace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/603-the-memory-palace-book/&#34;&gt;podcast from 99% invisible&lt;/a&gt; nudged me to get Nate DiMeo&amp;rsquo;s book - &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookshop.org/p/books/the-memory-palace-true-short-stories-of-the-past-nate-dimeo/21177599?ean=9780593446157&#34;&gt;The Memory Palace&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved the Memory Palace podcast. Super intrigued to see how Nate carries over the suspense in written form. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/16/the-memory-palace/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-15 06:30:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/15/piping-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/15/piping-hot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing to beat sunning on a calm and quite weekend morning with some steaming hot coffee.&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;image-gallery&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;ul class=&#34;photo-list single-image&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;             &#xA;            &lt;li&gt;&#xA;                &lt;img src=&#34;./images/20241215_082140.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20241215_082140.jpg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;            &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;style&gt;&#xA;.photo-list {&#xA;    display: flex;  &#xA;    flex-wrap: wrap;  &#xA;    margin: -1px;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list &gt; li {&#xA;    height: 40vh;  &#xA;    flex-grow: 1;  &#xA;    list-style-type: none;  &#xA;    margin: 1px;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list li img {&#xA;    max-height: 100%;  &#xA;    min-width: 100%;  &#xA;    object-fit: cover;  &#xA;    vertical-align: bottom;  &#xA;    border: 2px solid gray;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;.photo-list li:last-child {&#xA;    flex-grow: 10;  &#xA;    border: none;  &#xA;}&#xA;&#xA; &#xA;.photo-list.single-image &gt; li {&#xA;    height: auto;  &#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/style&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/15/piping-hot/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-12 21:25:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/12/rewind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 21:25:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/12/rewind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Built a &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/rewind&#34;&gt;Rewind&lt;/a&gt; page to nudge me to read my older posts. Interesting to see how my thought processes and writing has shifted over the years. This might also serve as a tool to fix any issues that might have crept in when I migrated over to Hugo. While at it, I also tweaked the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/archives&#34;&gt;archives&lt;/a&gt; page a bit to make it less dense.&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/12/rewind/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last mile closures</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/09/last-mile-closures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 23:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/09/last-mile-closures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of my free time over the last few days has been spent trying to implement the comments section on this site. Something that would have been super straightforward on a regular CMS is not quite so for a static site. Initially I tinkered with the idea of side-loading the comments feature over to the fediverse. It worked okay but it did feel quite choppy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking around a bit, I decided to give &lt;a href=&#34;https://isso-comments.de/&#34;&gt;ISSO&lt;/a&gt; a chance. It seemed to have all the features I was looking for and was reasonably easy to setup. As with most things tech though, I had quite some difficulty tweaking it to work the way I wanted it to. Taking a break and getting back to it after a few days, did get me to approach this from a different perspective and I think it&amp;rsquo;s super close to where I&amp;rsquo;d like it to be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On certain things, I am perfectly okay leaving things half baked and cutting my losses. On most things though, I do like seeing things to closure. There&amp;rsquo;s so much thrill in figuring out why something is not working the way it is supposed to. Most often it&amp;rsquo;s because of something ridiculously silly or because of minor oversights. Trials and tribulations of the last mile closures, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For now, this site has a basic commenting system and that gives me enough momentum to pursue other things to tweak. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/09/last-mile-closures/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-06 21:39:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/06/flexibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 21:39:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/06/flexibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Absolutely loving the flexibility of fast-tweaking markdown files in GO. I&amp;rsquo;m far from being a programmer/developer, but with a dash of AI and some bare minimum logic sense, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to build scripts to do a bunch of modifications on this site on the go. &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/06/flexibility/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-06 00:36:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/06/ca-aefm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:36:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/06/ca-aefm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;M just received an invite for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.state.gov/global-community-liaison-office/overseas-family-member-employment/family-member-employment-within-a-u-s-embassy-or-consulate/consular-affairs-appointment-eligible-family-member-program/&#34;&gt;CA-AEFM&lt;/a&gt; March&#39;25 cohort. Long overdue! Adds a small wrench to our planning for the PCS next year but as Pappaji says - it&amp;rsquo;s a Happy problem! Super excited! &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/06/ca-aefm/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-02 22:30:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/02/maintenance-of-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 22:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/02/maintenance-of-everything/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not quite sure when or where I came across this open book - &lt;a href=&#34;https://books.worksinprogress.co/book/maintenance-of-everything/the-maintenance-race/the-maintenance-race/7&#34;&gt;Maintenance: of everything&lt;/a&gt;. Fascinating read so far and I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did save it in my quick notes whenever I did! &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/02/maintenance-of-everything/&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: none !important;&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-01 22:26:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/01/all-hugod-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 22:26:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/01/all-hugod-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got some decent progress on tweaking this portal. All hugo&amp;rsquo;d out for now though and a short break is overdue. Super slow weekend otherwise. Watched Moana 2. Meh. Not much story but decent visuals. Tragedy of sequels, maybe?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-12-01 00:30:00</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/01/2024-12-01-003000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:30:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2024/12/01/2024-12-01-003000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moved over the syndication links in my posts to post-meta. The syndication icon only shows up if a valid link is present in the FrontMatter of a post. Once micro.blog picks up the feed, it&amp;rsquo;s currently set to auto publish to the fediverse on my GoToSocial (GTS) instance.  On the backend, a GO script fetches the RSS feed from my GTS instance and saves the RSS feed item link and the corresponding link to my post in a JSON file. Another script quickly looks up which post&amp;rsquo;s FrontMatter needs to be updated for the syndication links in each post and updates the files as needed. A bit windy but seems to do the job for now. I might end up consolidating these into just one script later and/or directly use the masto API to publish to the fediverse and grab the syndication link from there. For now, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty psyched this is all working.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
