<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry-Pi3 on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/raspberry-pi3/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry-Pi3 on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/raspberry-pi3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bringing the cloud home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/02/26/bringing-the-cloud-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019/02/26/bringing-the-cloud-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got my Shoebox server setup working! I now have three Single board Computer [SBC] working in tandem behind my home router to accomplish what I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to do for quite sometime now - Setting up an easy-to-maintain, in-house server for all my data and web hosting needs. Fixing this all together has been a tremendous learning experience. I still need to weed out some pesky issues but I believe I have the bearing right now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my current setup:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ownyourbits.com/nextcloudpi/&#34;&gt;NexcloudPi&lt;/a&gt; installed on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/products/raspberry-pi-3-model-b-plus/&#34;&gt;Raspberry pi 3B+&lt;/a&gt; board&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://yunohost.org/#/&#34;&gt;Yunohost&lt;/a&gt; installed on an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hardkernel.com/shop/odroid-xu4-special-price/&#34;&gt;Odroid XU4&lt;/a&gt; board&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dietpi.com/&#34;&gt;Diet-Pi&lt;/a&gt; installed on another Raspberry pi 3B+ board&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Nextcloud as my data storage solution for more than a year now. It does what I expect it to do and much more. NextcloudPi handles the intricate details and takes out the hassles that come with hosting data on personal servers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the ODroid-XU4, I installed debian stretch as the base OS and then manually installed Yunohost as my web server. I use ServerPilot on my Digital ocean servers and was looking for a close match while self hosting. Love YHs web-ui and they did seem to support quite a few web apps. I also have my eyes on &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.cozy.io/en/tutorials/selfhost-debian/&#34;&gt;cozy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://caprover.com/&#34;&gt;caprover&lt;/a&gt;. Might explore these at a later point in time if decide to switch to a different SBC.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both NextcloudPi and Yunohost have letsencrypt tools to setup and manage certificates for the domains/sub domains. While super useful, I realised to benefit from that feature, I had to rely on haproxy. With some &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.nextcloud.com/t/accessing-nextcloudpi-behind-haproxy/47489&#34;&gt;pointers from the Nextcloud forum&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to use another pi to front as the main server. Installed Diet-pi on it since it&amp;rsquo;s just something I really liked and configured haproxy on it to map to the corresponding server based on the hostname. While at it, I also added in a switch between the router and various servers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I still need to work on making this more robust. One niggling issue is the speed is heavily compromised. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing it&amp;rsquo;s do with my haproxy config and I should be able to fix it pretty soon. Once I have this sorted out, I need to spend some time hardening the security of the server, further configure Yunohost, device my backup strategies and finally moving my websites over from Digital Ocean.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fired up!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/11/04/fired-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/11/04/fired-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/1509819219.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;Finally got around procuring a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/products/raspberry-pi-3-model-b/&#34;&gt;pi3&lt;/a&gt; and setup the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nextcloud.com/box&#34;&gt;Nextcloud Box&lt;/a&gt;! Getting this up and running was super fun and pretty straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The OS Image that was delivered with the box was built for the pi2. So I had to format the drive with Gparted and flashed the pi3 image with &lt;a href=&#34;https://etcher.io/&#34;&gt;Etcher&lt;/a&gt; (One nifty piece of software!). Once the hardware was fired up, it just took care of itself. The web install was a 1-click setup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early this year as I initiated taking more control over my data, I also setup a &lt;a href=&#34;https://meandsri.ddns.net&#34;&gt;Nextcloud server on the cloud&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s been about eight months now and am thoroughly impressed with it. With the incredible iOS and android apps and the nifty client for linux I&amp;rsquo;m more than convinced the take this a step further and setup my personal home server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the next few weeks as I tinker more with this, I need to make this a more robust setup and make full use of the snappy Ubuntu core.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/cropped-cropped-SP01-550afdebv1_site_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com&#34;&gt;Srikanth Perinkulam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/cropped-cropped-SP01-550afdebv1_site_icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com&#34;&gt;Srikanth Perinkulam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/favorite?tweet_id=926942668512428032&#34;&gt;like&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?tweet_id=926942668512428032&#34;&gt;reply&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/retweet?tweet_id=926942668512428032&#34;&gt;repost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/favorite?tweet_id=926942668512428032&#34;&gt;like&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?tweet_id=926942668512428032&#34;&gt;reply&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intent/retweet?tweet_id=926942668512428032&#34;&gt;repost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
