<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hydventura-Snaps on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/hydventura-snaps/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hydventura-Snaps on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/hydventura-snaps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Of things that you chose to miss...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/21/of-things-that-you-chose-to-miss.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2009/01/21/of-things-that-you-chose-to-miss.../</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I happened to check the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tourisminap.com/home/intro.php&#34; title=&#34;Official APTDC site&#34;&gt;AP tourism site&lt;/a&gt; yesterday. Believe me. I literally dropped my jaws seeing the first intro page. I guess finally the government has realised the tremendous potential tourism has and decided to tap on it. AP tourism and development corp. is now having the facility of customised tours. Can you beat that? The site lists most of the places in AP and has been developed with the traveller in mind.You can plan your travel and the places that you want to visit and just drop them a request. They&amp;rsquo;d soon get back to you on that. Such a drastic change is highly commendable! We&amp;rsquo;re a bit late on this front but thankfully, there&amp;rsquo;s at least noticeable progress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a shame to the third degree that we Indians, do not have the interest to explore our own homeland before we proceed to cross the seas during our vacations.There&amp;rsquo;s so MUCH that there&amp;rsquo;s to see in India, that believe me you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t cover one eighth of it in even a two month long vacation.You could have a much more memorable vacation here than shelling out thousands of rupees on an Hawaiian beach or Mauritian visit.Agreed each place has got it&amp;rsquo;s own splendour and inviting features, But how sane is it to look for paradise thousands of miles away when you have one right in your backyard?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would primarily attribute the influx of tourists to India to word of mouth than to the publicity campaigns by the government. We&amp;rsquo;ve a long long way to go to reach the international standards in tourism and that definitely is a mammoth challenge. It&amp;rsquo;s high time we pull our socks and get things rolling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to be posted in Pune for close to six months last year and am myself shocked to see the stats in front of me at the end of the stay. I&amp;rsquo;ve never stayed home a single weekend all through my stay there but still, I&amp;rsquo;ve not even covered 30 percent of the sight-seeing spots close to the city! If a small city like Pune in the western region of India has so much to offer, I leave it to you to judge what whole lot of things we&amp;rsquo;re missing out in ditching our own boat and jumping over to the ship sailing past us.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Click on the image below to have a peek into a few places that I&amp;rsquo;ve covered during the last year. [ 90pc of the pictures in the second half of the presentation are taken in places around Pune. ]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
