<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/tech/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:41:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024-11-29 22:41:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/11/29/2024-11-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 22:41:00 -0500</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/11/29/2024-11-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just struck me that most of my disk drives are quite old. Almost all of them were salvaged from old laptops. Age does not necessarily equate to performance and I do have decent backups, but only a question of time before I see them going kaput. Living vicariously on the edge when it comes to self-hosting!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-11-01 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/11/01/running-on-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/11/01/running-on-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/posts/2024/10/crisp-new-start/&#34;&gt;That&lt;/a&gt;  didn&amp;rsquo;t last long. Moved over to Hugo from WriteFreely for a bit more flexibility. This site is going through some major overhaul. Slowly and recklessly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-01-06 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/01/06/desk-organizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/01/06/desk-organizer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240105_223326623482290447895837.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bought a desk organizer a few weeks ago to arrange all my micro systems. The NUC, RPi NCP, Odroid and routers all now sit neatly in one space. The sliding shelves are an added bonus and the open back and sides give a lot of space for air circulation and cable management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cable talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/22/cable-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/22/cable-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple weeks, a colleague and I have been trying to clean up the cable mismanagement behind our racks. To work on the equipment you&amp;rsquo;re literally standing on about 1 feet of coiled cable mess. This issue has probably been there over the last several years and nobody has paid much attention to it. Likely because it does not affect the actual functioning of the equipment? And also, this is painstakingly unrewarding work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every single day we&amp;rsquo;ve been behind those racks, we keep thinking - why would someone leave so much of surplus cable and more importantly leave it so disorganized? I believe the reasons are multi-fold. Experience (or lack thereof), workmanship issues, time constraints, personnel turnovers and culmination of several unintentional judgement calls is what comes to mind. And then it also strikes me that I&amp;rsquo;m probably making a heavy judgement without having exposure to the situation my predecessors were dealing with? There was probably a solid reason why they had left so much slack in the cable. We will never know. Ultimately we&amp;rsquo;re here and we&amp;rsquo;re working on this ‘mess’. A few years down the lane my successors would probably think why the cables were so short and didn&amp;rsquo;t have much surplus. I guess you just take a call on what&amp;rsquo;s right at this moment and hope it works for the next few years…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In work environments where there&amp;rsquo;s heavy turnover - either because of the nature of the job or because of the team dynamics, how do you set the bar for quality workmanship?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022-03-06 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/03/06/tiny-troubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/03/06/tiny-troubles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Imagepipe_9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of late, the NUC has been getting really hot. Core CPU temperatures were hitting the 80s despite the system being on literally no load. When I first bought it in mid-2020, I was aware that this lineage of tiny monsters were known for their &amp;lsquo;hot&amp;rsquo;ness and the fan being a bit loud.  Only over the last few months have I really seen this sudden spike in temperatures though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first obvious step was to get rid of the plastic lid and get those aluminum heat-sinks. That helped a bit until yesterday when the temps shot to the 90s for no reason. A quick &lt;strong&gt;htop&lt;/strong&gt; run didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to show any processes that were hogging resources. Troubleshooting this a bit further, I figured I did run some apt updates a few days back that triggered Kernel updates. I might now have to get into the BIOS and see if any firmware updates are pending. As luck might have it though, the current keyboard that I have functions via Bluetooth only and I can&amp;rsquo;t quite use it to get into the BIOS. I do have an alternate keyboard, again Bluetooth but this one comes with a USB receiver - which I conveniently left in my tech black-box in MD! 🤦 Really hope M doesn&amp;rsquo;t forget bringing it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For now, I installed the &lt;strong&gt;cpupower-gui&lt;/strong&gt; tool and set the Governor to &amp;lsquo;powersave&amp;rsquo; mode. Does seem to have done the trick for now. I might have to open up the unit and see if it needs some deep cleaning with some compressed air. Sometime soon I guess!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/governor-1200x608.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks – Feb 2022</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/22/state-of-the-networks-feb-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/22/state-of-the-networks-feb-2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A bi-yearly rundown on the state of the home-servers I run and applications I host on the cloud.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Published while listening to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://invidious.snopyta.org/watch?v=zkvNnRjIhPE&#34;&gt;Mist of Capricorn ( Manavyalakincharadate ) | Agam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/wireguard-2.drawio.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few major changes since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/09/07/state-of-the-networks-sep-2021/&#34;&gt;last September update&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;During the Jan trip, I moved the Odroid XU4 and NCP over to MD. Thanks to WireGuard, I can still access these remotely super seamlessly!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brought in the RPi4 NC to the same WireGuard network. Lesser maintenance!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not quite using the Navidrome and Calibre-web setup as much. Definitely nice to have though.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setup a couple &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/02/20/bridged/&#34;&gt;Matrix Bridges&lt;/a&gt;. Ansible is pretty awesome! Need to front the &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2022/01/25/snikket/&#34;&gt;Snikket instance&lt;/a&gt; I setup in Jan when I have the mind-space.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m liking Caddy better than Traefik!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next few months, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably focus a bit more on SSH hardening, implement more robust Firewalls and automating the backups.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridged</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/20/bridged/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2022/02/20/bridged/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a good &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/01/10/digital-reset/&#34;&gt;one year away&lt;/a&gt; from Whatsapp, I&amp;rsquo;m back on it . This time however, on better terms.  All thanks to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://maunium.net/go/mautrix-whatsapp/&#34;&gt;Mautrix bridge&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.org/faq/#what-is-matrix%3F&#34;&gt;Matrix protocol&lt;/a&gt;.  Essentially, I can access my whatsapp account data on my regular phone or desktop using &lt;a href=&#34;https://element.io/get-started&#34;&gt;Elements&amp;rsquo; pretty robust app&lt;/a&gt; system. Note that the whatsapp app however is either running on a Virtual Machine or in my case an old phone fronted with a VPN. Since whatsapp only needs the primary phone to connect with their servers once every two weeks, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much just sitting there turned off while all the group and individual messages show up on the bridged element app.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s tremendous benefit to this approach:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The metadata that whatsapp is known to generously absorb from your ecosystem is heavily &lt;strong&gt;reduced&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You still get to stay in touch with folks who&amp;rsquo;re pure lazy to install another communications app&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You get to be in the ecosystem and nudge people out&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This works not just with Whatsapp, but telegram, iMessage, FB messenger and other messaging apps.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Setting this up took me barely 30 minutes - thanks to this exceptionally well documented &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spantaleev/matrix-docker-ansible-deploy/&#34;&gt;ansible playbook&lt;/a&gt; . Sounds and reads terse but it is super straightforward to follow through. At this point, calls are not bridged. It otherwise works absolutely seamless. Not quite sure how long I&amp;rsquo;d use this. It started off more from the perspective of testing out matrix and the surrounding ecosystem and it&amp;rsquo;s been a fun ride so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Walk over that bridge. Will ya? Now, if you do not want to set this all up yourselves, you could for a small price, use the service provided by either &lt;a href=&#34;https://element.io/element-one&#34;&gt;element&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.beeper.com/&#34;&gt;Beeper&lt;/a&gt; . I think they offer it at at a fantastic price-point.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks – Sep 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/07/state-of-the-networks-sep-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/09/07/state-of-the-networks-sep-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months, I was able to take some time to explore a few self-hostable options. I got to explore &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/07/28/caddy-through-the-tunnel/&#34;&gt;caddy&lt;/a&gt; (Which is terrific by the way!), setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/07/15/guacamole-clientless-remote-desktop-access/&#34;&gt;guacamole&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;m also absolutely loving &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/07/28/july-27-2021-2105/&#34;&gt;Navidrome&lt;/a&gt;. I got rid of OSMC since we weren&amp;rsquo;t quite using it as much and setup pi-hole to block ads network wide. With these changes, I think I am able to put these devices to real good use. While at it, I also setup a WireGuard tunnel from a VPS to access my local devices securely outside my home network.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Screenshot-from-2021-09-07-13-25-42-600x296.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/02/05/state-of-the-networks-feb-2021/&#34;&gt;February update&lt;/a&gt;, I haven&amp;rsquo;t changed the services on the cloud much. I did get rid of Bookstack, Known and Signal-CLI since I wasn&amp;rsquo;t using them as much. I am however using &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/?s=trilium&#34;&gt;Trilium notes&lt;/a&gt; exhaustively as my go-to notes and knowledge-base application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caddy through the tunnel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/07/28/caddy-through-the-tunnel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/07/28/caddy-through-the-tunnel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leave a comment if any of this doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense. I&amp;rsquo;ll be more than happy to help.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently installed &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/07/28/july-27-2021-2105/&#34;&gt;Navidrome on an Odroid XU4&lt;/a&gt; and configured &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/07/15/guacamole-clientless-remote-desktop-access/&#34;&gt;Guacamole on my NUC&lt;/a&gt;. To access these applications securely on an external network, I setup a WireGuard tunnel and took this opportunity to learn how to use Caddy as a reverse proxy. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick walk-through:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/image-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup the VPS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since we need a VPS just to tunnel traffic, get a lightweight one from a reliable provider. After the regular server hardening, setup your first WireGuard peer. I chose to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/angristan/wireguard-install&#34;&gt;this script&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To route traffic from the external web, configure your DNS settings to point to the VPS and then setup haproxy on the VPS:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## install haproxy&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sudo apt install haproxy -y&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## setup the config&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sudo nano /etc/haproxy/haproxy.cfg&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get the proxy config from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sriperinkulam/805cd86cd9ed797c8774d2331f135326&#34;&gt;gist here&lt;/a&gt; and make sure you edit the IP address at the end. Once that is done, close out the file and restart the service:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## check config&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;haproxy -f /etc/haproxy/haproxy.cfg -c&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## restart&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sudo systemctl restart haproxy.service&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the above steps complete, you should have a WireGuard tunnel that&amp;rsquo;s ready to send traffic over to its peers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup your peers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install WireGuard on the device you&amp;rsquo;d like to connect to the external network. Since we&amp;rsquo;ve already setup the first peer [Server], we&amp;rsquo;ll just have to copy over the configs and update it for the other peers [clients]. There are quite a few guides out there that outline this. Happy to provide pointers if required. Once you the peer(s) up and running, make sure they can &amp;rsquo;talk&amp;rsquo; to each other :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ping -c 1 xx.xx.xx.xx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great! Now we have the VPS and the WireGuard peers setup and talking to each other. Now on to routing the traffic. I would generally use Traefik for this. However, I wanted to explore caddy and this was a great test-case. I have docker containers running in DietPi on my Odroid-XU4. I spun up the caddy container using the below compose:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;version: &amp;#34;3&amp;#34;&#xA;&#xA;networks:&#xA;        web:&#xA;                external: true&#xA;services:&#xA;        caddy:&#xA;                image: caddy:2-alpine&#xA;                restart: unless-stopped&#xA;                ports:&#xA;                        - &amp;#34;80:80&amp;#34;&#xA;                        - &amp;#34;443:443&amp;#34;&#xA;                volumes:&#xA;                        - /home/dietpi/caddy/Caddyfile:/etc/caddy/Caddyfile&#xA;                        - /home/dietpi/caddy/data:/data&#xA;                        - /home/dietpi/caddy/config:/config&#xA;                networks:&#xA;                        - web&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the Caddyfile below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{&#xA;    # Global options block. Entirely optional, https is on by default&#xA;    # Optional email key for lets encrypt&#xA;    email updateme@domain.tld &#xA;    # Optional staging lets encrypt for testing. Comment out for production.&#xA;    # acme_ca https://acme-staging-v02.api.letsencrypt.org/directory&#xA;}&#xA;app1.domain.tld {&#xA;    reverse_proxy containername:port&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt; You&amp;rsquo;ll obviously have to tweak them for your needs. With all this set, you should now have functional access to your applications on the home-server externally!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It did take me a bit to figure out the moving parts. However, this was a fun exercise to tinker with caddy. Also I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixel.srkn.org/p/sriperinkulam/321094300853211136&#34;&gt;journal feature in Trilium&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of those hopping thoughts as I worked my way through setting this up. Tremendously useful! Questions or have a better way to set this up? I&amp;rsquo;m all ears!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guacamole - Clientless Remote Desktop access</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/07/15/guacamole-clientless-remote-desktop-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/07/15/guacamole-clientless-remote-desktop-access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://anydesk.com/en&#34;&gt;Anydesk&lt;/a&gt; for a while now to remote into my NUC workstation. It works great but for one big downside - It needs you to install the tool on both machines.  While looking for alternatives, I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://guacamole.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Guacamole&lt;/a&gt; which is a clientless remote desktop gateway. Set it up on the server and you can access your desktops now from any browser! So technically, If needed I could access my workstation even from a hand held device. All I need is a browser that supports HTML5!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It literally took me five minutes to set this up. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick run-through:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/compose/install/&#34;&gt;Docker-compose&lt;/a&gt; if you don&amp;rsquo;t have that setup already&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If the server is a linux machine and you need remote desktop access, now might be a good time to check and install xrdp: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install xrdp -y&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fetch the docker-compose file &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/reisbel/guacamole-docker-compose&#34;&gt;from here&lt;/a&gt; and follow instructions in the readme. You&amp;rsquo;re essentially setting up the postgres database and then spinning up the guac and guacd containers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the containers are up and running, your Guacamole server should be available at &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:8080/guacamole/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a functional server, lets tweak the settings to make this a bit client-ready:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change the default login/password - duh!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Navigate to Settings &amp;gt; Connections and add a new connection.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Under Edit Connection, add in a name and select &lt;strong&gt;RDP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scroll down to Parameters and fill in details for your network and authentication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/image-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scroll all the way down and save. That&amp;rsquo;s it! As you&amp;rsquo;d see there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://guacamole.apache.org/doc/gug/configuring-guacamole.html#rdp&#34;&gt;quite a few parameters&lt;/a&gt; that you can define for each connection. The above should however be sufficient to get you started.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that you have the server setup and the connections defined, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to connect to the machines directly from any browser within the same network. Navigate to http://&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;:8080/guacamole, login and based on your configuration you will be either connected to the server directly or provided the option to choose from the connections available. To access the machine from a different network, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to tunnel through which I&amp;rsquo;ll probably cover in a follow-up post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Owning my Garmin data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/29/owning-my-garmin-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/29/owning-my-garmin-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last month, I took some time to build a tiny WordPress plugin that fetches data from my Garmin Connect platform and displays it on my website. Currently the workflow only pulls activity data from the platform - which was my focus for this month. With modifications to the python script, I think this can be extended further to fetch any type of data from the platform. Here&amp;rsquo;s a rundown of the publishing workflow so far:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bluetooth Sync data from the watch to the Garmin connect portal. This is manual since I see no point in having Bluetooth turned on 24/7&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Edit the activity in the Garmin connect app for say activity title, activity type or just add some more context to the workout&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A cron job runs on my website twice every week to trigger &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/johannesh83/garmin-connect-export&#34;&gt;this python script&lt;/a&gt; in my WordPress plugin. I made slight modifications to the script so as to tie-in with my workflow.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The python script connects to my Garmin connect account, pulls the latest three activities and saves them as JSON files on my server.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/garmin-stats/&#34;&gt;garmin-stats page&lt;/a&gt; when requested by a client, parses the JSON file for each activity and displays the content in a predefined format. There&amp;rsquo;s also a provision to publish a specific activity as an individual post. If I&amp;rsquo;m logged in WordPress, a &amp;lsquo;Publish this&amp;rsquo; button is displayed for activities that have not been posted yet.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Currently I am assigning all of these posts to the &amp;lsquo;workout&amp;rsquo; category and I&amp;rsquo;ve disabled these from showing up on my main RSS feed. These posts however do show up on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/micro/&#34;&gt;micro-posts&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To-do&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The script currently triggers a &amp;lsquo;Garmin login alert&amp;rsquo; email for my account. Most likely because of locale settings. Would be good to mute these.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The plugin code currently dynamically generates the summary page on 200+ JSON files. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably limit this to just 20 or so.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fetch non activity data too.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maps, charts, visualizations!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always scope for cosmetic tweaks!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Micro updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/05/08/may-7-2021-1431/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 7, 2021 14:31&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/05/12/garmin-plugin/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 11, 2021 19:19&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021-05-08 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/08/may-7-2021-1431/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/08/may-7-2021-1431/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, I came across this &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/garminexport/&#34;&gt;nifty python tool&lt;/a&gt; that lets you backup all your garmin data from the Garmin-Connect platform. I wrote a crude WordPress plugin to parse the json files over and display the data on my website &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/garmin-stats/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The tool is kind of unstable because it essentially &amp;lsquo;mimics&amp;rsquo; a regular Garmin-connect login and download. Also probably the reason why there aren&amp;rsquo;t many functional plugins for Garmin on wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Should be reasonably straightforward to automate this with a cron job once I sort out the connection issues with Garmin. Also for now, I&amp;rsquo;m just posting all the activities to a single page. Might be interesting to create short posts for new activities and obviously filter them out from the RSS Feeds. Love these teeny tiny coding projects!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State of The Networks - Feb 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/05/state-of-the-networks-feb-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/02/05/state-of-the-networks-feb-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A quick rundown on the state of the home-servers I run or applications I host on the cloud.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Published while listening to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://invidious.snopyta.org/watch?v=RlcY37n5j9M&#34;&gt;Malang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With our temporary relocation, I currently manage two &amp;lsquo;home-labs&amp;rsquo; - one which I remotely manage with a WireGuard tunnel and the other just a local-access only setup. The remote home-lab is essentially a Nextcloud server running on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dietpi.com/&#34;&gt;DietPi OS&lt;/a&gt; spun on an RPi4. I pulled down the HAProxy config on the fronting server since that was no longer required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Homelab-SoTN-Feb-2021-600x478.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The local home-lab currently encompasses four units:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ownyourbits.com/nextcloudpi/&#34;&gt;NextcloudPi&lt;/a&gt; running on an RPi3 and connected to a 1TB main drive: This has been our primary document and media backup servers silently chugging along for close to three years now!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osmc.tv/&#34;&gt;OSMC&lt;/a&gt; installed on another RPi3: With a 1TB media drive, Amazon video and Youtube addons this primarily serves as a secondary family Television. A bit on the sluggish end but does the job for now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;DietPi running on an &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.odroid.com/odroid-xu4/odroid-xu4&#34;&gt;Odroid-XU4&lt;/a&gt;: Pi-Hole for Ad control and WireGuard to access the remote home-lab.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pop.system76.com/&#34;&gt;PoPOS&lt;/a&gt; running on an Intel NUC7: My primary workstation! An attached 1TB drive acts as the secondary backup for my NC setup and then I run sync jobs to a 256GB flash drive for a cold backup of the really important files.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then, on a remote VM I run a slew of services that handle most of my social and productivity tools. Fronted by Traefik and running in docker containers, the following services run on the 8GB server:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bookstackapp.com/&#34;&gt;Bookstack&lt;/a&gt; – Wiki software which I am currently using to help publish my dad’s second book&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://known.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;Known&lt;/a&gt; – I mostly use this as a quick bookmarking tool. I also post short updates or status notes here infrequently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wallabag.it/en&#34;&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; – Read-later app&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/06/14/guyon-flats-and-tuffys-tavern-trail/&#34;&gt;Pixelfed&lt;/a&gt; – Way better than Instagram and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pixel.srkn.org/sriperinkulam&#34;&gt;my go-to space&lt;/a&gt; to post individual images&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://selfoss.aditu.de/&#34;&gt;Minflux&lt;/a&gt; – The light-weight feed-reader that I pipe all my RSS subscriptions to&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zadam/trilium&#34;&gt;Trilium Notes&lt;/a&gt; – A terrific Evernote alternative with awesome Markdown support&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbernhard/signal-cli-rest-api&#34;&gt;Signal-CLI&lt;/a&gt; – I use this for server trigger notifications to be sent via SMS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://etherpad.org/&#34;&gt;Etherpad&lt;/a&gt; – Quick, collaborative notes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptpad.fr/&#34;&gt;CryptPad&lt;/a&gt; - Collaboration suite for documents&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Calibre - I use this to manage &lt;a href=&#34;https://lib.srkn.org/&#34;&gt;my digital books collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lychee - A nifty photo gallery where I currently save my &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2020/08/26/stamp-collection-digitized/&#34;&gt;digital stamps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;WordPress – I run 4 instances of WordPress – Portals for folks in my family&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nextcloud – This one’s more to test the recent releases before I deploy them on my home-lab&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometime down the lane I would like to setup a &lt;a href=&#34;https://snikket.org/&#34;&gt;Snikket instance&lt;/a&gt; for family chats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DIY Passport Photos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/25/diy-passport-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/25/diy-passport-photos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick and simple way to make and print your own passport photos[PP]. I&amp;rsquo;ve used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt; - which is a fabulous photo editing tool. They have a nifty &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;installer&lt;/a&gt; irrespective of which OS you use and have stood the test of time. There are a slew of different ways to arrive at the final product. This method has worked well for me over the past and based on your specific needs, you might have to alter a few settings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s say you have the below image that you&amp;rsquo;d like to make PP&amp;rsquo;s out of and you&amp;rsquo;d like them to be 2&amp;rsquo;&amp;lsquo;x2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; with other constraints laid out &lt;a href=&#34;https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/passports/how-apply/photos.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This one&amp;rsquo;s obviously a bad image to start out with, but should be a good test subject!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Dummy-1-150x150.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isolate and sanitize&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ideally, you&amp;rsquo;d want to get a good photo of the subject. Make sure s/he is standing against a light background and there&amp;rsquo;s sufficient uniform lighting on the face. If you&amp;rsquo;re not able to get that you&amp;rsquo;ll have to &amp;lsquo;sanitize&amp;rsquo; the image first. And here&amp;rsquo;s how we go about doing that:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open the image in GIMP and scale the image such that the distance between the top of the head and the bottom of the chin is about 1.1875 inch [Midway between 1 inch and 1.375 inch - The specs that was mentioned in the Travel web portal].&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To measure: Press &amp;lsquo;Shift+M&amp;rsquo; - This is the shortcut for the measure tool. Use the mouse pointer to measure distance. The measurements should be visible at the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To scale: Navigate to &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Image&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; on the top navigation bar and then select &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Scale Image&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. Change the &lt;em&gt;Image size&lt;/em&gt; attribute to % and scale down to the requisite level. For instance, I had to scale down to 60% since my initial Head-chin length was about 50mm.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally measure the resulting image&amp;rsquo;s head to chin length in pixels. In our test case this was 366 pixels after the scaling. So our DPI [Dots (Pixels) per inch] is 366/1.1875 ~=308. We&amp;rsquo;ll use this later to crop our image.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Before-scaling-1200x652.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/scale-image-1200x656.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. If your image does not have a uniform light background or has shadows [Like in our case] here&amp;rsquo;s how you digitally make the background white. Do note that certain agencies/services do not accept digitally altered images - So make sure you have some great lighting!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Select the Paths tool - Shortcut &amp;lsquo;B&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use your mouse and make a path around the subject. Make sure you close out the loop at the end by pressing Ctrl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Convert the path to a selection by pressing on the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Selection from path&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; on the &lt;strong&gt;Path&lt;/strong&gt; sidebar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Selection-from-path-600x326.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Press Ctrl+I to invert the selection and press Delete on your keyboard to erase the background.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve cleared the background, export the image as a jpeg and save for further processing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create the 2&amp;rsquo;&amp;lsquo;x2&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; image&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since we have a 308 DPI image , The 2&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot; image would be about [308x2, 308x2] pixels = 617x617 pixels. [Your values would obviously be different based on where you started!]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To crop out our 2&amp;quot;x2&amp;quot; image, click on the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Rectangular Select tool&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; - [Shortcut R]. Then on the &amp;lsquo;&lt;strong&gt;Rectangular Select&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo; sidebar, check the &lt;em&gt;Fixed&lt;/em&gt; checkbox and set the parameter to &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;size&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. Also further below switch the &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;No guides&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; drop-down to &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Center Lines&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. Now click on the image and you should see a square box with central guide lines.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/2x2-grab-600x326.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Move the box and center it so as to fit the image well within the box. Finally, Right-click on the Image, select &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Image&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo; and then &amp;lsquo;&lt;em&gt;Crop to Selection&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build the 4&amp;quot;x6&amp;quot; canvas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lets create a new image canvas to hold our 6 PP photos. Use the shortcut Ctrl+N to create a new image. Set the image size as 4&amp;quot;x6&amp;quot;. Open the advanced options and set the X and Y resolution to 308 pixels/in. While here you might also want to set the &lt;em&gt;Fill&lt;/em&gt; option to &lt;em&gt;White&lt;/em&gt;. Now that we have the base canvas ready, navigate to Image&amp;gt;Guides&amp;gt;New Guide(By Percent) and create two horizontal (33.33%,66.66%) and one vertical(50.00%) guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Canvas-1200x675.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Guides-1200x675.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now switch back to the previous GIMP window that has the 2&amp;quot;x2&amp;quot; image. Select all with Ctrl+A, Copy with Ctrl+C, switch over to the 4&amp;quot;x6&amp;quot; canvas and paste it over six times with Ctrl+V. Move the pasted images to the individual boxes. The guides will help snap the the images correctly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/Final-4x6-1-1200x652.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! You now have a stellar looking 4&amp;quot;x6&amp;quot; canvas that you can export to a jpeg/jpg format and print out on a matte photo card either at home or any of the external printing centers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital reset</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/10/digital-reset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/01/10/digital-reset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been sitting on the ledge for a while now and Whatsapp&amp;rsquo;s latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://bag.srkn.org/share/5ffaa21254e415.40990025&#34;&gt;ultimatum&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; what I needed to see myself out the doors. I value my freedom and privacy - way more than the perceived convenience and I&amp;rsquo;ve deleted my Whatsapp account for good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since FB bought Whatsapp in 2014, they&amp;rsquo;ve been working on building a feature-set that would keep users tethered to the network - read receipts, web clients, weeding out third party clients, voice calls, removing the 1$ annual fee, file sharing, encryption, desktop clients, video calls, customer service platform for enterprises, status, enhanced video call features - you get it. The most recent move is a strategic attempt to enhance their monetizing pipeline by building the framework to better mine metadata across its various platforms - Whatsapp, Instagram, Facebook and CrowdTangle. In growing economies, Payments has been one realm they have had their eyes on for a while now and this latest move will turbo-boost that intent and help them compete with PayTM, Google and Amazon Payment systems. I&amp;rsquo;m surprised they took 6 years to get here though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Users currently have until Feb 8, 2021 to agree. Very few of the millions of users will end up deleting their accounts since most just cannot see beyond Whatsapp and the mainstream messaging platforms. Given its huge user base and the network effect, It&amp;rsquo;s terrifically socially engineered to keep you from moving out to other apps because of the perceived benefits. Also how do you move your family and then the extended network out of a system that is already so inter-twined? If most of your connections don&amp;rsquo;t move where&amp;rsquo;s the draw in moving out? And honestly, I would have probably stayed had they given me an option to opt-out of its most recent terms and conditions. As a business, I know you&amp;rsquo;re eyeing the honey pot - But hey, not at my expense, free will and something that you shove down my throat. Good riddance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I use(d) Whatsapp primarily to stay connected with close family. I&amp;rsquo;m coercing nudging them to move over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.signal.org/&#34;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://delta.chat/en/&#34;&gt;Delta-chat&lt;/a&gt;. Surprisingly, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that difficult to get them to move. I should have done this several months back…I created groups on Signal and shared those individual links in the Whatsapp groups that I was part of, left a message and immediately deleted my account not waiting for many responses or questions. Majority accepted and are now on Signal! And for those that don&amp;rsquo;t, there&amp;rsquo;s always the old school way of connecting via SMS/voice calls. My FB and Instagram accounts are in dormant mode for the last few years now and the only social space I&amp;rsquo;m ‘active’ is on this blog. Since moving over my RSS feeds to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/miniflux/&#34;&gt;miniflux&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m more actively following people&amp;rsquo;s blogs and find that way more enriching than mainstream media. I&amp;rsquo;m gunning on the premise that if someone really wants to get in touch with me, they will figure out how to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Love these digital resets. See you on the other side!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PS: Before deleting your account, If you do want to archive your chat history, make sure you manually &lt;em&gt;export&lt;/em&gt; and not backup all your chats prior to moving. The backup option on Whatsapp doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much since the messages are encrypted and Whatsapp deletes the backups too when the account is deleted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
