<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/code/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Code on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>May 28, 2021 20:16</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/28/may-28-2021-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2021/05/28/may-28-2021-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It just struck me today how much I love writing crude, rewarding code. The type that is just sufficient to get the job done and that which &amp;lsquo;scratches your itch&amp;rsquo; and might probably be useful for someone else too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not a software developer. Never been one. My day job is far, far from it. It&amp;rsquo;s been more than a decade that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in a software firm. And even when I did, a good bunch of my time then was spent of mainframe code [Rexx / JCL] and Change Management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All code that I write today is self-taught. Which is probably why it&amp;rsquo;s crude? But beautiful it is, because it challenges me to think of logic first and semantics next. It pushes me to find the quickest way possible because I know exactly what I want it to do. And most importantly it keeps my mind fired and active!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Response to Colin&#39;s post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2017/05/26/response-to-colins-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2017/05/26/response-to-colins-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really like your &amp;lsquo;how-to&amp;rsquo; getting plugged posts, Colin! Always something to glean! Most of the improvisations I make on my site have been pretty crude - I dice the meat in an mu-plugin (essentially a custom functions file) and leave it at that. I really need to work on better documenting or standardizing my code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colinwalker.blog/2017/05/25/getting-plugged-in-part-5-settings/&#34;&gt;Getting plugged in – part 5: settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What started as a quick update to split the plugin into parts (so that it wasn’t all one monolithic file) became quite a major one. My original plan was to move both hooks for updating the post content to separate included files – it hasn’t quite gone according to plan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
