<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2024-04 on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/month/2024-04/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2024-04 on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/month/2024-04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nevado de Toluca</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/23/nevado-de-toluca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/23/nevado-de-toluca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this, sick to the core at 0300, rallying between sweating out the sheets and freezing to the bones. It&amp;rsquo;s been a rough couple days. Oddly enough I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel one ounce of pain during the alpine hike I did on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240422_163850.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We summited Nevado de Toluca on Saturday and this would be one of my best hikes so far. Just two hours from Mexico city, this hike has something for everybody. First off, just getting to the alpine lakes from the base, which takes about 20 minutes, opens out the playground. One can literally see the whole terrain and trails that surround the pristine alpine lakes. We decide to head clockwise and summit Pico del Fraile (15388&amp;rsquo;). The climb up is reasonably straighforward and its mostly choosing your path to get to the peak.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240420_105952-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once at the peak, instead of scrambling downhill to the lakes, we decide to complete the loop and summit all the other peaks in that circuit. For the next 4 hours we&amp;rsquo;re trapezing the peaks, scrambling up and down paths of our choosing. It&amp;rsquo;s windy but not unreasonably cold. A thunderstorm looms further on one of the peaks and as we make plans to find cover under the rocks a mild hail storm hits us. Thankfully, our helmets protect us and we make decent progress towards the other peaks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240420_183656-scaled.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sound of conch shells and drums give us constant company - From high up here at 15000&amp;rsquo; we see a group of about 30 people performing some ritual near one of the alpine lakes. As we push for the final descent we somehow loose our trail. All we&amp;rsquo;re left with is super loose soil and huge stones at a 80° gradient. There&amp;rsquo;s barely any grip here and we&amp;rsquo;re at the mercy of luck as we make our way down. Finally at around 1500 we reach the base and wait for the transport truck to take us down to the actual base.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This hike was such a contrast to Izta. Izta felt like just a suffer fest with barely any rewards while Toluca offered some terrific views right from the start. I&amp;rsquo;d repeat this hike in a heartbeat!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024-04-20 07:39:31 - &lt;strong&gt;Nevado de Toluca&lt;/strong&gt; 🥾 Hiked 6.07 miles in 06:39:57 Pace : 65.89 min/mile. Elevation Gain : 2611 ft. Elevation Loss : 2613 ft. Calories : 1037 Location : Toluca 💓 : 90&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-14 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/14/pico-de-%C3%A1guila/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/14/pico-de-%C3%A1guila/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/signal-2024-04-14-17-12-24-029-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;S was having a rough day on Saturday and was scrunched up against me all day. Around 1900 I checked my work phone and saw that Mo had texted earlier that morning asking if I would be interested in hiking Pico de Aguilar the next day. I wanted to confirm immediately but given S&amp;rsquo;s health I wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite sure. Decided to take a call the next morning and hit the bed. Thankfully, on Sunday morning, S seemed to have almost recovered and I decide to head out to meet Mo at his place. With some starting troubles (literally!) we finally leave for Ajusco around 0830.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The drive up is super straightforward and we park at the trailhead around 1000. We decide to take on the steeper parts of the climb first going clockwise. Around 1200 we reach Pico de Águila (12596&amp;rsquo;) and in another 30 minutes we summit Cerro La Cruz del Marquez (12871&amp;rsquo;). The way down from the Cerro was super steep at an 82° gradient. So glad we decided not to climb up from here and note to self to bring a knee brace for these downhills next time I hike here in CDMX. The loose volcanic soil and incessant pebbles make for dicey path downhill. We finish the hike at around 1400 and relish some hot cakes at one of the shacks at the base.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More than anything, this hike was a major morale booster after last weeks Izta attempt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024-04-14 09:43:52 - &lt;strong&gt;Pico de Águila et Cerro La Cruz del Marquez&lt;/strong&gt; 🥾 Hiked 4.69 miles in 04:50:29 Pace : 61.94 min/mile. Elevation Gain : 2405 ft. Elevation Loss : 2384 ft. Calories : 1810 Location : La Magdalena Contreras 💓 : 152&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Izta Attempt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/12/izta-attempt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/12/izta-attempt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got my ass royally whooped last weekend on Izta. The plan was to camp at La Joya until 0000 on Sunday and push for the summit by 0800. With around 4500&amp;rsquo; to climb, I knew this would be challenging. What I was not ready for, was the elevation sickness that hit me at about 14000&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240412_0649293003591195629761476.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  title=&#34;Izta from La Joya&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;La Joya is at around 13000&amp;rsquo;. We got here around 1200 on Saturday, setup camp and did a short 1.5 hours acclimatization hike to Portillo 1 and got back to La Joya for dinner and rest around 1600. I&amp;rsquo;m usually able to sleep well despite the surroundings. Today however, I sense a mild headache and am not quite able get much sleep for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We break camp around 0000 on Sunday and start the climb. As we reach Portillo 1 in about an hour I do notice I&amp;rsquo;m hurting a bit. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t this difficult last evening. A short break here and we head up to Portillo 2. Marco our guide checks on how we&amp;rsquo;re doing and I tell him - Today&amp;rsquo;s not my day. The headache from last night lingers and I feel a bit queasy. First sign of altitude sickness hitting me. I ask if we can slow down the pace and keep moving. At Portillo 3, I&amp;rsquo;m laboring and for a moment I think I saw M climbing down. That can&amp;rsquo;t quite be true because she never did come on this hike. I eat a couple nutri bars and suggest I stick right behind Marco as we climb the loose soil gradient towards Portillo 4. Around 15000&amp;rsquo; I start feeling a bit dizzy and take a call to turn around. The group agrees and I stay real close to Marco just focussing on his feet movements. It&amp;rsquo;s still pitch dark. On the way down, a group of hikers attempting the summit wish us a good hike and trudge along in the opposite direction. As the last person in the group crosses me, one look at her and I realise its M and I turn around and follow her. Only issue being - it&amp;rsquo;s not her. She never came on this hike. I snap back into reality when Adam checks in on me questioning why I&amp;rsquo;d turned around. And this is when I realise my altitude sickness is getting worse - quicker. I take a couple minutes to gather myself and we attempt to scale down the peak as quickly and safely as we can.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Portillo 1, we get some well needed rest. The sky is free of any pollution and all we see is beautiful stars strewn all over the pitch black sky. Shooting stars and satellites galore! I wish I had a good camera to capture this all. But then that would still do no justice to the magnificent show the universe was putting up this morning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/20240412_0759053559839938595451752.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Though we didn&amp;rsquo;t quite summit and Izta is yet to checked off the list, It&amp;rsquo;s been quite an eventful night. With sufficient rest at Portillo 1, I feel much better and literally run down the last section of this trail. We reach La Joya by dawn break and make our way back to CDMX.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maui whales</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/06/maui-whales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/06/maui-whales/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The only regret I have from our recent trip to Maui is my zero involvement in any of the trip planning. We could have gone kayaking to see the whales up close. Such a missed opportunity&amp;hellip;Next time I guess!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-04 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/04/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/04/gallery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Setup a basic &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/gallery/&#34;&gt;gallery&lt;/a&gt; page on my website that automatically updates and displays thumbnails from all my posts. Turned out to be a fun mini project and I&amp;rsquo;ve now scratched a long time itch!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-04 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/04/globo-aerost%C3%A1tico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/04/globo-aerost%C3%A1tico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some good time up in the air above the Teotihuacán pyramids. Flight was super smooth and with us landing right over a cactus field, the ending was even better!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/imagepipe_705734486179367623137.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  title=&#34;Teotihuacán hot air balloon&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-04 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/04/junior-ranger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/04/junior-ranger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working with S on her first ever Junior ranger activity sitting right above the clouds. The park ranger sneaked in an &amp;rsquo;eating vegetables&amp;rsquo; pact in her oath and handed over a pretty cool wooden badge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/imagepipe_711900157028559585018.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024-04-03 00:00:00</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/03/leleiwi-overlook-trail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/03/leleiwi-overlook-trail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Super short hike up to the overlook. Absolutely mesmerized to see the Tradewinds holding down the sea of clouds!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/imagepipe_694997230811934222143.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
