<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2019-12-30 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/date/2019-12-30-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019-12-30 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/date/2019-12-30-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weeknote 52 - Piercings and Runs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/12/30/weeknote-52-piercings-and-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019/12/30/weeknote-52-piercings-and-runs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A glimpse of the past week and the few articles, podcasts, tools, videos and music that captivated my attention:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The drive down to Florida was pretty uneventful. But for some holiday traffic near Virginia, we had a pretty smooth drive, clocking about 15 hours in total.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A random talk with a runner at the Baseline trail coaxed us to run a longer distance the next day. Got the four kids and Sharath onboard too. Well, the kids decided to sleep-in on Sunday, while Sharath and I head out to the trail. Realised I didn&amp;rsquo;t carry cash, so we decided to run unsupported. Running conditions were just right with a good blend of drizzle and rain. The beauty of winter is that you can cover so many more miles in the dark! Was mostly helping Sharath pace and finish within 3 hours. Wrapped up with 14.5 miles under his belt. Not a bad way to close out the year!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A week packed with hikes almost every day of the week and a lot of downtime with family. The girls convinced their moms to get extra ear piercings and Nikhil rode the wagon and got one for himself too!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting tools this week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://convos.by/&#34;&gt;Convos&lt;/a&gt;: IRC based multi-user chat application&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting reads this week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outline.com/2GhBPn&#34;&gt;Colleges are turning students’ phones into surveillance machines, tracking the locations of hundreds of thousands&lt;/a&gt;: Thank you, but no thank you! &amp;lsquo;Tracking you for your own good&amp;rsquo; - Isn&amp;rsquo;t that where it all starts going downhill?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://outline.com/gawvRZ&#34;&gt;20,000 ft under the sea&lt;/a&gt;: Mining, exploring and ofcourse polluting. We&amp;rsquo;re doing things with absolutely no concern for and awareness of the impacts on future generations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
