<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2023-07-04 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/date/2023-07-04-000000-&#43;0000-utc/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2023-07-04 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/date/2023-07-04-000000-+0000-utc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>July 6, 2023 12:39</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/04/july-6-2023-1239/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/04/july-6-2023-1239/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;S had a seemingly sudden meltdown on the way back from her roller skating class asking for a &amp;lsquo;Hello Kitty Donut&amp;rsquo;. She hopped off her bike and said she won&amp;rsquo;t ride it until we got her one that very instant. M told her we could talk about it once we&amp;rsquo;re home. The looming thunder clouds didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to budge her too. M seemed to have had a word with her and that somehow changed her mind - a bit. Finally she did succumb, however vehemently showing her immense dissatisfaction by bawling and walking her bike home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M brings me up to speed once we&amp;rsquo;re home. A couple months ago, M apparently had promised her a donut the day she wore all her protección while skating. Today happens to be that day and in her mind S had all right to protest when we didn&amp;rsquo;t close our end of the deal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This kids got an elephant&amp;rsquo;s memory just like her Mom! While that&amp;rsquo;s a terrific thing, I&amp;rsquo;ve got work cut out for me!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notas de mitad de año</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/04/notas-de-mitad-de-a%C3%B1o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/07/04/notas-de-mitad-de-a%C3%B1o/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With quite a few things constantly evolving over the last several months, I haven&amp;rsquo;t actively paid much attention to this space. I&amp;rsquo;ve posted a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://srikanthperinkulam.com/micro/&#34;&gt;micro posts&lt;/a&gt; now and then, but nowhere close to chronicling things as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to. This is a quick run down of a few things occupying my mind space:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been about four months since we moved to Mexico City. We absolutely love it here. People are terrific, weather is just right, and this city&amp;rsquo;s got a dash of almost every city we&amp;rsquo;ve lived in so far! M&amp;amp;S have been able to explore the regular tourist spots thanks to the CLO trips. I&amp;rsquo;ve joined them for a few, but what I really enjoy is just experiencing the city for what it&amp;rsquo;s got to offer - And there&amp;rsquo;s no dearth to that. Absolutely blown away by the city planning and the presence of so many parks. The city is spectacularly clean for the number of people living here. Every Sunday one of the main avenues is closed out to vehicular traffic and opened out to runners, cyclists and essentially anybody who wants to enjoy the roads. Amazed at the resources that the local government is able to draw from to sustain this every single weekend! We haven&amp;rsquo;t been that lucky to find decent vegetarian food here. Most local restaurants offer some form of meat in almost all dishes and the vegetarian items are rarely tasty. Dining out definitely leaves a lot to be desired - unless of course you try out other cuisines. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there&amp;rsquo;s good food out there - yet to find it though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s exactly a year since I took on the current position. Best career move I&amp;rsquo;ve made so far, and I absolutely love every part of my job. There&amp;rsquo;s not one day that&amp;rsquo;s akin to another and I&amp;rsquo;m constantly learning every day. Most days just whizz by with constant troubleshooting on systems and processes. I&amp;rsquo;m barely at my desk for an hour a day. Tracing power and logic is so refreshing - The adrenaline rush that comes when you&amp;rsquo;ve found that nuanced fault in the system is addictive. The closest I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to this in the past was while writing code for enhancing functionality in one of my side projects. Ironic that it took me fifteen years to realize what I&amp;rsquo;m really good at - fixing things! And now I get paid to play with toys and travel the world. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to travel to Matamoros, Nuevo Laredo and Hermosillo so far. These cities are so different from CDMX and I&amp;rsquo;m glad I get a chance to experience these regions of the country too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been biking to work most days and doing the Reforma ride on the weekends. So good to be back on the saddle so regularly. Met a couple folks from a trail running group here last weekend and would love to join them whenever time permits. Over the next few months I would also like to visit the National parks around the city. Not having a car is kinda limiting but definitely not a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a family, we&amp;rsquo;ve really gotten into playing Zelda - Breath of the Wild. We each have our own profiles and are at different stages of the game. This is fascinating, engaging and such a good way to spend time together while indoors. S enjoys the challenges and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see how good she&amp;rsquo;s gotten at the game. Definitely getting the Tears of the Kingdom really soon!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been actively tinkering with my home-lab. Mostly doing the bare essentials to keep it updated and running. I&amp;rsquo;ve started using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.firefly-iii.org/&#34;&gt;FireFly III&lt;/a&gt; more actively to keep track of our expenses and for general budgeting. Since internet and power are decently reliable, I should probably move part of my home-lab over from MD to here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
