<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on Srikanth Perinkulam</title>
    <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/finance/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on Srikanth Perinkulam</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://srikanthperinkulam.com/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stimulus</title>
      <link>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/03/11/stimulus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>ssphugo@srkn.anonaddy.com (Srikanth Perinkulam)</author>
      <guid>https://srikanthperinkulam.com/2021/03/11/stimulus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting point on M1 and M2 [Measures of money]. With the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.allsides.com/story/biden-signs-19-trillion-covid-19-relief-bill-law&#34;&gt;signing of the 1.9T$ bill today&lt;/a&gt; in the US, we&amp;rsquo;ve essentially created 6T$ over the last 10 months. Just like that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Covid19 has brought  unprecedented suffering to many. Deaths, Unemployment, Medical complications, lifestyle changes, Social unrest and several other ramifications which we are yet to experience. If anything, it has taught us highlighted how abysmally poor we are in collectively addressing pressing issues. It has also shown us that when disaster strikes, we only take care of our own and we are selectively biased even at that. Nature gave us yet another opportunity to show how we could better ourselves and elevate us to the next stage of evolution and we miserably failed. With our myopic non-collaborative actions, pushing politics and power over general good, we&amp;rsquo;ve defined a new low. Mileage on isolated or individual efforts unfortunately does not carry the ripple effect that can scale. Nothing surprising there - Humans are selfish creatures. We of course needed something to balance all the &lt;em&gt;intelligence&lt;/em&gt; and cognitive advances we supposedly have over other living things. Humanity rests is constant chaos and Covid19 was continues to fuel that chaos.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quite a digression, eh?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
